<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-942</num>
  <heading>Hose stations.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-942 Hose stations. (a) Hose outlet valves. (1) At the riser on each floor served by the riser and on the entrance floor above the riser control valve, a two and one-half inch hose outlet valve shall be provided for fire department use. Such hose
    outlet valve shall be readily accessible from a stairway landing or from a floor, and shall be located between five feet and six feet above the landing or floor. (2) At the top of the highest riser, there shall be provided above the main roof level,
    a three-way manifold equipped with three two and one-half inch hose valves with hose valve caps. Where the manifold is located other than within a heated stair enclosure or bulkhead, the control valve shall be located in a horizontal run of piping
    below the roof. (b) Location. Hose stations shall be located at the standpipe risers located either within a stair enclosure or adjacent to the entrance to such enclosure as provided in section 27-936 of this article. When the hose station is located
    outside the stair enclosure and the riser is within the stair enclosure, it shall be known as and referred to as "Auxiliary Hose Station". (1) Hose stations shall be located so that every point in the floor area served by the hose station is within
    twenty feet of the end of the hose nozzle with the hose in its extended position. The maximum length of hose that shall be permitted at any hose station is one hundred twenty-five feet. (c) Size, type and quality of hose. Hose shall be provided on
    hose racks at each hose station as follows: (1) Hose shall be one and one-half inch "flax-line" unlined linen hose or equivalent, factory coupled, in occupancy groups C, E, F, G, H, and J. (2) Hose shall be two and one-half inch cotton, rubber-line,
    or rubber hose or equivalent, factory coupled, in occupancy group A. (3) Hose shall be two and one-half inch "flax-line" unlined linen hose or equivalent, factory coupled, for occupancy groups other than those in paragraphs one and two of this subdivision.
    (4) Hose for auxiliary hose stations shall be one and one-half inch "flax-line" unlined hose or equivalent. (5) Hose lines shall be made up of fifty foot factory coupled hose except that required hose lengths of less than fifty feet shall be in one
    section of the required length. Only one length less than fifty feet will be permitted where hose length is not of equal fifty foot increments, and no length shall be less than twenty-five feet. (6) Hose may be omitted from hose racks in occupancy
    groups J-1 and J-2 whenever at least three open nozzles, two one and one-half inch, and two two and one-half inch spanner wrenches, two two and one-half by one and one-half inch non-swivel reducing couplings and three hundred seventy-five feet of
    one and one-half inch hose are stored and maintained in a locked cabinet located on the main entrance floor in a location near the standpipe riser enclosure subject to the approval of the commissioner, and hose valves are capped with a hose valve
    cap fastened to the valve with a chain. The person responsible for the maintenance of the standpipe system shall maintain on the premises a key for unlocking the storage cabinet. The key shall be kept in a location where it is readily available to
    authorized persons, but not available to the general public. A sign shall be placed on the storage cabinet indicating the location of the key. An additional labelled key shall be kept in a locked receptacle near the storage cabinet openable by a fire
    department standard key. Such receptacle shall be marked "For Fire Department Use Only." A metal sign shall be placed in each stair enclosure on the main entrance floor stating clearly where the storage cabinet is located. (7) Hose may be omitted
    from hose racks for nonautomatic dry standpipe systems provided that the hose outlet valves are capped with hose valve caps which are chained to the valves. (d) Auxiliary hose stations. (1) Auxiliary hose stations may be installed in those occupancies
    where one and one-half inch hose is permitted as specified in subdivision (c) of this section. (2) When auxiliary hose stations are installed, the required two and one-half inch hose valve at the riser shall be installed and the valve shall be equipped
    with a cap fastened to the valve with a chain.</text>
</level>