<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-317.2</num>
  <heading>Exceptions within special flood hazard areas.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-317.2 Exceptions within special flood hazard areas. Mixed use buildings may be constructed within Zone A, as delineated in reference standard RS 4-4, with non-habitable portions below the base flood elevation, provided all of the following conditions
    are met: (a) The building is constructed so as to provide entrance access at or above the base flood elevation. (b) The portion of the building and all service equipment below the base flood elevation are floodproofed, in accordance with reference
    standard RS 4-5. (c) No habitable room may be located in such cellar or basement. (d) A water closet and/or a wash basin may be located in an enclosed space not to exceed four feet by four feet six inches in such cellar or basement, and no roughing
    therein shall be allowed to accommodate any additional fixtures. (e) No accessory kitchens shall be allowed in such cellar or basement; however, one two-compartment laundry tray or similar appliance may be installed outside the water closet compartment.
    (f) The building permit application filed with the department of buildings or the work permit application filed with the department of ports, and trade shall state that: (1) The premises is located within the special flood hazard area; (2) The cellar
    or basement is located below the level of the base flood elevation; and, (3) No portion of the cellar or basement may be used for living purposes. (g) A deed restriction noting all of the above is to be recorded in the county clerk's office and the
    page and liber number indicated on either the building permit application and certificate of occupancy filed with and issued by the department of buildings, or the work permit application and the certificate of completion filed with and issued by
    the department of ports and trade. (For Table 4-1 see chapter 839 of the laws of 1986) Notes: Tabulated areas are given in sq. ft. and establish maximum gross area permitted on any one story within a building or fire area. See section 27-303 and subdivision
    (e) of section 27-328 for permissible area increases. Tabulated heights are given in feet and number of stories (in parentheses) {a} See section 27-297 for construction exemptions. {b} See article eleven of subchapter seven of chapter one of this
    title for area and height limitations of open parking structures. {c} See paragraph two of subdivision (b) of section 27-548 for grandstand limitations. {d} See subdivision (c) of section 27-339 for area limitations for existing office buildings one
    hundred feet or more in height with mechanical ventilation and/or air-conditioning systems that serve floors other than the floor on which the equipment is located. {e} Spaces in occupancy group A solely due to their containing gas distribution piping
    at pressure levels above fifteen psig may be unsprinklered and conform with the area and height limitations set forth in table 4-2, provided other fire protection requirements set forth in section 27-404 and subchapters five and seventeen of chapter
    one of this title are met. {f} See section 27-954 for area limitations for buildings less than seventy-five ft. in height. {g} See subdivisions (u) and (v) of section 27-954 for requirements pertaining to F-4 spaces within J-1 buildings, catering
    establishments and banquet halls with occupant load of three hundred or more persons. (For Table 4-2 see chapter 839 of the laws of 1986) Notes: Tabulated areas are given in square feet and establish maximum gross area permitted on any one story within
    a building or fire area. See section 27-303 for permissible area increases. Tabulated heights are given in feet and number of stories (in parentheses). {a} See section 27-297 for construction exemptions. {b} See article eleven of subchapter seven
    of this chapter for area and height limitations of open parking structures.</text>
</level>