<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-588</num>
  <heading>Use of used and unidentified materials.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-588 Use of used and unidentified materials. The utilization of used materials and unidentified or ungraded materials shall be limited to non-structural elements, except: (a) Such materials (or elements) may be reused, or continued in use, at stress
    levels to which the materials or elements were subjected in the previous construction, or at load capacity as demonstrated by load test procedures as described in subdivision (a) of section 27-599 of article three of this subchapter. (b) Unidentified
    materials may be graded by the recovery and test of representative samples, or by other means satisfactory to the commissioner. (c) Used materials shall be considered to be graded where the grade is clearly indicated on the approved plans for the
    existing construction and may be used at the allowable stress levels for that grade of like material as established in the building code in force at the time the plans for the existing construction were approved. Table 10-1 Inspection of Materials
    and Assemblies ======================================================================== Elements That Shall Be Elements That Are Not Materials Subject to Controlled Subject to Controlled Inspection a,b,d Inspection a,c,d ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Steel None All structural elements and connections Concrete Materials for all structural (1) All materials for elements proportioned on the structural elements basis of calculated stresses proportioned on the basis of seventy per cent or greater,
    calculated stresses less than of basic allowable values. seventy per cent of basic See article five for allowable values specific requirements (2) Concrete materials for: relating to "quality control (a) Short span floor and roof of materials and
    batching." construction proportioned as per section 27-610. (b) Walls and footings for buildings in occupancy group J-3. (3) Metal reinforcement. Aluminum None All structural elements and connections. Wood None All structural elements and connections.
    Reinforced None All structural elements. gypsum concrete Masonry None All structural elements. Other Requirements as may be established in other subchapters of this code or by the commissioner. Notes: a For general provisions relating to inspection
    see section 27-132. b All structural materials and assemblies subject to controlled inspection shall be tested and/or inspected at their place of manufacture and evidence of compliance with the provisions of this subchapter shall be provided as stipulated
    in articles four through twelve. c Mill, manufacturer's and supplier's inspection and test reports will be accepted as evidence of compliance with the provisions of this code for all structural materials and assemblies not subject to controlled inspection.
    d Basic allowable stress values as referenced herein shall denote allowable stress value without increase for infrequent stress conditions as established in this code or in the applicable reference standard for the material or element in its proposed
    use. Notes: Table 10-2 Inspection of Methods of Construction ======================================================================== Operations on Structural Operations on Structural Elements That Shall Be Elements That Are Not Subject to Controlled
    Subject to Controlled Materials Inspection a,b,d Inspection a,c,d ------------------------------------------------------------------------ Steel (1) Welding operations and (1) Welding operations and the tensioning of high the tensioning of high strength
    bolts in connections strength bolts in connections where the calculated stresses where the calculated stresses in the welds or bolts are in the welds or bolts are fifty per cent or more of less than fifty per cent of basic allowable values. basic
    allowable values. (2) Connection of fittings to (2) All other fabrication and wire cables for suspended erection operations not structures, except where designated for controlled cables together with their inspection. attached fittings are proof-loaded
    to not less than fifty-five per cent of ultimate capacity. Concrete Except for those operations (1) All operations relating specifically designated in to the construction of this table as not subject to members and assemblies (other controlled inspection,
    for than pre-stressed members) all concrete, the operations which involve the placement described in subdivision of a total of less than fifty (a) of section 27-607 shall cubic yards of concrete and be subject to controlled wherein said concrete is
    used inspection. at levels of calculated stress seventy per cent or less of basic allowable values. (2) Placing and curing of concrete for all: (a) Short span floor and roof construction as per section 27-610. (b) Walls and footings for buildings
    in occupancy group J-3. (3) Size and location of reinforcement for walls and footings for buildings in occupancy group J-3. (4) All other operations not described in subdivision (a) of section 27-607. Aluminum Welding operations in (1) Welding operations
    in connections where the cal- connections where the cal- culated stresses in the culated stresses in the welds welds are fifty per cent are less than fifty per cent or more of the basic of basic allowable values. allowable values. (2) All other fabrication
    and erection operations not designated for controlled inspection. Wood Fabrication of All other operations not glued-laminated assemblies designated for controlled and of plywood components. inspection. Reinforced None All operations incident to Gypsum
    the fabrication and placement Concrete of structural elements. Reinforced (1) Fabrication of (1) All masonry work for Masonry prefabricated units. buildings in occupancy (2) Placement and bedding of group J-3. units; sizes of members, (2) All mixing
    of mortar. including thickness of walls (3) All other operations and wythes; sizes of columns; not designated for the size and position of controlled inspection. reinforcement, in place, and provisions for curing and protection against freezing for
    all reinforced masonry construction unless such operations are specifically not designated for controlled inspection. Un- Placement and bedding of units (1) All masonry work for reinforced and sizes of members buildings in occupancy Masonry including
    thickness of walls group J-3. and wythes; sizes of columns; (2) All mixing of mortar. cleanouts; and provisions (3) All other operations not for curing and protection designated for controlled against freezing for all inspection. masonry construction
    proportioned on the basis of structural analysis as described in section four of reference standard RS 10-1B, unless such operations are specifically not designated for controlled inspection. Piling See provisions of subchapter eleven. Other Requirements
    as may be established in other subchapters of this code. ======================================================================== a For general provisions relating to inspection see section 27-132. b All construction operations designated for controlled
    inspection shall be inspected by the architect or engineer designated for controlled inspection during the performance of such operation. c Certification by the fabricator or erector, as applicable, will be accepted as evidence of compliance with
    the provisions of this code for all construction operations not subject to controlled inspection. d Basic allowable stress values as referenced herein shall denote allowable stress value without increase for infrequent stress conditions as established
    in this code or in the applicable reference standard for the material or element in its proposed use.</text>
</level>