<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-392</num>
  <heading>Fines; issuance, renewal, suspension and revocation of license.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-392 Fines; issuance, renewal, suspension and revocation of license. a. The commissioner shall have the power to impose a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars upon a licensee and/or suspend or revoke a license or deny an application for the issuance
    or renewal of a license for any one or more of the following causes: 1. Fraud, misrepresentation, or bribery in securing a license. 2. The making of any false statement as to a material matter in any application for a license. 3. The person or the
    management personnel of the contractor are untrustworthy or not of good character. 4. The business transactions of the contractor have been or are marked by a practice of failure to timely perform or complete its contracts, or the manipulation of
    assets or accounts, or by fraud or bad faith, or is marked by an unwholesome method or practice of solicitation of business from owners. 5. Failure to display the license as provided in this subchapter. 6. Failure to comply with any demand or requirement
    lawfully made by the commissioner. 7. When an agent or employee of a licensee has been guilty of an act of omission, fraud, or misrepresentation and the licensee has approved or had knowledge thereof. 8. Violation of any provision of this subchapter
    or any rule or regulation adopted hereunder or for performing or attempting to perform any act prohibited by this subchapter. 9. Violation of any provision of subchapters one, two or three of title twenty-six or subchapter one of title twenty-seven
    of this code, or any rule adopted thereunder or for performing or attempting to perform any act prohibited by such subchapters, provided that the commissioner shall suspend or revoke the license of any licensee who continues to work in violation of
    a stop-work notice or order issued pursuant to section 26-118 of this code. b. In addition to any of the powers that may be exercised by the commissioner pursuant to this subchapter and chapter one of this title, the commissioner, after notice and
    an opportunity to be heard, may refuse to issue or renew, or may suspend or revoke, a license required under this subchapter if the applicant or licensee, or any of its principals, officers or directors, or any of its stockholders owning more than
    ten percent of the outstanding stock of the corporation has been convicted of a crime which, in the judgment of the commissioner, has a direct relationship to such person's fitness or ability to perform any of the activities for which a license is
    required under this subchapter or has been convicted of any other crime which, in accordance with article twenty-three-a of the correction law, would provide a justification for the commissioner to refuse to issue or renew, or to suspend or revoke,
    such license.</text>
</level>