<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-316</num>
  <heading>Permit restrictions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-316 Permit restrictions. Within special flood hazard areas, as delineated in reference standard RS4-4, applications for permits shall be subject to the following: (a) Permissible uses and other measures to reduce flood losses shall take precedence
    over any conflicting laws. (b) Major repairs or alterations shall be with construction materials and utility equipment that are resistant to flood damage, and use construction methods and practices that will minimize flood damage. (c) New and proposed
    construction or substantial improvements shall be protected against flood damage, be designed (or modified) and anchored to prevent flotation, collapse or lateral movements of the structure, use construction materials and utility equipment that are
    resistant to flood damage, and use construction methods and practices that will minimize flood damage. (d) New and proposed developments and construction shall minimize flood damage, locate, elevate and construct all public utilities such as gas,
    sewer, electrical and water systems to minimize or eliminate flood damage, and provide adequate drainage so as to reduce exposure to flood hazards. (e) New or replacement water supply systems and/or sanitary sewage systems shall be designed to minimize
    or eliminate infiltration of floodwaters into the systems, and discharges from the systems into floodwaters, and require on-site disposal systems to be located so as to avoid impairment of them or contamination from them during flooding. (f) Subdivision
    proposals and other proposed new developments and construction shall (i) minimize flood damage, (ii) have all public utilities, such as sewer, gas, electrical and water systems located and constructed to minimize or eliminate flood damage, and (iii)
    provide adequate drainage so as to reduce exposure to flood hazards. (g) Upon placement of the lowest floor, or flood-proofing by any means, the holder of any permit to which this section applies shall submit to the department a certification of the
    elevation of the lowest floor, or where applicable of the lowest flood-proofed elevation, in relation to mean sea level. Provided, however, that in areas designated as Zone V in reference RS 4-4, such permit holder shall certify to the department
    the elevation, in relation to mean sea level, of the bottom of the lowest structural member of the lowest floor. Such certification shall be prepared by a registered architect or licensed professional engineer. (h) Compliance with the foregoing shall
    be accomplished in accordance with sections 27-317, 27-317.1, 27-317.2, 27-550, 27-580, 27-652, 27-771 and 27-787 and subdivision (aa) of section 27-901 of this title and reference standards RS 4-4 and RS 4-5.</text>
</level>