<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>11-4023</num>
  <heading>Authority to seal premises.</heading>
  <text>ยง 11-4023 Authority to seal premises. (a) If any person has been finally determined to have engaged in the acts described in subdivision b of this section, the commissioner of finance shall be authorized to order: (1) the sealing of any premises operated
    by such person where such acts occurred; and (2) the removal, sealing or making inoperable of any devices, items or goods used in connection with any of such acts. (b) The following acts shall serve as the basis for a sealing order pursuant to this
    section: (1) the violation of subdivisions a or b of section 11-1303 of this title or section 17-703 or 20-202 of the code on at least two occasions within a three-year period; or (2) the violation of any provision of chapter thirteen of this title
    or any of sections 17-703, 17-703.2, 17-704, 17-705, subdivision a or b of section 17-706, 17-715 or 20-202 of the code on at least three occasions within a three-year period. (c) Orders of the commissioner to seal premises. (1) Orders of the commissioner
    issued pursuant to this section shall be posted at the premises at which the acts described in subdivision b of this section have occurred. (2) Ten days after the date of such posting, and upon the written directive of the commissioner, police officers
    designated in section 1.20 of the criminal procedure law and peace officers employed by the department of finance, including but not limited to the sheriff, undersheriff and deputy sheriffs of the city of New York designated as peace officers in subdivision
    two of section 2.10 of the criminal procedure law, are authorized to act upon and enforce such orders. (3) Any devices, items or goods removed pursuant to this section, shall be stored in a garage, pound or other place of safety and the owner or other
    person lawfully entitled to the possession of such devices, items or goods may be charged with reasonable costs for removal and storage payable prior to the release of such devices, items or goods to such owner or such other person. (4) The owner
    or other person lawfully entitled to reclaim the devices, items or goods described in paragraph three of this subdivision shall reclaim such devices, items or goods. If such owner or such other person does not reclaim such devices, items or goods
    within ninety days of their removal, such devices, items or goods shall be subject to forfeiture upon notice and judicial determination in accordance with provisions of law. Upon forfeiture the department shall, upon a public notice of at least five
    days, sell such forfeited devices, items or goods at public sale. The net proceeds of such sale, after deduction of the lawful expenses incurred, shall be paid into the general fund of the city. (d) Unsealing of premises. The commissioner shall order
    that any premises which are sealed pursuant to this section shall be unsealed and that any devices, items or goods removed, sealed or otherwise made inoperable pursuant to this section shall be released, unsealed or made operable upon: (1) payment
    of all outstanding cigarette taxes and civil penalties and all reasonable costs for removal and storage; and (2) the expiration of a period of time from the date of enforcement of the order to be determined by the commissioner not to exceed sixty
    days. (e) Any person aggrieved by an order issued pursuant to this section may seek judicial review of such order through a proceeding pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules. (f) Removal of seal. Any person who removes
    the seal on any premises or removes the seal on or makes operable any devices, items or goods sealed or otherwise made inoperable in accordance with an order of the commissioner shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</text>
</level>