<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-118</num>
  <heading>Construction of sheds; regulation by commissioner.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-118 Construction of sheds; regulation by commissioner. a. Whenever any person, shall be owner or lessee of any water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead, and shall use it for the purpose of regularly receiving and discharging cargo such
    owner or lessee, with the consent of the lessor, may erect and maintain thereon, sheds for the protection of property so received or discharged, provided they shall have obtained from the commissioner, license or authority to erect or maintain the
    same, subject to the conditions and restrictions contained in such license or authority. Such license or authority, after it has been granted and has been acted upon, shall not be revoked by such commissioner without the consent in writing of the
    mayor and the board of estimate. Notice shall be given to all parties having any interest therein of a hearing before the board of estimate to consider the application of the commissioner for the revocation of such license or authority. Such notice
    shall be given by publication thereof for six consecutive days in the City Record, not less than ten nor more than thirty days before such hearing, and by posting, not less than ten nor more than thirty days before such hearing, copies of such notice,
    in the form of handbills, upon the shed or sheds erected or maintained pursuant to such license or authority, or upon the water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead upon which such shed or sheds shall have been erected or maintained. Such
    sheds hereafter shall be constructed subject to the regulations and under the authority of the commissioner. The commissioner may build and maintain such sheds on any water front property, wharf, pier, dock or bulkhead owned by the city and under
    the charge and control of the department, and may lease the same; and any lessee thereof shall have all the rights and privileges above granted. b. Nothing in subdivision a of this section shall be construed to authorize the erection or maintenance
    on any pier of any storehouse, booths, shops or other structures than the sheds mentioned with the proper doors and gates appertaining thereto. The commissioner may grant a permit or license, however, upon such terms and conditions as he or she may
    deem proper to the lessee of piers twelve, thirteen, fifteen, and sixteen owned by the city in the borough of Staten Island, to maintain a place for the keeping and care of goods, merchandise and materials discharged from vessels, upon any floor of
    any such pier. c. Nothing contained in subdivision b of this section shall be construed as interfering in any respect with the government or regulation of the Staten Island free port.</text>
</level>