<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-815</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-815 Definitions. For the purposes of this subchapter, the following terms shall have the following meanings: a. "Abortion" shall mean the termination of a pregnancy for purposes other than producing a live birth, which includes but is not limited
    to a termination using pharmacological agents. b. "Client" shall mean an individual who is inquiring about or seeking services at a pregnancy services center. c. "Emergency contraception" shall mean one or more prescription drugs used separately or
    in combination, to prevent pregnancy, when administered to or self-administered by a patient, within a medically recommended amount of time after sexual intercourse, and dispensed for that purpose in accordance with professional standards of practice
    and determined by the United States food and drug administration to be safe. d. "Health information" shall mean any oral or written information in any form or medium that relates to health insurance and/or the past, present or future physical or mental
    health or condition of a client. e. "Licensed medical provider" shall mean a person licensed or otherwise authorized under the provisions of articles one hundred thirty-one, one hundred thirty-one-a, one hundred thirty-one-b, one hundred thirty-nine
    or one hundred forty of the education law of New York, to provide medical services. f. "Personal information" shall mean any or all of the following: the name, address, phone number, email address, date of birth, social security number, driver's license
    number or non-driver photo identification card number of a client, a relative of a client or a sexual partner of a client. This term shall apply to all such data, notwithstanding the method by which such information is maintained. g. "Pregnancy services
    center" shall mean a facility, including a mobile facility, the primary purpose of which is to provide services to women who are or may be pregnant, that either: (1) offers obstetric ultrasounds, obstetric sonograms or prenatal care; or (2) has the
    appearance of a licensed medical facility. Among the factors that shall be considered in determining whether a facility has the appearance of a licensed medical facility are the following: the pregnancy services center (a) offers pregnancy testing
    and/or pregnancy diagnosis; (b) has staff or volunteers who wear medical attire or uniforms; (c) contains one or more examination tables; (d) contains a private or semi-private room or area containing medical supplies and/or medical instruments; (e)
    has staff or volunteers who collect health insurance information from clients; and (f) is located on the same premises as a licensed medical facility or provider or shares facility space with a licensed medical provider. It shall be prima facie evidence
    that a facility has the appearance of a licensed medical facility if it has two or more of the factors listed in subparagraphs (a) through (f) of paragraph (2) of this subdivision. A pregnancy services center shall not include a facility that is licensed
    by the state of New York or the United States government to provide medical or pharmaceutical services or where a licensed medical provider is present to directly provide or directly supervise the provision of all services described in this subdivision
    that are provided at the facility. h. "Premises" shall mean land and improvements or appurtenances or any part thereof. i. "Prenatal care" shall mean services consisting of physical examination, pelvic examination or clinical laboratory services provided
    to a woman during pregnancy. Clinical laboratory services refers to the microbiological, serological, chemical, hematological, biophysical, cytological or pathological examination of materials derived from the human body, for purposes of obtaining
    information, for the diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of disease or the assessment of health condition.
  </text>
</level>