<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-353</num>
  <heading>Smoke and heat venting.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-353 Smoke and heat venting. (a) Where the floor area of a one-story building classified in occupancy group A, B-1, or D-1 is greater in depth than one hundred feet from a frontage space, that portion beyond one hundred feet shall be provided with
    roof vents and smoke curtains complying with the requirements of reference standard RS 5-11. Where the effective area of vents are glazed with plain glass or plastic not thicker than one-eighth inch, they need not be provided with automatic opening
    devices. (b) Buildings classified in occupancy group E, one hundred feet or more in height, having air-conditioning and/or mechanical ventilation systems that serve more than the floor on which the equipment is located, shall be provided with at least
    one smoke shaft by means of which smoke and heat shall be mechanically vented to the outdoors as provided in reference standard RS 5-17. Buildings that are sprinklered throughout shall be exempt from the smoke shaft requirements. (c) Existing office
    buildings, one hundred feet or more in height, having air-conditioning and/or mechanical ventilation systems that serve more than the floor on which the equipment is located, shall be provided with at least one smoke shaft by means of which smoke
    and heat shall be mechanically vented to the outdoors as provided in reference standard RS 5-17, or in lieu of such smoke shaft or shafts, all interior enclosed stairs other than a fire tower or access stairs may be provided with a system of pressurization
    for fire emergency use. Such pressurization shall be provided by means of a system or systems as provided in reference standard RS 5-18. Such buildings shall comply with the smoke and heat venting requirements herein on or before September thirteenth,
    nineteeen hundred eighty-two. Complete plans showing such compliance shall be filed with, and a permit secured from, the commissioner on or before September thirteenth, nineteen hundred eighty. Existing buildings that are sprinklered throughout shall
    be exempt from the smoke shaft and stair pressurization requirements. An existing building which is to be sprinklered throughout shall be exempt from the smoke shaft and stair pressurization requirements under the following conditions: (1) the installation
    proceeds in conformance with a schedule acceptable to the commissioner, setting forth the sequence and corresponding time for installation in the various locations. On or before September thirteenth, nineteen hundred eighty such a schedule, as well
    as complete plans of the installation, shall be filed with, and a permit secured from, the commissioner for the phase of the work to be done as required by paragraph two of this subdivision. (2) at least one-third of the total floor area of the building,
    including but not limited to the entrance lobby, corridors and elevator landing areas, is sprinklered on or before December thirteenth, nineteen hundred eighty-one. (3) at least two-thirds of the total floor area of the building is sprinklered on
    or before December thirteenth, nineteen hundred eighty-two. (4) the building is sprinklered throughout on or before December thirteenth, nineteen hundred eighty-three. Where compliance with the time requirements of this subdivision would cause undue
    hardship, the commissioner, with the approval of the fire commissioner, may extend the time for compliance, in accordance with rules and regulations to be promulgated. Before such application for a time extension shall be considered all required applications
    and plans must be filed and approved, permits obtained and a good faith effort towards completion of the work shall have been made.</text>
</level>