<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>25-405</num>
  <heading>District plan.</heading>
  <text>ยง 25-405 District plan. (a) The mayor may provide for the preparation of a district plan, upon his or her own initiative, or at the request of an individual or agency designated by him or her, or at the request of the city council, or upon the written
    petition, signed and acknowledged, of (1) the owners of at least fifty-one percent of the assessed valuation of all the taxable real property within the boundaries of the district proposed for establishment or extension, as shown upon the latest completed
    assessment roll of the city, and (2) at least fifty-one percent of the owners of real property within the area included in the district proposed for the establishment or extension. (b) The establishment or extension of a district shall be based upon
    the district plan filed in the office of the city clerk, except as provided in subdivision (c) of this section. (c) The district plan shall first be submitted to the city planning commission which shall forward a copy within five days to the city
    council and to the council member or members representing the council district or districts in which the proposed district is located, to the community board or boards for the community district or districts in which the proposed district is located,
    and to the respective borough board and borough president, if the plan involves properties located in two or more community districts. Each community board shall notify the public of the proposed plan in accordance with the requirements established
    by the city planning commission, and may conduct a public hearing and submit a written recommendation to the city planning commission not later than thirty days after receipt of the plan. The city planning commission shall review the plan and recommendations,
    and, after a public hearing, prepare a report. The city planning commission shall submit its report to the mayor, to the affected borough president, to the city council and to the council member or members representing the council district or districts
    in which the proposed district is located, together with copies of any recommendation of a community board, within sixty days from the date of expiration of the community board's period for reviewing the plan and submitting recommendations. This report
    shall certify the city planning commission's unqualified approval, disapproval or qualified approval with recommendations for modifications of the district plan. A copy of this report together with the original district plan shall be transmitted for
    filing with the city clerk. In the event the city planning commission shall fail to submit its report within ninety-five days of receipt of the original district plan, it shall be required to immediately transmit the original plan to the city clerk
    for filing and no report of the city planning commission shall be necessary. (d) All district plans shall conform with the requirements of this chapter. The mayor may determine that the plan or any part of the plan, shall be prepared by, or under
    the supervision of city officers and employees to be designated by the mayor, or by persons or firms to be employed for that purpose. Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the expense incurred for the preparation of the plan or part of the
    plan shall be a city charge. (e) If the city shall thereafter establish or extend the district or provide the improvements or additional services or contract for the required services, the expense incurred by the city for the preparation of the plan
    or any part of the plan shall be deemed to be part of the cost of the improvement, or the rendering of additional services, and the city shall be reimbursed in the amount paid, or the portion of that amount which the city council, at a public hearing
    held pursuant to this chapter, shall allocate against the district.</text>
</level>