<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-203</num>
  <heading>Photo identification card required.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-203 Photo identification card required. a. The market manager shall issue photo identification cards to those principals, employees and agents of any business licensed pursuant to this chapter who perform any function directly related to the handling
    or transportation of seafood within or from the market area. Such cards shall be termed class A photo identification cards and shall be issued subject to the provisions set forth in section 22-216 of this chapter and the fee for such card established
    by the commissioner by rule pursuant to section 22-223 of this chapter. Such cards shall be displayed so as to be readily visible to others during the hours of market operation, as designated by the market manager. b. (i) In addition to the identification
    cards issued pursuant to subdivision a of this section, the market manager shall issue photo identification cards to those principals and employees of any business entity registered pursuant to this chapter and also to any agent of such registrant,
    other person or business entity who performs any function directly related to the handling and transportation of seafood within or from the market area. Such identification cards shall be termed class B photo identification cards and shall be issued
    subject to such requirements and fees as the commissioner shall promulgate by rule pursuant to section 22-223 of this chapter. Such cards shall be displayed so as to be readily visible to others during the hours of market operation designated by the
    market manager. (ii) Notwithstanding any provision of this subdivision, the commissioner may, when there is reasonable cause to believe that an applicant for a class B photo identification card lacks good character, honesty and integrity, require
    that such applicant be fingerprinted and provide to the commissioner the information set forth in subdivision a of section 22-216 of this chapter. The commissioner may thereafter, after notice and opportunity to be heard, refuse to issue a photo identification
    card for the reasons set forth in subdivision b of such section. (iii) If at any time subsequent to the issuance of a class B photo identification card, there is reasonable cause to believe that the holder thereof does not possess good character,
    honesty and integrity, the commissioner may require such person to be fingerprinted and to provide the background information required by subdivision a of section 22-216 of this chapter and may, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, revoke such
    class B photo identification card for the reasons set forth in subdivision b of such section. c. The market manager may, where appropriate, issue a provisional photo identification card to an employee or agent of a licensee or registrant who has submitted
    the information and fee required by this chapter or any rules promulgated thereunder. A photo identification card issued pursuant to this paragraph shall be valid until the commissioner has either issued or denied a permanent identification card,
    unless such provisional card has been revoked or suspended prior thereto in accordance with the procedures set forth in this chapter. The market manager, may, in his or her discretion, also make provision for temporary identification cards, which
    shall be valid for a period not to exceed six weeks, to be issued to persons employed by unloaders, loaders, wholesalers and seafood deliverers on a seasonal or other temporary basis. d. A photo identification card issued pursuant to this section
    shall bear a photograph of the person to whom it was issued and such other identifying information as may be specified by the commissioner.</text>
</level>