<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-365</num>
  <heading>Egress from rooms and spaces.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-365 Egress from rooms and spaces. (a) There shall be at least two door openings, remote from each other and leading to exits, from every room or enclosed space in which the total occupant loads exceeds the number of persons listed in table 6-3.
    Table 6-3 Maximum Occupant Load--Spaces With One Door Max. Occupant Load ======================================================================== Occupancy Group Max. Occupant Load Classification With One Door ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    A 10 B 50 C 75 D 50 E 75 F 75 G 75 H 15 J 20 ======================================================================== (b) Except as otherwise provided for in subdivisions (c) and (d) of this section, in buildings of combustible construction group
    II exceeding two stories in height there shall be at least two door openings from each J-1 or J-2 dwelling unit which shall be remote from each other. Each door opening shall lead to separate exits either directly or by separate corridors or one door
    opening shall lead to an exit and the other to a balcony complying with subdivision (g) of section 27-369 of article five of this subchapter. (c) In buildings or spaces classified in occupancy group J-2 not more than three stories and forty feet in
    height, occupied by not more than four families on each story and of combustible construction group II there shall be at least two door openings from each J-2 dwelling unit which shall be remote from each other. One door opening shall lead to an exit
    and the other to a balcony complying with subdivision (g) of section 27-369 of article five of this subchapter. TABLES 4-1 and 4-2 OMITTED (d) Buildings not exceeding three stories in height and occupied exclusively by not more than one family on
    each story without boarders, roomers or lodgers are exempt from the provisions of subdivisions (b) and (c) of this section.</text>
</level>