<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-205</num>
  <heading>Investigations and studies by the commissioner.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-205 Investigations and studies by the commissioner. (a) The commissioner may make or cause to be made any investigation or study which in his or her opinion is desirable for the purpose of enforcing this code or controlling or abating an unreasonable
    or prohibited noise. For such purposes, the commissioner may make tests, conduct hearings, compel the attendance of witnesses, and take their testimony under oath and may compel the production of books, papers and other things reasonably necessary
    to the matter under consideration. (b) The commissioner shall study and propose strategies to control and/or reduce sound levels associated with airports, rapid transit and railroad operations and within twenty-four months of the effective date of
    this section shall report to the mayor his or her findings and recommendations, specifically identifying those recommendations that may only be implemented through state or federal legislation or rules. (c) The commissioner, in conjunction with the
    police department, shall study noise abatement strategies for audible motor vehicle burglar alarms and within twenty-four months of the effective date of this section shall report to the mayor his or her findings and recommendations. (d) The commissioner,
    in conjunction with the police department, shall study on an ongoing basis emerging technology in acoustical measurement and shall periodically report to the mayor his or her findings and recommendations regarding the testing and potential use of
    equipment for enforcement of this code. In conjunction with such study, the commissioner may issue a request for expressions of interest to determine new and emerging technological solutions for accurate and efficient measurement of sounds as enumerated
    in this code. (e) The commissioner shall study the impact of motor vehicle back-up warning devices installed on motor vehicles on ambient sound levels and within twenty-four months of the effective date of this section shall report to the mayor his
    or her findings and recommendations, specifically identifying those recommendations that may only be implemented through state or federal legislation.</text>
</level>