<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-702</num>
  <heading>Port Morris zone.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-702 Port Morris zone. a. There is hereby established in the borough of the Bronx an empire zone as follows: BEGINNING at the point where the center line of the prolongation of East 157th Street meets the U.S. pierhead and bulkhead line located
    on the Bronx County side of the Harlem River; thence southerly and easterly along the said U.S. pierhead and bulkhead line to a point where said pierhead and bulkhead lines divide; thence northerly along the U.S. pierhead line of the East River to
    the point where it meets the easterly terminus of East 149th Street; thence northwesterly along the center line of East 149th Street to the point where it meets the center line of Southern Boulevard; thence southerly along the center line of Southern
    Boulevard to the point where it meets the center line of East 145th Street; thence westerly along the center line of East 145th Street to the point where it meets the center line of the block bounded on the west by Jackson Avenue and on the east by
    Concord Street; thence southerly along the center line of such block to the point where it meets the center line of East 144th Street, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-1 and M1-2 zoning districts as it appears on Sheet 6c
    of the Zoning Map of the New York City Planning Commission as amended effective February eighth, nineteen hundred ninety (A-1571), as contained in the Zoning Resolution of the City of New York; thence westerly along the center line of east 144th Street
    to the point where it meets the center line of Jackson Avenue, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-1 and M1-2 zoning districts as it appears on Sheet 6c as described aforesaid; thence southerly along the center line of Jackson
    Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of St. Mary's Street; thence westerly along the center line of St. Mary's Street to the point where it meets the center line of Cypress Avenue, said line being the district boundary lines between
    the M1-2 and R7-1 zoning districts and the R6 and R7-1 zoning districts as they appear on Sheet 6c as described aforesaid; thence southerly along the center line of Cypress Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of East 139th Street; thence
    westerly along the center line of East 139th Street to the point where it meets the center line of Morris Avenue; thence northerly along the center line of Morris Avenue to the point where it meets the southerly street line of East 148th Street; thence
    easterly along the southerly street line of East 148th Street to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Brook Avenue; thence northerly along the westerly street line of Brook Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of East
    159th Street; thence easterly along the center line of East 159th Street to the point where it meets the center line of St. Ann's Avenue/Third Avenue, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-2 and R6 zoning districts as it appears
    on Sheet 6c as described aforesaid; thence northerly along the center line of St. Ann's Avenue/Third Avenue to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Boston Road; thence northeasterly along the westerly street line of Boston Road to
    the point where it meets the northerly street line of East 166th Street; thence northwesterly and then westerly along the northerly street line of East 166th Street to the point where it meets the easterly street line of Third Avenue; thence northerly
    along the easterly street line of Third Avenue to the point where it meets the southerly street line of East 168th Street; thence northwesterly along the southerly street line of East 168th Street to the point where it meets the westerly street line
    of Webster Avenue; thence southerly along the westerly street line of Webster Avenue to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Brook Avenue; thence southeasterly along the westerly street line of Brook Avenue to the point where it meets
    the northerly street line of East 162nd Street; thence westerly along the northerly street line of East 162nd Street to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Grant Avenue; thence northerly along the westerly street line of Grant Avenue
    to the point where it meets the southerly street line of East 163rd Street; thence westerly along the southerly street line of East 163rd street to the point where it meets the center line of Concourse Village West/Sheridan Avenue; thence southerly
    along the center line of Concourse Village West/Sheridan Avenue to a point 541 feet to the south of the southerly street line of East 161st Street, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-1 and R8 zoning districts, the C4-6 and C8-3
    zoning districts and the R8 and C8-3 zoning districts as they appear on Sheet 3b of the Zoning Map of the New York City Planning Commission as amended effective March sixth, nineteen hundred ninety-two (A-1632) and Sheet 6a of the Zoning Map of the
    New York City Planning Commission as amended effective January twenty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-three (A-1648), as contained in the Zoning Resolution of the City of New York; thence easterly along a line 541 feet to the south of East 161st Street
    and running parallel thereto to the point where it meets the center line of Concourse Village East/Morris Avenue, said line being the district boundary line between the C8-3 and the R8 zoning districts as it appears on Sheet 6a as described aforesaid;
    thence northerly along the center line of Concourse Village East/Morris Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of East 161st Street, said line being the district boundary line between the C8-3 and R8 zoning districts as it appears on Sheet
    6a as described aforesaid; thence easterly along the center line of East 161st Street to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Third Avenue; thence southerly along the westerly street line of Third Avenue to the point where it meets
    the northerly street line of East 152nd Street; thence westerly along the northerly street line of East 152nd Street to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Melrose Avenue; thence southerly along the westerly street line of Melrose
    Avenue to the point where it meets the northerly street line of East 149th Street; thence westerly along the northerly street line of East 149th Street to the point where it meets the southeastern prolongation of the northerly street line of East
    151st Street; thence northwesterly along the southeastern prolongation of the northerly street line of East 151st Street and the northerly street line of East 151st Street to the point where it meets the easterly street line of Gerard Avenue; thence
    northerly along the easterly street line of Gerard Avenue to the point where it meets the northerly street line of East 162nd Street; thence northwesterly along the northerly street line of East 162nd Street to the point where it meets the center
    line of River Avenue; thence southerly along the center line of River Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of East 161st Street, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-1 and R8 zoning districts as it appears on Sheet
    3b as described aforesaid; thence westerly along the center line of East 161st Street to the point where it meets the center line of Ruppert Place, said line being the district boundary line between the C8-3 and R7-1 zoning districts as it appears
    on Sheet 3b as described aforesaid; thence southwesterly along the center line of Ruppert Place to the point where it meets the center line of East 157th Street, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-1 and C8-3 zoning districts
    as it appears on Sheet 3b and Sheet 6a as described aforesaid; thence westerly along the center line of East 157th Street and its prolongation to the point and place of beginning. There is one subzone: BEGINNING at the point of intersection of the
    easterly street line of Park Avenue and the southerly street line of East 174th Street; thence southerly along the easterly street line of Park Avenue to the point where it meets the northerly street line of Claremont Parkway; thence easterly along
    the northerly street line of Claremont Parkway to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Fulton Avenue; thence northerly along the westerly street line of Fulton Avenue to the point where it meets the southerly street line of the Cross
    Bronx Expressway; thence westerly along the southerly street line of the Cross Bronx Expressway to the point where it meets the easterly street line of Washington Avenue; thence southerly along the easterly street line of Washington Avenue to the
    point where it meets the southerly street line of East 174th Street; thence westerly along the southerly street line of East 174th Street to the point and place of beginning. b. The chairperson of the economic development corporation shall be the
    zone certification officer of the Port Morris empire zone. c. The administrative board of the Port Morris empire zone shall be comprised of: 1. the commissioner of the department of small business services; 2. the president of the economic development
    corporation; 3. the commissioner of social services; 4. the commissioner of the department of housing preservation and development; 5. the member or members of the city council whose districts include the Port Morris zone; 6. a member appointed by
    the president of the borough of the Bronx. Such member shall serve for a term of two years from the date of appointment and shall be removable without cause by the borough president; 7. a representative of the local chamber of commerce or like group
    appointed by the mayor. Such member shall serve for a term of two years from the date of appointment and shall be removable without cause by the mayor; and 8. a representative of a local community group appointed by the mayor. Such member shall serve
    for a term of two years from the date of appointment and shall be removable without cause by the mayor. d. The commissioner of the department of small business services shall be the chairperson of the board. The administrative board shall choose at
    its first meeting one of its members who shall be treasurer and may appoint a secretary. e. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum of such board. f. Whenever any act is authorized to be done or any determination or decision made by the
    board, the act, determination or decisions of the majority of the board shall be held to be the act, determination or decision of the board. g. Members of the board shall serve as such without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary
    out-of-pocket expenses in connection with attendance at regularly scheduled meetings of the board. h. The board shall meet at least four times each year. i. Upon approval by the empire zones designation board, pursuant to subdivision (a-3) of section
    960 of the general municipal law, of the initial distinct and separate contiguous area described by block and lot in subdivision j of this section, the boundaries of the zone set forth in subdivision a of this section shall be superseded by subdivision
    j of this section. j. There is hereby established in the borough of the Bronx an empire zone consisting of the following blocks and lots: Block: 2260 Lots: 1; 4; 10; 17; 18; 19; 34; 38; 62; 100; 140; 180; 192; 193. Block: 2261 Lots: 3; 5; 9; 15; 22;
    23; 27; 30; 32; 37; 38; 43; 45; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 55; 62. Block: 2277 Lots: 1; 2; 5; 10; 50; 51; 70; 78; 82; 92; 94. Block: 2278 Lots: 1; 4; 5; 9; 12; 13; 14; 15; 16; 17; 18; 19; 20; 21; 22; 23; 24; 25; 26; 27; 28; 29; 30; 31; 33; 34; 35; 36; 37;
    38; 39; 40; 41; 42; 43; 44; 45; 46; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 53; 56; 59; 61; 64; 70; 75; 77. Block: 2293 Lots: 1; 4; 7; 8; 21; 23. Block: 2294 Lots: 1; 2. Block: 2295 Lots: 49; 51; 67; 71. Block: 2296 Lots: 1; 3; 4; 5; 6; 7; 8; 9; 10; 11; 12; 13; 14; 15;
    18; 20; 26; 42; 43; 44; 45; 46; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 52; 53; 54; 55; 56; 57; 102. Block: 2308 Lots: 1; 5; 15; 18. Block: 2309 Lots: 1; 20; 21; 22; 23; 24; 25; 26; 27; 28; 29; 30; 31; 33. Block: 2316 Lots: 1; 35. Block: 2317 Lots: 1; 5; 6; 8; 9; 10;
    13; 15; 17; 19; 22; 23; 25; 33; 35; 41; 43; 51; 52; 53. Block: 2318 Lots: 5; 7; 9; 15; 16; 18; 19; 22; 75; 100. Block: 2319 Lots: 2; 37; 55; 62; 98; 99; 100; 108; 109; 112; 120; 200. Block: 2320 Lots: 5; 6; 7; 8; 9; 10; 11; 32; 33; 37; 41; 42; 43;
    45; 46; 47; 50; 51; 53; 59; 66; 72; 73; 74; 77; 79; 88; 164; 185. Block: 2322 Lots: 1; 5; 15; 28; 67; 71; 81; 101; 104; 111; 129. Block: 2323 Lots: 5; 13; 18; 28; 43; 60; 112; 114; 130. Block: 2327 Lots: 38; 39; 48; 51; 52; 54; 61; 64; 72. Block:
    2328 Lots: 24; 25; 32; 33; 35; 37; 39; 42; 43. Block: 2330 Lots: 1; 5; 7; 10; 11; 12; 14; 15; 16; 17; 18; 19; 20; 22; 24; 26; 30; 34; 37; 38; 39; 44; 45; 51; 53; 57; 59; 61; 62; 66; 69; 70; 73; 77. Block: 2331 Lots: 1; 3; 4; 5; 6; 7; 9; 10; 11; 12;
    13; 15; 16; 18; 19; 21; 22; 28; 29; 30; 33; 34; 36; 39; 41; 43; 48; 49; 50; 51; 52; 54; 55; 56; 57; 63; 64; 66; 68; 69; 70; 71; 72; 74. Block: 2333 Lots: 1; 6; 10; 12; 26; 33; 50. Block: 2334 Lots: 43; 45. Block: 2338 Lots: 3. Block: 2340 Lots: 1;
    3; 8; 11; 14; 16; 20; 28; 40; 42; 56; 58; 63; 72; 105; 107; 108; 110; 113; 115; 116; 119; 131; 133; 142; 145; 186; 195; 204; 208; 209; 213; 215; 218; 219; 220; 221; 372. Block: 2341 Lots: 1; 6; 10; 23; 28; 31; 34; 37; 40; 42; 54; 55; 58; 60; 150.
    Block: 2342 Lots: 1; 7; 13. Block: 2343 Lots: 1; 4; 6; 9; 10; 12; 14; 32. Block: 2344 Lots: 1; 11; 17; 27; 52; 60; 75; 83; 96; 110; 112. Block: 2345 Lots: 1; 5; 10; 12; 14; 18; 22; 26; 49. Block: 2346 Lots: 1; 18; 29; 43. Block: 2347 Lots: 1; 4; 5;
    6; 7; 8; 10; 11; 12; 13; 14; 15; 16; 17; 18; 19; 20; 23; 24; 31; 33; 34; 35; 37; 38. Block: 2348 Lots: 1; 4; 5; 13; 14; 15; 28; 29; 30; 31; 32; 33; 34; 35; 36. Block: 2349 Lots: 3; 15; 20; 38; 46; 47; 80; 90; 100; 103; 107; 112; 146. Block: 2350 Lots:
    1; 5; 11; 16; 24; 29; 34; 39; 63. Block: 2351 Lots: 1; 3; 12; 20; 22; 25; 35. Block: 2352 Lots: 3; 6; 15; 28; 40; 41; 42; 43; 45; 46; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 52; 53; 147. Block: 2353 Lots: 1; 16; 20; 28; 29; 30; 31; 32; 33; 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 39; 40;
    41; 42; 43; 44; 45; 46; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 52; 53; 54. Block: 2354 Lots: 1; 20. Block: 2362 Lots: 1; 7; 10; 11; 12; 13; 15; 21; 25; 26; 38; 39; 40; 41; 42; 43; 44; 48; 49; 71; 72. Block: 2363 Lots: 4; 7; 12; 14; 16; 24. Block: 2364 Lots: 1; 2; 3;
    4; 5; 6; 7; 8; 9; 10; 13; 15; 17; 19; 21; 22; 23; 24; 25; 45; 49; 51; 52; 55; 56; 58; 60; 61; 70. Block: 2365 Lots: 1; 9; 12; 14; 15; 17; 20; 22; 23; 24; 25; 26; 29. Block: 2366 Lots: 1. Block: 2367 Lots: 1; 3; 6; 7; 8; 10; 11; 12; 14; 15; 16; 17;
    18; 28; 29; 30; 31; 32; 33; 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 50; 55; 60. Block: 2368 Lots: 2; 4; 5; 6; 7; 8; 9; 12; 14; 15; 17; 19; 21; 23; 27; 28; 35; 37; 38; 48; 50; 51; 55. Block: 2369 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6; 8; 9; 10; 12; 13; 14; 16; 18; 20; 21; 23; 24; 25;
    26; 27; 28; 29; 30; 32; 34; 36; 37; 38; 39; 40; 41; 45; 47; 48; 53; 54; 55; 56; 57; 58; 59; 60; 61; 62; 63; 64; 65; 66; 67; 68; 69; 70; 71; 90; 100; 153. Block: 2370 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6; 7; 8, 9; 13; 16; 17; 23; 24; 25; 26; 27; 29; 30; 32; 33;
    34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 39; 40; 41; 43; 44; 45; 47; 49; 50; 52; 143. Block: 2371 Lots: 1; 4; 5; 6; 9; 10; 11; 12; 13; 15; 17; 19; 22; 23; 24; 27; 29; 31; 55; 56; 57; 58; 61; 64; 65; 70. Block: 2372 Lots: 1; 7; 9; 11; 13; 15; 18; 20. Block: 2373 Lots:
    1; 3; 4, 5; 6; 7; 9; 10; 12; 14; 21; 23; 24, 25; 27; 37; 38; 43; 48; 50; 148. Block: 2374 Lots: 1; 4; 9; 10; 15; 17; 18; 20; 21; 41, 45; 48; 51; 56; 59; 60; 85; 86; 90; 97. Block: 2375 Lots: 18; 19; 21; 23; 24; 26; 27; 42; 43; 48. Block: 2376 Lots:
    23; 25; 27; 47; 49; 51; 53; 54; 165; 167; 169; 171; 173; 175. Block: 2377 Lots: 20; 41; 42; 49; 54; 55; 56; 57; 60; 144; 146; 148; 150; 152; 154; 160. Block: 2384 Lots: 25; 28; 32; 33; 34; 61. Block: 2385 Lots: 1; 3; 7; 11; 15; 17; 18; 23; 30; 33;
    34; 35; 36; 38; 44; 45; 49; 50; 51; 53; 55; 59; 65. Block: 2386 Lots: 1; 2; 5; 7; 8; 11; 17; 20; 21; 22; 24; 29; 30; 34; 35; 37; 40; 43; 56; 57; 58; 59; 65; 66; 67; 74; 136; 144; 164. Block: 2387 Lots: 1; 10; 25; 29; 31; 32; 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 40;
    41; 44; 49; 51; 55. Block: 2388 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 5; 8; 10; 11; 12; 13; 16; 17; 18; 19; 20; 22; 25; 28; 29; 30; 34; 37; 45; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 52; 53; 54; 57; 58; 59; 61; 63; 64; 65; 67; 68; 69; 71; 74; 85; 87. Block: 2389 Lots: 1; 7; 11; 13; 14; 16;
    20; 26; 27; 28; 31; 32; 33; 34; 38; 39; 40; 43; 45; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 54; 55; 56; 57; 65. Block: 2391 Lots: 1; 45; 49; 52; 62; 63. Block: 2392 Lots: 1; 6; 16; 20; 25; 35; 38; 40; 41; 42; 46; 51; 56; 66; 71. Block: 2393 Lots: 1; 5; 6; 10; 14; 16;
    20; 21; 22; 26. Block: 2394 Lots: 1; 5; 17; 23; 24; 28; 29; 30; 34. Block: 2425 Lots: 20. Block: 2426 Lots: 17; 21; 25; 64; 75; 82. Block: 2443 Lots: 1; 4; 300; 400. Block: 2543 Lots: 1; 30; 40; 50; 60. Block: 2546 Lots: 1; 11; 15; 19; 27; 33; 52;
    64; 67; 74; 82; 90; 94; 95; 96; 97; 98; 99; 100; 101; 135; 137; 138; 140; 141. Block: 2552 Lots: 40; 45; 145; 146; 147; 148; 149; 150; 151; 152; 153. Block: 2553 Lots: 36; 46; 47; 48; 49; 51; 52. Block: 2554 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 26; 44; 49; 54; 60. Block:
    2557 Lots: 61; 62; 80. Block: 2561 Lots: 1; 13; 15; 17; 18; 19; 21; 25; 35; 36; 37; 39; 42; 46; 47; 50; 56; 58; 60; 78; 80; 81; 82; 83; 84; 94. Block: 2562 Lots: 1; 17; 18; 19; 20; 21; 23; 25; 26; 27; 28; 29; 30; 31; 32; 33; 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 40;
    41; 49; 56; 58; 60; 61; 62; 64; 65; 66; 67; 68; 69; 70; 71; 72; 73; 74; 75; 80; 81; 82; 83; 84; 85; 86; 88; 89; 90; 91; 92; 93; 94; 95. Block: 2563 Lots: 12; 15; 17; 21; 26; 28; 31; 40; 56. Block: 2564 Lots: 1; 5; 10; 38; 40; 45; 47; 51; 58; 61; 63;
    72. Block: 2565 Lots: 1; 8; 25; 28; 47; 49; 50; 51; 52; 53; 54; 55; 56; 60; 65; 66; 68; 69; 70; 71; 72; 74; 75; 76; 78; 80. Block: 2566 Lots: 5; 6; 10; 14; 18; 20; 22; 25; 26; 30; 32; 36; 37; 38; 41; 55; 60; 61; 62; 66; 68; 70; 71. Block: 2567 Lots:
    6; 7; 8; 9; 10; 13; 26; 30. Block: 2568 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 6; 8; 9; 12; 20; 39; 40; 41; 45; 46; 47; 48; 49; 51; 54; 57; 60; 63; 68; 73; 76; 145; 170; 180; 181. Block: 2569 Lots: 1; 5; 20; 25; 29; 32. Block: 2570 Lots: 1; 4; 6; 10; 16; 18; 35; 38; 39;
    42; 45. Block: 2571 Lots: 1; 14; 23; 24; 25; 26; 28; 29; 30; 31; 32; 132. Block: 2572 Lots: 1; 6; 56; 57; 59; 60; 61; 63; 64; 65; 67; 68; 69; 70; 71; 72; 73; 74; 75; 76; 162. Block: 2573 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6; 7; 8; 9; 10; 21; 22; 23; 24; 25; 26;
    27; 28; 29; 30; 31; 32; 33; 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 39; 40; 41; 44; 49; 56; 71; 78; 81; 87; 91; 101. Block: 2574 Lots: 1; 40; 46; 53; 56; 64; 70; 74; 77; 78; 79; 82. Block: 2575 Lots: 28; 31; 34; 41; 50; 65. Block: 2576 Lots: 1; 5; 6; 7; 17; 21; 23; 25.
    Block: 2577 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 6; 7; 8; 20; 22; 24. Block: 2578 Lots: 1; 18; 21. Block: 2583 Lots: 2; 30; 50; 62; 365; 368; 500; 650. Block: 2584 Lots: 1; 17; 24; 48. Block: 2585 Lots: 1; 18; 19; 26; 62. Block: 2586 Lots: 1; 12; 14; 19; 20; 26;
    65. Block: 2587 Lots: 1; 11; 21; 22; 30; 40; 43; 46; 48; 50; 69; 72. Block: 2588 Lots: 1; 8; 14; 17; 22; 33; 73. Block: 2589 Lots: 1; 15; 16; 25; 31. Block: 2590 Lots: 1; 16; 20; 36; 44; 51; 84; 89; 98; 100; 102. Block: 2591 Lots: 17; 23; 30; 37;
    38; 44; 46; 85; 88. Block: 2592 Lots: 1; 13; 17; 19; 21; 28; 34; 35; 69; 70; 72. Block: 2593 Lots: 1; 30. Block: 2594 Lots: 1; 5; 30; 35; 50. Block: 2595 Lots: 1; 33; 35; 39; 107; 500. Block: 2596 Lots: 1; 10; 20; 40; 60. Block: 2597 Lots: 1; 41;
    70; 105. Block: 2598 Lots: 1; 46; 62; 66; 70; 74; 77; 78; 79; 80; 82; 83; 86; 98. Block: 2599 Lots: 1; 2; 5; 61; 62; 69; 87; 89; 90; 92; 100; 101; 107; 110; 128; 139; 146; 165; 175; 200; 269; 295; 400. Block: 2600 Lots: 1; 25; 28; 30; 43; 47; 49;
    50; 51; 70; 71; 72; 73; 74; 75; 76; 77; 78; 79; 89; 96; 99; 100; 101; 103; 122; 125; 131; 142; 148; 150; 153; 159; 166; 167; 168; 169; 170; 186; 187; 191; 193; 194; 195; 196; 197; 198; 199; 200; 202; 206; 208; 213; 220; 222; 250. Block: 2601 Lots:
    1; 7; 12; 20; 24; 35; 48; 50; 54; 57; 61; 65; 67. Block: 2607 Lots: 2; 6; 7; 8; 9; 11; 12; 13; 14; 17; 23; 26; 29; 32; 34; 37; 38; 43; 44; 45; 46; 47; 67; 68; 72; 78; 81; 84; 85; 86; 87; 91; 93; 95; 96; 97; 100. Block: 2608 Lots: 1; 4; 9; 10; 11;
    12; 19. Block: 2888 Lots: 39; 43; 50; 58. Block: 2889 Lots: 29; 33; 35; 38; 40; 41; 43; 44; 61; 88; 92; 93. Block: 2890 Lots: 20; 24; 56; 60; 66; 71; 73. Block: 2892 Lots: 46; 49; 54; 59; 62; 63; 65; 73; 77; 85; 125. Block: 2897 Lots: 24; 29; 39;
    42; 44; 47; 48; 49; 51; 52; 53; 54; 55; 56; 57; 58; 61; 62; 124; 140; 142; 143; 182; 192. Block: 2898 Lots: 1; 10; 11; 13; 14; 16; 22; 24; 29; 31; 50; 51; 53; 54; 55; 58; 60; 85. Block: 2899 Lots: 1; 29; 34; 35; 37; 42; 44; 46; 48; 49; 50; 51; 53;
    58; 70. Block: 2900 Lots: 1; 4; 7; 10; 12; 15; 18; 20; 27; 28; 33; 39; 46; 48; 51; 77; 83; 90; 107. Block: 2904 Lots: 1; 10; 12; 16; 18; 20; 22; 23; 24; 25; 27; 29; 30; 31; 32; 34; 36; 39; 41; 42. Block: 2905 Lots: 1; 3; 6; 8; 10; 13; 16; 18; 20;
    24; 26; 28; 30; 38; 41; 44; 47; 49. Block: 2906 Lots: 51; 56; 57; 59; 63; 67; 68; 76; 78; 83; 89; 93; 97; 101; 102; 103; 104. Block: 2907 Lots: 1; 2; 6; 9; 10; 22; 23; 24; 25; 26; 27; 28; 29; 31; 52; 56; 57; 58; 59; 61; 63; 68; 75; 76. Block: 2908
    Lots: 1; 5; 8; 11; 13; 15; 17; 20; 22; 47. Block: 2909 Lots: 1; 40. Block: 2910 Lots: 1. Block: 2911 Lots: 1; 30. Block: 2912 Lots: 1; 2; 24; 25; 26; 113; 114; 115; 116; 117; 118; 119; 120; 121; 122; 123; 124; 125; 126; 127; 128; 129; 130; 131; 132;
    133; 134; 135; 136; 137; 138; 139; 140; 141; 142; 143; 144; 145; 146; 147; 148; 149; 150; 151; 152; 153; 154; 155; 156; 157; 158; 159; 160; 161. Block: 2913 Lots: 1; 42; 43. Block: 2914 Lots: 1. Block: 2915 Lots: 1. Block: 2916 Lots: 2. Block: 2919
    Lots: 1; 5; 39; 42; 43; 44; 45; 50. Block: 2920 Lots: 2. Block: 2921 Lots: 1. Block: 2922 Lots: 2. Block: 2929 Lots: 23; 50; 58; 65; 66; 67; 68; 74; 78; 82; 169; 170; 171; 172. Block: 2930 Lots: 1; 12; 26; 28; 29; 30; 39.</text>
</level>