<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-652</num>
  <heading>Paving.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 27-652 Paving. (a) Definitions. For the purposes of this article the following terms shall have the following definitions: ASPHALT. A dark brown to black bitumen pitch that melts readily and which appears in nature in asphalt beds or is produced
    as a by-product of the petroleum industry. ASPHALTIC CONCRETE or ASPHALT PAVING. A mixture of liquid asphalt and graded aggregate used as a paving material. I-4 MIX. A type of heavy duty asphaltic concrete mix containing 0.75 inch (19 mm) nominal
    maximum size aggregate with 25% to 50% of the aggregate capable of passing through a No. 8 sieve and in which all sand contained in the mix is crushed. RECLAIMED ASPHALT PAVEMENT. Asphalt pavement that has been processed for reuse in asphaltic concrete.
    (b) Reclaimed asphalt pavement content in asphaltic concrete. Asphaltic concrete, other than I-4 mix or other approved heavy duty asphaltic concrete mix, shall contain not less than thirty percent reclaimed asphalt pavement, as measured by weight.
    I-4 mix or other approved heavy duty asphaltic concrete mix shall contain not less than ten percent reclaimed asphalt pavement, as measured by weight. Reclaimed asphalt pavement used in asphaltic concrete shall comply with the version of ASTM D692
    or ASTM D1073 specified in chapter 35 of the New York city building code or in the rules of the department. This subdivision shall not apply to asphaltic concrete used in a project where the content of asphaltic concrete is governed by a federal or
    state law, rule, regulation, guideline, or specification that requires a different composition or to runways, taxiways, or other surfaces utilized by aircraft. The commissioner may waive compliance with this subdivision if the commissioner, after
    consulting with the commissioner of transportation and the owners or persons in charge of all asphalt plants located within the city, finds that a sufficient supply of reclaimed asphalt pavement is not available. * NB There are 2 ยง 27-652's * NB Effective
    January 1, 2015</text>
</level>