<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2127</num>
  <heading>Corrective action pursuant to court order.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2127 Corrective action pursuant to court order. a. The department may elect to proceed to take action to correct violations under this article pursuant to a prior court order. If the department so elects, it may serve, with any order served pursuant
    to subdivision a or b of section 27-2125 of this article, a notice that upon failure to comply with the order within the stated time the department may apply for a court order directing it to execute the repair order. b. Upon failure to comply with
    the repair order within the time fixed therein, the department may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for an order directing the owner and any mortgagees or lienors of record to show cause why the department should not be directed to execute
    the order, and obtain a lien for the costs of such execution which shall have priority over all other liens and encumbrances. The application shall identify the dwelling, describe the violations covered by the repair order, the work required to remedy
    such violations and an estimate of the cost thereof, and contain proof of service of the repair order as required by this section. c. The order to show cause shall be served in the manner prescribed for service of an order to show cause in a receivership
    proceeding by subdivision c of section 27-2132 of article six of this subchapter. d. On the return date of the order to show cause, determination thereof shall have precedence over every other business of the court unless the court shall find that
    some other pending proceeding, having similar statutory preference, has priority. If the court finds that the facts stated in the application warrant the granting thereof, it shall issue an order directing the department to proceed to execute its
    repair order, or such part thereof as remains unexecuted. e. If the owner or any mortgagee or lienor of record or other person having an interest in the property, shall apply to the court to be permitted to remove or remedy the violations specified
    in the repair order and shall: (1) demonstrate the ability promptly to undertake the work required; and (2) post security for the performance thereof within the time, and in the amount and manner, deemed necessary by the court, then the court in lieu
    of issuing an order as provided in subdivision d of this section, may issue an order permitting such person to perform the work within a time fixed by the court. f. If, after issuance of an order pursuant to subdivision e of this section, but before
    the time fixed in such order for the completion of the work prescribed therein, it shall appear to the department that the person permitted to do the same is not proceeding with due diligence, the department may apply to the court on notice to those
    persons who have appeared in the hearing under subdivision d of this section for a hearing to determine whether an order should be rendered immediately as provided in subdivision g of this section. g. If, upon a hearing authorized in subdivision f
    of this section, the court shall determine that such person is not proceeding with due diligence, or upon the failure of such person to complete the work in accordance with the provisions of said order, the court shall order the department to execute
    or complete the execution of said order. Such order shall direct the department to apply the security to the expenses incurred in the execution of the repair order. In the event that such security should exceed the amount required to remove or remedy
    such violations, such order shall direct the department to file with the court, upon completion of the work prescribed therein, a full accounting of the amount of such security and the expenditures made pursuant to such order, and to turn over such
    surplus to the person who posted such security, together with a copy of such accounting.</text>
</level>