<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-105.1</num>
  <heading>Trees, bushes and other vegetation obstructing a traffic signal or device.</heading>
  <text>ยง 18-105.1 Trees, bushes and other vegetation obstructing a traffic signal or device. a. Definitions. For purposes of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings: 1. "Traffic control signal" shall mean any such signal as defined
    in section 154 of the vehicle and traffic law. 2. "Select traffic control device" shall mean any stop sign, yield sign or do not enter sign. 3. "Traffic control device" shall mean any traffic control device as defined in section 153 of the vehicle
    and traffic law, other than a select traffic control device. b. The department shall inspect any location within four days of receiving notice that any traffic control signal, select traffic control device or traffic control device at such location
    is not visible or legible to a motorist who must obey or rely upon such sign due to an obstruction by a tree, bush or other vegetation or any portion thereof. c. The department shall within ten days of the inspection required pursuant to subdivision
    b of this section prune or cause to be pruned any tree, bush or other vegetation found to require pruning because it obstructs any select traffic control device or traffic control signal; provided that the department shall prioritize such pruning
    the department determines is most immediately needed to correct a hazard. d. The department shall within twenty days of the inspection required pursuant to subdivision b of this section prune or cause to be pruned any tree, bush or other vegetation
    found to require pruning because it obstructs any traffic control device. e. The department shall maintain a log of all notices of the type described in subdivision b of this section. Such log shall include the date and time such notice was received,
    the date and time on which such location was inspected, and the date and time when such tree, bush or other vegetation was pruned or the date and time of a determination that such tree, bush or other vegetation did not require pruning, as applicable.
  </text>
</level>