<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-952</num>
  <heading>Power and duties of the commission.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-952 Power and duties of the commission. The commission shall be responsible for the licensing and regulation of shipboard gambling businesses. The powers and duties of the commission shall include, but not be limited to the following: a. To issue
    and establish standards for the issuance, renewal, suspension and revocation of licenses, certificates of approval and registrations and waivers therefrom pursuant to this chapter; provided that the commission may by resolution delegate to the chair
    the authority to make individual determinations regarding the issuance, renewal, suspension and revocation of such licenses, certificates of approval and registrations and the appointment of independent auditors in accordance with the provisions of
    this chapter, except that a determination to refuse to issue a license, renewal, certificate of approval or registration or to refuse to grant a waiver therefrom pursuant to this chapter shall be made only by a majority vote of the commission. b.
    To investigate any matter within the jurisdiction conferred by this chapter, including, but not limited to, any matter that relates to the good character, honesty and integrity of any owner, officer or director of an applicant business entity, or
    affiliate or subsidiary thereof, irrespective of whether such person is a principal of such business as defined in subdivision 1 of section 20-950 of this chapter, and to have full power to compel the attendance, examine and take testimony under oath
    of such persons as it may deem necessary in relation to such investigation, and to require the production of books, accounts, papers and other documents and materials relevant to such investigation. c. To appoint, within the appropriations available
    therefor, such employees as may be required for the performance of the duties prescribed herein. In addition to such employees, the commission may request that the commissioner of any other appropriate city agency provide staff and other assistance
    to the commission in conducting background investigations for licenses, certificates of approval and registrations pursuant to this chapter in order that such work may be performed efficiently, within existing city resources. d. To conduct studies
    or investigations into matters related to gambling in the city and other jurisdictions in order to assist the city in formulating policies relating to the regulation of shipboard gambling. e. To establish standards for the conduct of shipboard gambling
    businesses. f. To set forth requirements necessary to protect the public health, safety and welfare, including but not limited to requirements for the provision of security for patrons on shipboard or on the pier or adjacent area in coordination with
    appropriate law enforcement authorities, and other measures to provide for the welfare of patrons on such piers and in such areas. g. To establish standards to protect consumers from fraudulent and misleading advertising and other solicitation of
    customers for shipboard gambling businesses. h. To establish fees and promulgate rules as the commission may deem necessary and appropriate to effectuate the purposes and provisions of this chapter.</text>
</level>