<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-241.1</num>
  <heading>a.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-241.1 a. Newsstands installed and maintained pursuant to a franchise. a. Construction. Upon the grant of a franchise, no person shall construct or install a newsstand other than a franchisee granted such a franchise. Newsstands installed and maintained
    pursuant to such a franchise shall comply with all applicable law, rules and regulations. b. Transition. Upon the grant of a franchise, each licensee operating or maintaining a newsstand licensed pursuant to this subchapter shall be provided with
    reasonable notice when such newsstand structure is to be replaced by a newsstand installed and maintained pursuant to such franchise at a location approved by the department of transportation and instructions for applying for a replacement newsstand
    within the catchment area of such newsstand. Such replacement shall be subject to contractual incentives and/or penalties, if any, to ensure timely replacement of the newsstand pursuant to such franchise. The licensee shall have the option of removing
    the existing structure or such structure shall be removed by the franchisee granted such franchise. Operation of the newsstand licensed pursuant to this subchapter shall cease during such time as the newsstand is replaced. Upon being notified of the
    completion of the replacement of the newsstand, the licensee may resume operation pursuant to the terms of his or her license and the provisions of this subchapter. c. Costs. 1. The cost of constructing and installing a replacement newsstand by the
    franchisee pursuant to such franchise shall be borne by the franchisee in accordance with such franchise. The cost of constructing and installing a newsstand by the franchisee pursuant to such franchise, which newsstand is not a replacement newsstand,
    shall be borne by the licensee of such newsstand in accordance with paragraph two of this subdivision. 2. A licensee who maintains or operates a newsstand that is not a replacement newsstand and that has been constructed and installed by the franchisee
    pursuant to such franchise shall reimburse the franchisee for the cost of such construction and installation, which cost shall include costs associated with any interior electric and/or telephone hook-ups to the newsstand structure. The department
    shall determine the applicable construction and installation costs for purposes of this paragraph, which costs shall be limited to the costs incurred by the franchisee and certified by the franchisee to the department. d. Fees. A licensee licensed
    to maintain or operate a newsstand constructed and installed by the franchisee pursuant to such franchise shall be liable for the payment to the department of the biennial fee for a license to operate a newsstand payable in accordance with subdivision
    b of section 20-230 of the code. e. Enforcement. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the commissioner shall be authorized, after notice and an opportunity to be heard, to order any person who is unlawfully operating a newsstand
    that has been constructed or installed by a person other than the franchisee in violation of subdivision a of this section to remove such newsstand within seven days of the issuance of such order. Such order shall be posted at the premises of such
    newsstand. If such person does not remove such newsstand within seven days of the issuance of such order, an authorized officer or employee of any city agency or a police officer is authorized to provide for the removal of such person's newsstand
    and the contents thereof to a place of safety. If such newsstand or the contents thereof are not claimed within thirty days after their removal, they shall be deemed to be abandoned and may be either sold at a public auction after having been advertised
    in the City Record, the proceeds thereof being paid into the general fund, used or converted for use by the department or another city agency, or otherwise disposed of. Newsstands and the contents thereof that are removed pursuant to this subdivision
    shall be released to the owner or other person lawfully entitled to possession upon payment of the costs for removal and storage and any civil penalty imposed for the violation or, if an action or proceeding for the violation is pending, upon the
    posting of a bond or other form of security acceptable to the department in an amount which will secure the payment of such costs and any penalty which may be imposed for the violation. In the event that any removal made pursuant to this subdivision
    shall include any perishable items, goods, or food products which cannot be retained in custody without such items, goods, or food products becoming unwholesome, putrid, decomposed or unfit in any way, they may be delivered to the commissioner of
    health and mental hygiene for disposition pursuant to the provisions of section 17-323 of this code.</text>
</level>