<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-998</num>
  <heading>Periodic inspection and test intervals.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-998 Periodic inspection and test intervals. Every new and existing device listed in article one of this subchapter except elevators located, (i) in owner occupied one-family or two-family dwellings provided that the elevator services only the owner
    occupied dwelling unit and that such dwelling unit is not occupied by boarders, roomers or lodgers, or (ii) within convents or rectories which are not accessible to non-occupants on a regular basis, or (iii) within an owner occupied dwelling unit
    which is not occupied by boarders, roomers or lodgers, shall be inspected and tested at least at the following intervals: (a) Elevators -- five times every two years, or as otherwise provided by the commissioner and except: (1) Car safeties and counterweight
    safeties, where provided, shall be inspected at intervals not exceeding one year and shall be tested at intervals not exceeding two years. (2) Oil buffers and governors shall be periodically inspected and shall be tested at intervals not exceeding
    one year. (3) Hydraulic elevator pressure tanks and the piston rods of roped hydraulic elevators every three years. (b) Escalators -- five times every two years. (c) Amusement devices -- every six months except that the commissioner may extend the
    periodic inspection and test for an additional two months for amusement devices located in premises which are seasonally operated. (d) Workers' hoists -- every three months and immediately following each increase in travel. (e) All other devices at
    such intervals as the commissioner may require. (f) Additional inspections -- in addition to the inspections required by subdivisions (a) through (e) of this section, the commissioner may make such additional inspections as required to enforce the
    provisions of this code. No fee shall be charged for such additional inspections. (g) Fees -- every owner of elevators and other devices shall pay to the department an inspection fee for each elevator or device in the amount prescribed by subdivision
    c of section 26-213 of title twenty-six of the administrative code.</text>
</level>