<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-182</num>
  <heading>Citizen's complaint.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-182 Citizen's complaint. (a) Any person, other than personnel of the department and employees of the city of New York authorized by law to serve summonses for violations of the code, may serve upon the department a complaint, in a form prescribed
    by the department, alleging that a person has violated any provision of this code or order or regulation promulgated by the commissioner or the board, except with respect to sections 24-143, 24-150 and 24-163 of this code, but still applicable to
    buses as defined in section one hundred four of the vehicle and traffic law and trucks as defined in section one hundred fifty eight of the vehicle and traffic law, together with evidence of such violation. With respect to section 24-142 of this code,
    only such person who has been certified as a smoke watcher, by passing a course of smoke observation approved by the department within three years prior to the observation, may serve such complaint. (b) A person who has served a complaint pursuant
    to subdivision (a) of this section may serve upon the person allegedly in violation, and upon the board, a notice of violation in a form prescribed by the board within forty-five days from service of such complaint if; (1) The department has failed
    to serve a notice of violation, pursuant to section 24-180 of this code, for the violation alleged in a complaint pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section; or (2) The department fails to serve a written notice upon the complainant of its determination
    that his or her complaint is frivolous or duplicitous. (c) A person commencing a proceeding pursuant to this section shall prosecute such proceeding at his or her own expense. The department may intervene in such a proceeding at any time. (d) In any
    proceeding brought by the department after receiving a complaint, pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section, pertaining to a violation of this code or any regulation or order promulgated by the commissioner or the board, wherein the source of the
    violation is a manufacturing or industrial facility or a facility for the generation of steam for off-premises sale or electricity or equipment used by any such facility, the board shall award the complainant, out of the proceeds collected, an amount
    which shall not exceed twenty-five percent of such proceeds, for disclosure of information or evidence, not in the possession of the department prior to the receipt of the complaint by the department, which leads to the imposition of the civil penalty.
    (e) In any proceeding brought by a complainant pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section, the board shall award, out of the proceeds collected, fifty percent of any civil penalty as fair and reasonable compensation to such person.</text>
</level>