<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-702</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-702 Definitions. For the purpose of this chapter the following terms shall mean: (a) "chemical name": the scientific designation of a chemical in accordance with the nomenclature system developed by the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry
    or the Chemical Abstracts Service (CAS) rules of nomenclature. (b) "citywide facility inventory database": a compendium of information filed by responsible parties with the department in accordance with this chapter regarding the location of hazardous
    substances. (c) "commissioner": the commissioner of the department of environmental protection. (d) "department": the department of environmental protection. (e) "disposal": the placing of any hazardous substance into any land or water so that such
    hazardous substances or any constituent thereof may be released into the environment. (f) "emergency response agencies": the departments of fire, police, environmental protection, health, transportation and sanitation, and the division of emergency
    medical services of the health and hospitals corporation. (g) "emergency response personnel": any member of the departments of fire, police, environmental protection, health, transportation and sanitation, the division of emergency services of health
    and hospitals corporation and any other government agency participating in response measures undertaken in connection with a fire, or a spill, or release or threatened release of a hazardous substance into the environment. For purposes of this chapter,
    the term "response measures" shall include actions taken by a city agency within the meaning of subdivision (f) of section 24-603. (h) "extremely hazardous substance": a substance on a list of extremely hazardous substances promulgated pursuant to
    42 U.S.C. section 11002(a). (i) "facility": all buildings, equipment, structures, and other stationary items that are located on a single site or on contiguous or adjacent sites and that are owned, leased or operated by the same person, or by any
    person which controls, or is controlled by or under common control with, such person, including any building, structure, installation or area involved in the processing, storage, handling, treatment, placement, disposal or use of any hazardous substance.
    (j) "facility inventory form": a standard written form, developed by the department for completion by a responsible party at each privately or publicly owned facility in the city of New York. (k) "hazardous substance": any chemical which is a physical
    hazard or a health hazard and which is listed on the hazardous substance list or special health hazard list. For purposes of this chapter, the term "hazardous substance" shall not include the following: (1) any food, food additive, color additive,
    drug, or cosmetic regulated by the federal food and drug administration; (2) any substance present as a solid in any manufactured item to the extent exposure to the substance does not occur under normal conditions of use; (3) any substance to the
    extent it is used for personal, family, or household purposes, or is present in the same form and concentration as a product packaged for distribution and use by the general public; (4) any substance to the extent it is used in routine agricultural
    operations or is a fertilizer held for sale by a retailer to the ultimate consumer; (5) any hazardous waste as such term is defined by the solid waste disposal act, as amended by the resource conservation and recovery act of nineteen hundred seventy-six,
    as amended (42 U.S.C. section 6901, et seq.); (6) tobacco or tobacco products; (7) wood or wood products; (8) articles, which for purposes of this subdivision shall mean manufactured items which (i) are formed to a specific shape or design during
    manufacture; (ii) which have an end use function or functions dependent in whole or in part upon their shape or design during end use; and (iii) which do not release, or otherwise result in exposure to, a hazardous substance, under normal conditions
    of use; (9) food, drugs, cosmetics, or alcoholic beverages in a retail establishment which are packaged for sale to consumers; (10) foods, drugs, or cosmetics intended for personal consumption by employees while in the work place; (11) any consumer
    product or hazardous substance, as those terms are defined in the consumer product safety act (15 U.S.C. section 2051, et seq.) and federal hazardous substances act (15 U.S.C. section 1261, et seq.) respectively, where the employer can demonstrate
    it is used in the workplace in the same manner as normal consumer use, and which use results in a duration and frequency of exposure which is not greater than exposures experienced by consumers; or (12) any drug, as that term is defined in the federal
    food, drug, and cosmetic act (21 U.S.C. section 301, et seq.), when it is in solid, final form for direct administration to a patient. (l) "hazardous substance list": a list of hazardous substances which the commissioner shall by regulation establish
    in accordance with section 24-703 of this chapter. The commissioner shall at the minimum include on the original list, those hazardous substances contained on the following existing list of dangerous substances: the New Jersey Right to Know, Hazardous
    Substance List developed pursuant to the Worker and Community Right to Know Act (New Jersey Administrative Code, stat. 34:5A-1 et seq.) as in effect in December of nineteen hundred eighty-seven. (m) "health hazard": a chemical for which there is statistically
    significant evidence based on at least one study conducted in accordance with the established scientific principles that acute or chronic health effects may occur in exposed persons. The term "health hazard" includes chemicals which are carcinogens,
    toxic or highly toxic agents, reproductive toxins, irritants, corrosives, sensitizers, hepatotoxins, nephrotoxins, neurotoxins, agents which act on the hematopoietic system, and agents which damage the lungs, skin, eyes, or mucous membranes. (n) "material
    safety data sheet" (MSDS): written or printed material concerning a hazardous substance which is identical in form and content to the data sheet described at 29 C.F.R. part 1910.1200 and required under subdivision (a) of section three hundred eleven
    of the emergency planning and community right-to-know act of nineteen hundred eighty-six (42 U.S.C. section 11001, et seq.). (o) "mixture": a combination of two or more substances not involving a chemical reaction. (p) "person": any individual, trust,
    firm, partnership, corporation, joint stock company, association, joint venture or government entity. (q) "physical hazard": a chemical for which there is scientifically valid evidence that it is a combustible liquid, a compressed gas, explosive,
    flammable, an organic peroxide, an oxidizer, pyrophoric, unstable (reactive) or water-reactive. (r) "regulated toxic substance": a substance on a list of regulated toxic substances promulgated pursuant to 42 U.S.C. section 7412 (r). (s) "responsible
    party": an owner, operator, manager, or corporate officer of the person who owns, leases or operates a facility, provided that if such facility is leased, the responsible party shall be the lessee of the facility or his or her representative. (t)
    "risk management plan": a plan filed by a responsible party with the commissioner pursuant to section 24-718 of this chapter. (u) "special health hazard list": a list of hazardous substances that the commissioner may develop through regulation which
    would consist of substances that have been proven to be carcinogenic, mutagenic or teratogenic, as established by at least one study conducted in accordance with established scientific principles, and thereby pose a special hazard to health and safety.
    (v) "treatment": any method, technique, or process, including neutralization, designed to change the physical, chemical, or biological character or composition of any hazardous substance so as to neutralize such substance or so as to render such substance
    nonhazardous, safe to transport, amendable to recovery, amendable to storage, or reduced in volume. Such term includes any activity or processing designed to change the physical form or chemical composition of a hazardous substance so as to render
    it nonhazardous.</text>
</level>