<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-112.10</num>
  <heading>Waiver of application, permit and inspection fees for certain work arising out of the storm that occurred on October 29 and 30, 2012.</heading>
  <text>ยง 28-112.10 Waiver of application, permit and inspection fees for certain work arising out of the storm that occurred on October 29 and 30, 2012. The commissioner shall waive the fees that would otherwise be required to be paid by this code, the electrical
    code or the rules of the department for applications, permits and inspections for certain work arising out of the storm that occurred on October 29 and 30, 2012 as provided in subsections 28-112.10.1 and 28-112.10.2. ยง 28-112.10.1 Eligible buildings.
    For the purposes of this article, eligible buildings are those buildings that, following the storm and pursuant to an inspection program established by the department under an emergency order of the Mayor, are designated by the department after inspection
    through a notation on the department's records and/or by the posting of a red placard warning on the building or premises as seriously damaged and unsafe to enter or occupy or completely demolished and/or washed away. With respect to eligible buildings,
    fees associated with applications, permits and inspections shall be waived for alteration work, demolition work, construction of new buildings and associated work, including but not limited to associated electrical and plumbing work. The commissioner
    may request the applicant to submit additional information relating to the damage. Waiver of such fees pursuant to this section shall be applicable for jobs where the initial application for construction document approval or, if no construction documents
    are required, application for permit is submitted on or after October 30, 2012 and on or before October 31, 2014. ยง 28-112.10.2 Storm related damage to electrical and plumbing systems. In buildings other than eligible buildings, fees shall be waived
    only for applications, permits and inspections for work related to plumbing and electrical systems damaged by such storm. Applicants must submit certification by a licensed master electrician or a licensed master plumber or fire suppression piping
    contractor that the proposed work is related to such storm damage. The commissioner may request the applicant to submit additional information relating to the damage. Waiver of such fees pursuant to this section shall be applicable for jobs where
    the initial application for construction document approval or, if no construction documents are required, application for permit is submitted on or after October 30, 2012 and on or before December 31, 2013.</text>
</level>