<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-444</num>
  <heading>Persons operating and conducting games; equipment; expenses; compensation.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-444 Persons operating and conducting games; equipment; expenses; compensation. No person shall hold, operate or conduct any games of chance under any license issued under this subchapter except an active member of the authorized organization to
    which the license is issued, and no person shall assist in the holding, operating or conducting of any game of chance under such license except such an active member or a member of an organization or association which is an auxiliary to the licensee
    or a member of an organization or association of which such licensee is an auxiliary or member of an organization or association which is affiliated with the licensee by being, with it, auxiliary to another organization or association. No game of
    chance shall be conducted with any equipment except such as shall be owned or leased by the authorized organization so licensed or used without payment of any compensation therefor by the licensee. At least two officers, directors, trustees or clergy
    of the authorized organization shall upon request certify, under oath, that the persons assisting in holding, operating or conducting any game of chance are bona fide members of such authorized organization, auxiliary or affiliated organization. Upon
    request by the department, any such person involved in such games of chance shall certify that he or she has no criminal record. No items of expense shall be incurred or paid in connection with the conducting of any game of chance pursuant to any
    license issued under this subchapter except those that are reasonable and are necessarily expended for games of chance supplies and equipment, prizes stated rental if any, bookkeeping or accounting services according to a schedule of compensation
    prescribed by the board, janitorial services and utility supplies if any, license fees, and the cost of bus transportation, if authorized by such department.
  </text>
</level>