<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2140</num>
  <heading>Content and effect of vacate order.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2140 Content and effect of vacate order. a. An order issued pursuant to subdivision b of section 27-2139 of this article shall set forth the conditions which render the dwelling or part thereof unfit for human habitation. b. The order shall require
    all persons occupying the dwelling or part affected to vacate it within a period of time, not less than twenty-four hours nor more than ten days, to be stated in the order. c. 1. The order shall require that the owner correct the conditions which
    render the dwelling or part thereof unfit for human habitation within a period of time, not to exceed ten days, to be stated in the order. 2. If the department has not revoked or extended the order pursuant to subdivision b of section 27-2142 of this
    article, where such dwelling is a class B multiple dwelling or a class A multiple dwelling used for single room occupancy pursuant to section two hundred forty-eight of the multiple dwelling law, the owner of such dwelling shall be subject to a civil
    penalty of five thousand dollars for each dwelling unit which is included in said order. The fine shall be recoverable by the department by civil action in a court of appropriate jurisdiction. Such action must be commenced or notice of pendency filed
    within one year of the effective date of the vacate order. d. If a vacate order is not complied with within the time specified, the department may cause the dwelling or part thereof affected to be vacated. e. The filing of a vacate order in the office
    of the county clerk in the same manner as a notice of pendency shall be notice to any subsequent purchaser, mortgagee or lienor that any lien resulting from such vacate order shall be enforceable against and superior to the rights of such purchaser,
    mortgagee or lienor. f. When the department obtains a determination in an action under this article against an owner, judgment may be entered against the premises which shall constitute a lien when a transcript of such judgment is filed in the office
    of the county clerk in the manner prescribed for the filing of mechanic's liens and may be enforced against the premises as such, except that such lien shall have a duration of ten years.</text>
</level>