<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-297</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-297 Exemptions. The following constructions shall be exempt from the provisions of section 27-296 of this article: (a) One- or two-family dwellings. One- or two-family detached or semi-detached dwellings of two stories or less in height and two
    thousand five hundred square feet or less in area located within zoning residence districts may be constructed or reconstructed of construction groups II-D combustible materials, or if damaged for any cause, only the damaged portions shall be required
    to be reconstructed to conform to II-D construction. In addition, one-family dwellings located within zoning residence district anywhere in the city, may be of combustible group II-E construction in conformance with the area and height limits established
    by tables 4-1 and 4-2. (b) Fences. Fences not over six feet high may be erected of wood or other combustible material. (c) Storm enclosures, bay windows, etc. Storm enclosures, bay windows and similar appendages may be constructed of combustible materials
    in accordance with the provisions of section 27-336 of article four of subchapter five of this chapter. (d) Accessory buildings for open parking lots. Parking lot offices and similar accessory buildings not more than ten feet high and not more than
    one hundred fifty square feet in area may be constructed of combustible materials when on the same lot or accessory to a lot used for motor vehicle parking, and when located at least six feet from any lot line or building. (e) Temporary structures.
    Temporary platforms, reviewing stands, and similar miscellaneous structures may be constructed of combustible materials and used for a limited period of time, subject to the approval of the commissioner. (f) Greenhouse. Greenhouses may be constructed
    of combustible materials when accessory to a one- or two-family dwelling on the same lot and when located at least six feet from any lot line or building. (g) Roof structures. Cooling towers, antenna supports, and other roof structures may be constructed
    of combustible materials in accordance with the provisions of section 27-338 of subchapter five of this chapter. (h) Bins, tanks, and towers. Coal and material bins, water towers, tank structures, and trestles may be constructed of wood planking and
    timbers of dimensions not less than as required for class II-A construction when not over thirty-five feet high and having an exterior separation of a least thirty feet. (i) Signs. Ground signs, wall signs, roof signs, and temporary signs may be constructed
    of combustible materials within the limitations established in article eighteen of subchapter seven of this chapter.</text>
</level>