<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-741.1</num>
  <heading>Refund anticipation loans.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-741.1 Refund anticipation loans. 1. Any tax preparer who advertises the availability of a refund anticipation loan may not directly or indirectly represent such a loan as a refund. Any advertisement which mentions a refund anticipation loan must
    state conspicuously that it is a loan and that a fee or interest will be charged by the lending institution. The advertisement must also disclose the name of the lending institution. 2. Before any taxpayer enters into a refund anticipation loan, the
    tax preparer facilitating such loan shall provide the following disclosure to the taxpayer in writing, in English and Spanish, in at least 14-point type. In the event that the taxpayer does not understand English or Spanish, the tax preparer shall
    also provide a point-by-point oral explanation of the following required disclosure in a language understood by the tax payer: . YOU ARE NOT REQUIRED TO ENTER INTO THIS REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN AGREEMENT MERELY BECAUSE YOU HAVE RECEIVED THIS INFORMATION.
    . IF YOU DO SIGN A CONTRACT FOR A REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN, YOU WILL BE TAKING OUT A LOAN. YOU WILL BE RESPONSIBLE FOR REPAYMENT OF THE ENTIRE LOAN AMOUNT AND ALL RELATED COSTS AND FEES, REGARDLESS OF HOW MUCH MONEY YOU ACTUALLY RECEIVE IN YOUR TAX
    REFUND. . IF YOU DO NOT TAKE OUT THIS REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN, YOU ARE ELIGIBLE TO RECEIVE A GROSS TAX REFUND OF APPROXIMATELY $ (insert amount). . IF YOU DO TAKE OUT THIS REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN, YOU WILL BE RESPONSIBLE TO PAY $ (insert amount)
    IN FEES FOR THE LOAN. AFTER THESE FEES ARE PAID, YOU WILL RECEIVE APPROXIMATELY $ (insert amount) AS YOUR LOAN. . THE ESTIMATED ANNUAL PERCENTAGE RATE OF YOUR REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN IS (insert amount) %. THIS IS BASED ON THE ACTUAL AMOUNT OF TIME
    YOU WILL BE LENT MONEY THROUGH THIS REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN. . IF YOU DO TAKE OUT THIS REFUND ANTICIPATION LOAN, YOU CAN EXPECT TO RECEIVE YOUR LOAN WITHIN APPROXIMATELY TWO BUSINESS DAYS OF (insert date). . IF YOU DO NOT TAKE OUT THIS REFUND ANTICIPATION
    LOAN, YOU CAN STILL RECEIVE YOUR TAX REFUND QUICKLY. IF YOU FILE YOUR TAX RETURN ELECTRONICALLY AND RECEIVE YOUR TAX REFUND THROUGH THE MAIL, YOU CAN EXPECT TO RECEIVE YOUR REFUND WITHIN APPROXIMATELY TWO BUSINESS DAYS OF (insert date). IF YOU FILE
    YOUR TAX RETURN ELECTRONICALLY AND HAVE YOUR TAX REFUND DIRECTLY DEPOSITED INTO A BANK ACCOUNT, YOU CAN EXPECT TO RECEIVE YOUR REFUND WITHIN APPROXIMATELY TWO BUSINESS DAYS OF (insert date). It shall be the obligation of the tax preparer to complete
    the required disclosure accurately with all relevant information for each taxpayer, to provide the required point-by-point oral explanation when necessary, and to ensure that the completed disclosure form is signed by the taxpayer before he or she
    enters into a refund anticipation loan.</text>
</level>