<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2097</num>
  <heading>Registration; time to file.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2097 Registration; time to file. a. The owner of a dwelling required to register under this article shall register with the department in accordance with the provisions of this article. b. A registration statement shall be filed: (1) For every
    existing multiple dwelling. A registration statement filed by the present owner of a dwelling pursuant to the requirements of the prior law shall constitute compliance with this section. (2) Prior to the issuance of a certificate of occupancy, for
    any multiple dwelling hereafter erected, or any dwelling or building hereafter altered or converted to a multiple dwelling. (3) For all one- and two-family dwellings where neither the owner nor any family member occupies the dwelling and thereafter
    not later than ten days after the date neither the owner nor any family member occupies the dwelling. For purposes of this paragraph, "family member" shall mean an owner's spouse, domestic partner, parent, parent-in-law, child, sibling, sibling-in-law,
    grandparent or grandchild. (4) On or before July first, nineteen hundred eighty-four, for any garden-type maisonette dwelling project consisting of a series of dwelling units which together and in their aggregate are arranged or designed to provide
    three or more apartments, and are provided as a group collectively with all essential services such as, but not limited to, house sewers and heat, and which are operated as a unit under single ownership, notwithstanding that certificates of occupancy
    were issued for portions thereof as private dwellings. (5) Within such time as provided in section 27-2099 of this article, in the case of a change of ownership where registration is required under this article. c. An owner who is required to register
    shall file a new registration statement annually. d. An owner who is required to register shall file a new registration statement on the registration date assigned to that dwelling by the department whether or not that owner filed a registration statement
    for that dwelling previously. e. The registration date of a dwelling shall be a calendar date assigned by the department to that dwelling for the purpose of registration on such date at intervals of one year.</text>
</level>