<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2059</num>
  <heading>Lighting and ventilation of living rooms in converted dwellings.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2059 Lighting and ventilation of living rooms in converted dwellings. a. Required windows. Except as provided in subdivision c, every living room in a converted dwelling shall have at least one window opening on: (1) A street, (2) A yard or outer
    court which complies with the provisions of section one hundred seventy-two of the multiple dwelling law, or (3) An inner court or shaft with minimum dimensions of three feet, nine inches in width and eight feet in length. For a room located on the
    top story, a skylight of the dimensions required in subdivision b may be substituted for a window. b. Size of windows. (1) The total area of all windows in the room shall be at least one-tenth the floor area of such room. (2) Every required window
    or skylight shall be at least twelve square feet, except that if the total area of windows in the room is one-eighth of the floor area this requirement shall not apply. (3) At least one-half of every required window shall open. One-half of the skylight
    shall have ventilating openings, unless (a) the skylight is equipped with a minimum of one hundred and forty-four square inches of ventilation, and (b) there is at least one window in the room, and (c) the combined glazed area of the skylight and
    window is at least one-eighth of the floor area. (4) The top of every required window shall be at least seven feet above the floor, except that on the top story it shall be a minimum of six feet above the floor. c. Noncomplying rooms. (1) A room which
    is noncomplying with the minimum room size requirements of subdivision b of section 27-2074 of article four of this subchapter or with the requirements of subdivisions a and b of this section may not be occupied unless it has a single or unbroken
    opening of not less than thirty-two and one-half square feet into an immediately adjoining room. Such adjoining room shall have a window on a street or a yard which complies with the provisions of section one hundred seventy-two of the multiple dwelling
    law, except that if the dwelling is two stories or less in height, the window of such adjoining room may open on an outer court or a court not less than four feet in width extending from street to yard. (2) No room may be subdivided in any manner
    unless each subdivided portion meets the requirements of paragraph one of this subdivision, or of subdivision a of this section.</text>
</level>