<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-383</num>
  <heading>Suspensions and revocations.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-383 Suspensions and revocations. a. After notice and opportunity to be heard, the commissioner may suspend or revoke any sight-seeing bus license where the holder has failed to comply with any provisions of this subchapter or of the rules promulgated
    thereunder, or with any other laws or rules governing sight-seeing buses, or which sight-seeing bus is otherwise found to be unfit for operation. Such suspension shall remain in effect until compliance and fitness have been established by the licensee
    and accepted by the department. Grounds for suspension or revocation shall include, but not be limited to, installation of an engine which does not meet the requirements of subdivision b of section 20-376 of this subchapter, being found to have violated
    the requirements for diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing buses contained in section 24-163.6 of the administrative code, failure to submit a bus for inspection, installation of an engine not covered by a certificate of conformity in a vehicle which was
    originally manufactured with such an engine and installation of an engine of any model year preceding the year of manufacture in a vehicle which was originally manufactured with an engine covered by a certificate of conformity. b. Any driver of a
    horse drawn cab found to have committed within any twelve-month period, in the aggregate, at least three violations of this subchapter shall have his or her license suspended by the commissioner for a period of not less than three months. For purposes
    of this subdivision, all violations written on any one day shall constitute a single violation. c. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision b of this section, any driver of a horse drawn cab found to have committed within any twenty-four month
    period, in the aggregate, at least five violations of this subchapter shall have his or her license suspended by the commissioner for six months. For purposes of this subdivision, all violations written on any one day shall constitute a single violation.
    d. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions b and c of this section, any driver of a horse drawn cab found guilty of one violation of subdivision d of section 20-381.1 of the code or sections three hundred fifty-one, three hundred fifty-three,
    three hundred fifty-five through three hundred sixty-two or three hundred sixty-nine of the New York state agriculture and markets law or who is found guilty of a violation of this subchapter while his or her license is suspended, shall have his or
    her license revoked. A driver whose license has been revoked in accordance with this provision may not apply for a new license for five years from the date of revocation.</text>
</level>