<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-211</num>
  <heading>Registration required for seafood delivery business.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-211 Registration required for seafood delivery business. a. It shall be unlawful to conduct a seafood delivery business in the fulton fish market distribution area without having first registered such business with the commissioner and obtained
    a registration number from the commissioner. A registration application shall be submitted by a seafood delivery business upon a form prescribed by the commissioner containing such information as the commissioner shall require by rule and shall be
    signed by all the principals of such seafood delivery business. The market manager may require that seafood deliverers affix a sticker or decal containing such registration number to their delivery vehicles. A seafood delivery registration number
    or sticker or decal shall not be transferable. b. (i) Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter, the commissioner may, when there is reasonable cause to believe that any or all of the principals, employees or agents of a seafood deliverer lack
    good character, honesty and integrity, require that any or all of such principals be fingerprinted and provide to the commissioner the information set forth in subdivision a of section 22-216 of this chapter, and may, after notice and the opportunity
    to be heard, refuse to register such seafood deliverer for the reasons set forth in subdivision b of such section. (ii) If at any time subsequent to the registration of a seafood deliverer, the commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that any
    or all of the principals, employees or agents of a seafood deliverer lacks good character, honesty and integrity, the commissioner may require that any or all of such principals be fingerprinted and provide the background information required by subdivision
    a of section 22-216 of this chapter and may, after notice and the opportunity for a hearing, revoke the registration of such seafood deliverer for the reasons set forth in subdivision b of such section.</text>
</level>