<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2034</num>
  <heading>Space and water heaters.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2034 Space and water heaters. a. Any gas-fueled space or water heater used in any dwelling unit, in addition to the provisions of section 27-2032 of article eight of this subchapter, shall comply with the provisions of this section and with the
    regulations of the department. b. No person shall install or maintain in any dwelling unit a gas fuel-fired space or water heater unless the heater obtains combustion air directly from the outside of the building. In the alternative, a gas fuel-fired
    water heater that does not obtain its combustion air directly from the outside of the building may be installed, provided that such installation is in compliance with the conditions of subdivision i of section P107.26 of reference standard RS-16 of
    the building code. c. No person shall install or maintain a gas-fueled water heater in a room occupied for sleeping purposes, or cause or permit to be occupied for sleeping purposes any room in which a gas-fueled heater is installed. d. No person
    shall install or maintain in any dwelling unit a gas-fueled water heater so designed and arranged that it heats water in pipe coils placed at a distance from the hot water storage tank. e. Every gas fuel-fired space or water heater shall be (i) currently
    listed by an independent laboratory acceptable to the commissioner of buildings, (ii) approved by the department of buildings and (iii) approved by the department of health and mental hygiene. All accessories or control devices for use with such heaters
    shall have proof of such listing. f. Each heater shall be equipped with an effective device which will automatically shut off the gas supply to the heater if its pilot light or other constantly burning flame is extinguished, or in the event of an
    interruption of the gas supply to the heater, and will not permit the heater to be relighted unless such shut-off device is first reset manually. g. Each heater shall be rigidly connected to the gas piping supplying gas in the premises. h. Each heater
    shall be connected to a flue or outlet pipe conforming to the provisions of the building code. No heater shall be vented to an inner court. A flue or outlet pipe may be extended to an inner court if the flue or pipe is connected with an outside chimney
    which conforms with the provisions of the building code.</text>
</level>