<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-744</num>
  <heading>Procurement or sale of tickets, reservations or passenger accommodations.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-744 Procurement or sale of tickets, reservations or passenger accommodations. a. It is hereby determined and declared that the price or charge for the procurement on behalf of another, by purchase or otherwise or upon the sale or resale, within
    the corporate limits of the city of New York, of tickets, reservations or passenger accommodations issued by any railroad, parlor or sleeping car owner or operator, steamship company, air line or bus line is a matter affected with a public interest
    and subject to the supervision of the authorities of said city for the purpose of safeguarding the public against fraud, extortion, exorbitant rates and similar abuses. b. It shall be unlawful for any person to require, charge, make or receive, within
    the corporate limits of the city of New York, for the procurement on behalf of another, by purchase or otherwise, of any ticket, reservation or passenger accommodation, issued by any railroad, parlor or sleeping car owner or operator, steamship company,
    air line or bus line, a fee or service charge or any payment or consideration for rendering such service in excess of one dollar for the first transportation ticket, reservation or passenger accommodation or first parlor car or sleeping car reservation
    or passenger accommodation, or in excess of one dollar for any additional transportation ticket or parlor car or sleeping car reservation or passenger accommodation over the established tariff charge or charges therefor. c. It shall be unlawful for
    any person to procure on behalf of another person, within the corporate limits of the city of New York by purchase or otherwise, any ticket, reservation or passenger accommodation, issued by any railroad, parlor or sleeping car owner or operator,
    steamship company, air line or bus line, with the intent, with respect to such other person, to require, charge, make or receive a service charge or any payment or consideration for rendering service in excess of the amount or amounts hereinabove
    specified in subdivision b over the established tariff charge or charges therefor. Proof of the making of a service charge or of the receipt of any payment or consideration, in connection with the procurement of such ticket, reservation or passenger
    accommodation, for such other person, in excess of the amount or amounts hereinabove specified in subdivision b, over such established tariff charge or charges, shall be presumptive evidence of the intent mentioned in the next preceding subdivision.
    d. It shall be unlawful for any person to sell, resell or cause to be resold, within the corporate limits of the city of New York, any ticket, reservation or passenger accommodation, issued by any railroad, parlor or sleeping car owner or operator,
    steamship company, air line or bus line, at a price in excess of the amount or amounts hereinabove specified in subdivision b over the established tariff charge or charges therefor. e. It shall be unlawful for any person to procure, within the corporate
    limits of the city of New York, by purchase or otherwise, any ticket, reservation or passenger accommodation, issued by any railroad, parlor or sleeping car owner or operator, steamship company, air line or bus line, with the intent to sell or resell
    the same, or cause the same to be sold or resold, at a price in excess of the amount or amounts hereinabove specified in subdivision b over the established tariff charge or charges therefor. Proof of the sale or resale of such ticket, reservation
    or passenger accommodation or combination thereof at a price in excess of the amount or amounts hereinabove specified in subdivision b over such established tariff charge or charges shall be presumptive evidence of the intent mentioned in the next
    preceding subdivision. f. The term "person" as used in this section includes any officer or employee of a corporation or a member or employee of a partnership who, as such officer, member or employee, is responsible for the act in respect of which
    the violation occurs. The term "established tariff charge" shall be the charge set forth in the tariff as published and filed by the railroad, parlor or sleeping car owner or operator, steamship company, air line or bus line involved. g. The person
    responsible for the management of each travel agency and hotel operating within the corporate limits of the city of New York shall cause a copy of this subchapter to be posted in a conspicuous place upon the premises of the agency or hotel for the
    information of patrons, guests and members of the public at large. h. Any person violating any of the provisions of this subchapter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine not exceeding one hundred dollars
    or by imprisonment not exceeding ten days or both, for each separate offense. i. This subchapter shall not apply to tickets, reservations or passenger accommodations: (a) to or from places outside of the continental United States and Canada, excluding
    Alaska; nor (b) to existing written contracts between any travel agency with corporations, firms or government agencies covering tourist or travel services.</text>
</level>