<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-163.6</num>
  <heading>Use of best available retrofit technology by sight-seeing buses.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-163.6 Use of best available retrofit technology by sight-seeing buses. a. Definitions. When used in this section: (1) "Best available retrofit technology" means technology, verified by the United States environmental protection agency or the California
    air resources board, for reducing the emission of pollutants that achieves reductions in particulate matter emissions at the highest classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in subdivision d of this section, that is
    applicable to the particular engine and application. Such technology shall also, at a reasonable cost, achieve the greatest reduction in emissions of nitrogen oxides at such particulate matter reduction level and shall in no event result in a net
    increase in the emissions of either particulate matter or nitrogen oxides. (2) "Reasonable cost" means that such technology does not cost greater than thirty percent more than other technology applicable to the particular engine and application that
    falls within the same classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in subdivision d of this section, when considering the cost of the strategies, themselves, and the cost of installation. (3) "Sight-seeing bus" means a
    motor vehicle designed to comfortably seat and carry eight or more passengers operating for hire from a fixed point in the city of New York to a place or places of interest or amusements, and shall also include a vehicle, designed as aforesaid which
    by oral or written contract is let and hired or otherwise engaged for its exclusive use for a specific or special trip or excursion from a starting point within the city of New York. b. (1) Beginning January 1, 2007, any diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing
    bus that is licensed pursuant to subchapter 21 of chapter 2 of title 20 of the administrative code and that is equipped with an engine that is over three years old shall utilize the best available retrofit technology. (2) Notwithstanding any provision
    of subdivision c of this section, any diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus that is licensed pursuant to subchapter 21 of chapter 2 of title 20 of the administrative code shall utilize the best available retrofit technology that meets the level 4 emission
    control strategy as defined in subdivision d of this section, or be equipped with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter as set forth in section 86.007-11 of title 40
    of the code of federal regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for such pollutant that is at least as stringent, by January 1, 2017. c. (1) The commissioner shall make determinations, and shall publish
    a list containing such determinations, as to the best available retrofit technology to be used for each type of diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus to which this section applies. Each such determination shall be reviewed and revised, as needed, on
    a regular basis, but in no event less often than once every six months. (2) No owner or operator of a diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus licensed pursuant to the provisions of subchapter 21 of chapter 2 of title 20 of the administrative code shall
    be required to replace best available retrofit technology or other authorized technology utilized for a diesel fuel-powered bus in accordance with the provisions of this section within three years of having first utilized such technology for such
    bus, except that technology that falls within Level 4, as set forth in subdivision d of this section, shall not be required to be replaced until it has reached the end of its useful life. d. The classification levels for diesel emission control strategies
    are as follows, with Level 4 being the highest classification level: i. Level 4 - strategy reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by 85 percent or greater or reduces engine emissions to less than or equal to 0.01 grams diesel particulate matter
    per brake horsepower-hour; ii. Level 3 - strategy reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 50 and 84 percent; iii. Level 2 - strategy reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 25 and 49 percent; iv. Level 1 - strategy reduces
    diesel particulate matter emissions by between 20 and 24 percent. e. The commissioner may issue a waiver for the use of the best available retrofit technology by a diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus where the department of consumer affairs makes
    a written finding, which is approved, in writing, by the commissioner, that such technology is unavailable for purchase for such bus, in which case the owner or operator of such bus shall be required to use the technology for reducing the emission
    of pollutants that would be the next best best available retrofit technology and that is available for purchase for such bus. Any waiver issued pursuant to this subdivision shall expire after three years. The commissioner shall not renew any waiver
    issued pursuant to this subdivision after January 1, 2014. f. The requirements of subdivision b of this section shall not apply to a diesel-fuel powered sight-seeing bus that is equipped with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States
    environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter as set forth in section 86.007-11 of title 40 of the code of federal regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for such pollutant that is
    at least as stringent. g. Not later than January 1, 2008, and not later than January 1 of each year thereafter, the commissioner shall submit a report to the comptroller and the speaker of the council regarding, among other things, the use of the
    best available retrofit technology by diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing buses during the immediately preceding fiscal year. This report shall include, but not be limited to: (i) the total number of diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing buses licensed pursuant
    to subchapter 21 of chapter 2 of title 20 of the administrative code; (ii) the number of such buses that utilized the best available retrofit technology, including a breakdown by vehicle model, engine year and the type of technology used for each
    vehicle; (iii) the number of such buses that utilized other authorized technology in accordance with this section, including a breakdown by vehicle model, engine year and the type of technology used for each vehicle; (iv) the number of such buses
    that are equipped with an engine certified to the applicable United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter in accordance with subdivision f of this section; (v) the locations where such buses that utilized the best
    available retrofit technology, utilized such other authorized technology in accordance with this section or were equipped with an engine certified to the applicable United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter were
    used; (vi) the age of the engine with which each bus that did not utilize the best available retrofit technology is equipped; and (vii) all waivers issued pursuant to subdivision e of this section, which shall include, but not be limited to, all findings
    and specific information submitted by the department of consumer affairs or the owner or operator of a diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus upon which such waivers are based and the type of other authorized technology utilized in accordance with this
    section in relation to each waiver, instead of the best available retrofit technology. h. Any owner or operator of a diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus who violates any provision of this section, except as provided in subdivision i of this section,
    shall be liable for a civil penalty of not less than one thousand dollars and not more than ten thousand dollars, in addition to twice the amount of money saved by such owner or operator for failure to comply with this section. i. Where an owner or
    operator of a diesel fuel-powered sight-seeing bus has been found to have made a false claim with respect to the provisions of this section, such owner or operator shall be liable for an additional civil penalty of twenty thousand dollars.</text>
</level>