<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-111</num>
  <heading>Soliciting of contributions in public.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-111 Soliciting of contributions in public. a. It shall be unlawful for any person, organization, society, association or corporation or their agents or representatives to solicit money, donations of money or property, or financial assistance of
    any kind upon the streets, in office or business buildings, by house to house canvass, or in public places in the city, except upon a license issued by the commissioner and an identification card issued by the chairperson or district chairperson of
    any charitable drive and any such regulations as hereinafter provided. b. Application to solicit funds for any cause whatever as provided for in this section shall be addressed to the commissioner and such application shall contain the following information:
    1. Name and purpose of the cause for which permission is sought. 2. Names and addresses of the officers and directors of the organization. 3. Time for which permission is sought and localities and places of solicitation. 4. Whether or not any commissions,
    fees, wages or emoluments are to be expended in connection with such solicitation. 5. Such other information as the commissioner shall require. c. It shall be the duty of the commissioner, before granting permission to solicit funds or donations as
    provided for in this section, to compel the applicant to file with him or her a signed statement of all moneys collected in the calendar year or the fiscal year of such organization, society, association or corporation previous to the application,
    the expenditures connected therewith, together with the names and addresses of all persons receiving wages, commissions or emoluments and the amounts so expended. d. The commissioner may establish such regulations as he or she may deem necessary in
    effectuating the purposes and objects of this section. e. Licensees operating under this section shall be compelled to label all collection boxes or containers used in the solicitation of funds either by appeal in person or the placing of receptacles
    for the receipt of such public contributions in stores, factories, shops, offices, theatres, hotels, restaurants, railway stations, ferry houses, or other public places, with the name of the organization for which the permit is issued, and in such
    conspicuous manner as the commissioner may direct. In addition, where the solicitation of funds is by appeal in person and where the solicitor receives no compensation for such solicitation, the box or container shall bear on it the word "volunteer"
    in a conspicuous place. Any solicitor receiving compensation for such solicitation who uses a box or container bearing the word "volunteer" shall be subject to a fine not to exceed one hundred dollars or to imprisonment for a period not to exceed
    thirty days or both. f. Any person or persons who shall violate any of the provisions of this section, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment not exceeding ninety days, or by
    both. g. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any corporation organized under the religious corporations law; nor to solicitation at the regular exercises or services of any lodge, benevolent order or fraternity, or any branch thereof,
    whenever such solicitation is made at the regularly appointed meetings and regular places of worship or exercises of such lodge, order or fraternity.</text>
</level>