<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-504.4</num>
  <heading>Exceptions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 28-504.4 Exceptions. Bicycle access need not be provided pursuant to this article if an owner, lessee, manager or other person who controls a building applies to the commissioner of transportation for an exception, on a form provided by the department
    of transportation and sent to the department of transportation by certified mail, return receipt requested, within fifteen days of receipt of a request for a bicycle access plan, and certifies that either: 1. The building's freight elevator is not
    available for the use described in this article because unique circumstances exist involving substantial safety risks directly related to the use of such elevator. Such application shall include the reasons for such assertion and supporting documentation.
    or 2. There is sufficient secure alternate covered off-street or sufficient secure alternate indoor no-cost bicycle parking available on the premises or within three blocks or seven hundred fifty feet, whichever is less, of such building to accommodate
    all tenants or subtenants of such building requesting bicycle access. Such application shall include supporting documentation for such assertion, including proof that such alternate off-street or indoor parking is available to or under the control
    of such owner, lessee, manager or other person who controls the building. If an exception is sought for the reasons set forth in subdivision one of this section, the department shall conduct an inspection of the building and freight elevator and shall
    thereafter issue a final determination as to whether to grant an exception. If an exception is sought for the reasons set forth in subdivision two of this section, the department, in consultation with the department of transportation, shall thereafter
    conduct an inspection of the secure alternate covered off-street or secure indoor no-cost bicycle parking and the department of transportation shall thereafter issue a final determination as to whether to grant an exception. In either event, a letter
    of exception or denial shall be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the owner, lessee, manager, or other person in control of the building. If the exception is denied, a bicycle access plan shall be posted within twenty days of receipt
    of such determination. Failure to timely post a bicycle access plan shall be cause for the issuance of a violation.</text>
</level>