<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-777.1</num>
  <heading>Smoke control requirements.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-777.1 Smoke control requirements. (a) In all buildings classified in occupancy group C, D, E, F, G, H, J-1 or J-2: (1) Ventilation systems supplying different occupancy groups shall not be interconnected, provided however that a ventilation system
    may serve two occupancy groups located on the same floor when the accessory use occupies less than twenty per cent of the floor area occupied by the principal use. (2) Ventilation systems supplying corridors shall not be interconnected with systems
    serving other spaces, except that this requirement shall not apply to floors used exclusively as office space in buildings classified in occupancy group E which are fully sprinklered. (3) A ventilation system supplying any part of a means of egress
    shall not be interconnected with any other ventilation system. (4) A ventilation system supplying public areas and assembly spaces shall have smoke detecting devices that will shut down the system upon detecting smoke. (5) In buildings classified
    in occupancy group J-2, ventilation systems supplying individual apartments shall not be directly connected with any other ventilation system. (6) Except in buildings classified in occupancy group J-2, and as otherwise provided in section 27-343 of
    article five of subchapter five of this chapter, either a combined heat and smoke damper or independent heat and smoke dampers shall be installed at any penetration of construction required to have a fire-resistance rating. (b) In all buildings classified
    in occupancy group C, D, E, F, G, H or J-1, there shall be provided a system of mechanical means of sufficient capacity to exhaust six air changes per hour or 1 cfm/sq. ft., whichever is greater, from the largest floor in the building, using either
    dedicated fan equipment or the building ventilation system arranged to shut down automatically with manual override capability to exhaust one floor at a time through a roof or an approved location on an exterior wall other than a lot line wall.</text>
</level>