<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-355</num>
  <heading>Police protection to inhabitants of construction areas; appointment and dismissal of police; powers and duties.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-355 Police protection to inhabitants of construction areas; appointment and dismissal of police; powers and duties. a. It shall be the duty of the commissioner of environmental protection to provide proper police protection to the inhabitants of
    the localities in which any work may be constructed under the authority of this subchapter during the period of construction, against the acts or omissions of persons employed on such works or found in their neighborhood. To that end the commissioner
    is authorized and required to appoint a sufficient number of persons to adequately police such localities for such periods. The commissioner shall also have power to remove such persons and to fix or change their compensation in his or her discretion,
    which compensation shall be paid by the city upon a certificate of the commissioner, as part of the expense authorized to be incurred by this subchapter. b. The commissioner of environmental protection shall give to each person so appointed a certificate
    of appointment and certified copies thereof, one of which shall be filed in the office of the sheriff of each county in which any work shall be in process of construction under this subchapter and in which such person shall be authorized to perform
    that person's duties. Each person so appointed shall be and have all the powers of a peace officer in the county where any work is being constructed under the authority of this subchapter. Such person shall at all times when on duty wear upon his
    or her clothing or have in his or her possession a shield or other suitable badge of authority which such person shall at once exhibit to any person asking therefor. c. It shall be the special duty of the persons so appointed to prevent breaches of
    the peace and unlawful depredations and to arrest and bring before the proper magistrates persons employed on such works or found in the vicinity thereof, who are guilty of offenses against the law punishable by death, imprisonment or fines, or persons
    whom they may have reasonable cause to believe to be guilty of such offenses. d. The sheriff of a county wherein a certificate of appointment of any such person as a peace officer is filed may cancel such certificate for cause, and shall immediately
    give notice in writing of such cancellation to the commissioner of environmental protection, specifying the cause of such revocation. Such notice may be given by mail. On such cancellation the authority of such person as a peace officer shall immediately
    cease. e. Any expense necessarily incurred by a county, town or city in a criminal action or proceeding against any person employed on any works constructed or in process of construction under this subchapter, or in the suppression of riots among
    persons employed on such work, or in the prevention of the commission of crime by such person, after being duly audited, as required by law, shall constitute a claim in favor of such county, town or city against the city of New York and an action
    may be maintained on such audit as for money paid to the use of the city.</text>
</level>