<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3010</num>
  <heading>Qualification and Examination of applicants for master electrician's and special electrician's licenses.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-3010 Qualification and Examination of applicants for master electrician's and special electrician's licenses. a. Qualification of Applicant. An applicant for a license as a master electrician or special electrician must be over the age of twenty-one
    years, of good moral character and, at the time of applying for examination, shall have had, during the ten (10) years immediately preceding his or her application, at least seven and one-half (7 1/2) years or the equivalent as indicated below and
    during such time a minimum of ten thousand five hundred (10,500) hours or the equivalent as indicated below of satisfactory experience in the installation, alteration and repair of wiring and appliances for electric light, heat and power in or on
    buildings or comparable facilities. Except as otherwise provided below, such satisfactory experience must have been obtained while under the direct supervision of a licensed master electrician or special electrician or, with respect to experience
    outside the city, under the direct supervision of an individual with comparable qualifications as determined by the commissioner, and while in the employ of (i) a master electrician business as defined herein, or (ii) an individual, a partnership
    or a corporation owning, leasing or managing a building, buildings or parts thereof and employing a special electrician to perform electrical work in or on specific buildings, lots or parts thereof owned, leased or managed by such individual, corporation
    or partnership, or (iii) an individual, a partnership or a corporation deemed acceptable by the commissioner. No more than twenty-five percent (25%) of such satisfactory experience shall have been gained while working outside the United States unless
    the commissioner determines that the licensing system and electrical code of the foreign jurisdiction is essentially similar to licensing systems and electrical codes in the United States. The following shall be deemed to fulfill the satisfactory
    experience requirement: 1. A journeyman electrician who has worked at least seven and one-half (7 1/2) years and during such time a minimum of ten thousand five hundred (10,500) hours of such experience must have been obtained by working with his
    or her tools on the installation, alteration and repair of wiring and appliances for light, heat and power in or on buildings or comparable facilities, or 2. A graduate of a college or university who holds a degree in electrical engineering, either
    a master of science (M.S.) or bachelor of science (B.S.) and has in addition worked at least (i) with respect to an applicant with an M.S. degree, two and one-half (2 1/2) years and during such time a minimum of thirty-five hundred (3500) hours of
    such experience or, (ii) with respect to an applicant with a B.S. degree, three and one-half (3 1/2) years and during such time a minimum of forty-nine hundred (4900) hours of such experience must have been obtained by working with his or her tools
    on the installation, alteration and repair of wiring and appliances for electric light, heat and power in or on buildings or comparable facilities, or 3. A graduate of a vocational, industrial, trade school, or apprenticeship program registered with
    the New York state department of labor, specializing in electrical wiring, installation and design or applied electricity, who has worked at least five and one-half (5 1/2) years and during such time a minimum of seventy-seven hundred (7700) hours
    of such experience must have been obtained by working with his or her tools on the installation, alteration and repair of wiring and appliances for electric light, heat and power in or on buildings or comparable facilities, or 4. Any person who attended
    courses in a college or university leading to a degree in electrical engineering, mechanical engineering, bachelor of science in electrical engineering or mechanical engineering, who passed all subjects in the required courses shall be credited with
    satisfactory experience equal to fifty per cent (50%) of the number of curricula years he or she has satisfactorily completed which, in no event, however, shall exceed two and one-half (2 1/2) years credit of satisfactory experience, the balance of
    the required seven and one-half (7 1/2) years, i.e., five (5) years and during such time a minimum of seven thousand (7000) hours of such experience must have been obtained by working with his or her tools on the installation, alteration and repair
    of wiring and apparatus for light, heat and power in or on buildings or comparable facilities, or 5. Any person who attended courses in a vocational, industrial or trade school, registered with the New York state department of labor, specializing
    in electrical wiring, installation and design or applied electricity who has passed all subjects in the required courses shall be credited with fifty per cent (50%) of the number of curricula years that he or she has satisfactorily completed which,
    however, in no event, shall exceed two (2) years credit of such experience, the balance of the required seven and one-half (7 1/2) years, i.e., five and one-half (5 1/2) years of such experience and during such time a minimum of seventy-seven hundred
    (7700) hours must have been obtained by working with his or her tools on the installation and repair of wiring for electric light, heat and power in or on buildings or comparable facilities, or 6. An employee of a government agency, private inspection
    agency or other entity, acceptable to the commissioner, whose duties primarily involve the inspection of electrical work for compliance with the electrical code and the electrical code technical standards and/or other laws relating to the installation,
    alteration or repair of electrical wiring or appliances shall be credited with fifty percent (50%) of the number of years that he or she has been satisfactorily employed in such duties within the ten (10) year period prior to application, which, however,
    in no event, shall exceed two and one-half (2 1/2) years credit of satisfactory experience. The balance of the required seven and one-half (7 1/2) years, i.e., five (5) years and during such time a minimum of seven thousand (7000) hours of such experience
    must have been obtained by working with his or her tools on the installation, alteration and repair of wiring and appliances for electric light, heat and power in or on buildings or comparable facilities except that the requirement of subdivision
    a of this section that an applicant's working experience must have been within the ten (10) year period prior to application shall not apply to such balance of five (5) years working experience required pursuant to this paragraph. b. Examination of
    Applicant. 1. Every application for a master electrician's or special electrician's license shall be made in writing in such form and shall furnish such information as the commissioner may, from time to time, prescribe, and set forth in the rules
    of the department. It is a condition of the license that information in the application be kept correct and current. Any change in required information that occurs prior to the issuance of the license shall be reported to the department within fourteen
    days of the change. 2. Every applicant shall be required to take an examination in accordance with the rules of the department. However, where the application is on behalf of a city agency, the commissioner may waive the examination requirement if
    the applicant has sufficient experience qualifications of a type and duration comparable to those set forth in subdivision a of this section as determined by the commissioner. 3. Every applicant shall submit to such investigation by the license board
    as may be proper to determine the applicant's character and fitness. Every applicant shall commence the application process with the department within one year of passing the examination for licensure and shall furnish to the department a completed
    application within one year of submission of the first filing. Failure to provide all requested documents in a timely manner will constitute an incomplete application and may result in denial of the license. 4. Every applicant shall be required to
    submit such documentation as is required to establish a place of business within ninety days after the license board's recommendation that the applicant has the required character and fitness for licensure. Where all requested documents are not provided
    in a timely manner an application will be deemed incomplete and may result in the denial of the license.</text>
</level>