<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-273</num>
  <heading>Record of purchase and sales.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-273 Record of purchase and sales. a. Every dealer in second-hand articles shall keep a book in which shall be legibly written in English, at the time of every purchase and at the time of every sale, a description of every article so purchased or
    sold, the number or numbers and any monograms, inscription or other marks of identification that may appear on such article, a description of the articles or pieces comprising old gold, silver, platinum, or other metals, and any monogram, inscription
    or marks of identification thereon, the name, residence and general description of the person from whom such purchase was made or to whom sold and the day and hour of the purchase or sale. b. In the case of a purchase or sale of a pawnbroker ticket
    or other evidence of a pledged article or a redemption or sale of a pledged article, there shall be written in such book at the time of such purchase, sale or redemption: 1. The name and address of the person who issued such ticket or other evidence;
    2. The pledge number of such pawn ticket or other evidence; 3. The name and address of the pledgor as it appears upon such pawn ticket or other evidence; 4. The amount loaned or advanced as it appears on such pawn ticket or other evidence; 5. The
    day and hour of such purchase, sale or redemption, as the case may be; 6. The name, residence and general description of the person from whom or to whom the redeemed article is purchased or sold, as the case may be; 7. The sum paid or received for
    such pawn ticket or other evidence, or the sum paid or received for the redeemed article or pledge; 8. Such description of a pledged article as appears on such pawn ticket or other evidence and an accurate description of every redeemed pledged article.
    c. In the case of a sale or other disposal of a motor vehicle, motor cycle or motor thereof, the licensee shall, in addition to any other entry required, enter in a permanent record the manner in which said motor vehicle, motor cycle or motor was
    removed from the premises, giving the name and address of the person who removes it and the motor vehicle registration number of any vehicle used to tow, remove or transport such motor vehicle, motor cycle or motor. d. Such book, at all reasonable
    times, shall be open to the inspection of any police officer, to the commissioner or departmental inspector, or any judge of the criminal court, or any person duly authorized in writing for such purposes by the commissioner or by any judge of the
    criminal court, who shall exhibit such written authority to the dealer.</text>
</level>