<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-411</num>
  <heading>Judicial review.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-411 Judicial review. a. (1) Any person who is aggrieved by the final determination of the city rent agency in an administrative proceeding protesting a regulation or order of such agency may, in accordance with article seventy-eight of the civil
    practice law and rules, within sixty days after such determination, commence a proceeding in the supreme court. The petition shall specify his or her objections and pray that the regulation or order protested be enjoined or set aside in whole or in
    part. Such proceeding may at the option of the petitioner be instituted in the county where the city rent agency has its principal office or where the property is located. The city rent agency shall file with such court the original or a transcript
    of such portions of the proceedings in connection with its final determination as are material under the petition. Such return shall include a statement setting forth, so far as practicable, the economic data and other facts of which the city rent
    agency has taken official notice. Upon the filing of such petition the court shall have jurisdiction to set aside the regulation or order protested, in whole or in part, to dismiss the petition, or to remit the proceeding to the city rent agency,
    provided, however, that the regulation or order may be modified or rescinded by the city rent agency at any time notwithstanding the pendency of such proceeding for review. (2) No objection to such regulation or order, and no evidence in support of
    any objection thereto, shall be considered by the court, unless such objection shall have been presented to the city rent agency by the petitioner in the proceedings resulting in the determination or unless such evidence shall be contained in the
    return. If application is made to the court by either party for leave to introduce additional evidence which was either offered and not admitted or which could not reasonably have been offered or included in such proceedings before the city rent agency,
    and the court determines that such evidence should be admitted, the court shall order the evidence to be presented to the city rent agency. The city rent agency shall promptly receive the same, and such other evidence as the city rent agency deems
    necessary or proper, and thereupon the city rent agency shall file with the court the original or a transcript thereof and any modification made in such regulation or order as a result thereof; except that on request by the city rent agency, any such
    evidence shall be presented directly to the court. Upon final determination of the proceeding before the court, the original record, if filed by the city rent agency with the court, shall be returned to the city rent agency. b. No regulation or order
    of the city rent agency shall be enjoined or set aside, in whole or in part, unless the petitioner shall establish to the satisfaction of the court that the regulation or order is not in accordance with law, or is arbitrary or capricious. The effectiveness
    of an order of the court enjoining or setting aside, in whole or in part, any such regulation or order shall be postponed until the expiration of thirty days from the entry thereof. The jurisdiction of the supreme court shall be exclusive and its
    order dismissing the petition or enjoining or setting aside such regulation or order, in whole or in part, shall be final, subject to review by the appellate division of the supreme court and the court of appeals in the same manner and form and with
    the same effect as provided in the civil practice law and rules for appeals from a final order in a special proceeding. Notwithstanding any provision of paragraph one of subdivision (b) of section five thousand seven hundred one of the civil practice
    law and rules to the contrary, any order of the court remitting the proceeding to the city rent agency may, at the election of the city rent agency, be subject to review by the appellate division of the supreme court and the court of appeals in the
    same manner and form and with the same effect as provided in the civil practice law and rules for appeals from a final order in a special proceeding. All such proceedings shall be heard and determined by the court and by any appellate court as expeditiously
    as possible and with lawful precedence over other matters. All such proceedings for review shall be heard on the petition, manuscript and other papers, and on appeal shall be heard on the record, without requirement of printing. c. Within thirty days
    after arraignment, or such additional time as the court may allow for good cause shown, in any criminal proceeding, and within five days after judgment in any civil or criminal proceeding, brought pursuant to subdivision ten of section one of the
    state enabling act or section 26-413 of this chapter involving alleged violation of any provision of any regulation or order of the city rent agency, the defendant may apply to the court in which the proceeding is pending for leave to file in the
    supreme court a petition setting forth objections to the validity of any provision which the defendant is alleged to have violated or conspired to violate. The court in which the proceeding is pending shall grant such leave with respect to any objection
    which it finds is made in good faith and with respect to which it finds there is reasonable and substantial excuse for the defendant's failure to present such objection in an administrative proceeding before the city rent agency. Upon the filing of
    a petition pursuant to and within thirty days from the granting of such leave, the supreme court shall have jurisdiction to enjoin or set aside in whole or in part the provision of the regulation or order complained of or to dismiss the petition.
    The court may authorize the introduction of evidence, either to the city rent agency or directly to the court, in accordance with subdivision a of this section. The provisions of subdivision b of this section shall be applicable with respect to any
    proceedings instituted in accordance with this subdivision. d. In any proceeding brought pursuant to subdivision ten of section one of the state enabling act or section 26-413 of this chapter involving an alleged violation of any provision of any
    such regulation or order, the court shall stay the proceeding: (1) During the period within which a petition may be filed in the supreme court pursuant to leave granted under subdivision c of this section with respect to such provision; (2) During
    the pendency of any protest properly filed under section 26-410 of this chapter prior to the institution of the proceeding under subdivision ten of section one of the state enabling act or section 26-413 of this chapter, setting forth objections to
    the validity of such provision which the court finds to have been made in good faith; and (3) During the pendency of any judicial proceeding instituted by the defendant under this section with respect to such protest or instituted by the defendant
    under subdivision c of this section with respect to such provision, and until the expiration of the time allowed in this section for the taking of further proceedings with respect thereto. e. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision d of this
    section, stays shall be granted thereunder in civil proceedings only after judgment and upon application made within five days after judgment. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision d of this section, in the case of a proceeding under paragraph
    (a) of subdivision ten of section one of the state enabling act or subdivision a of section 26-413 of this chapter, the court granting a stay under subdivision d of this section shall issue a temporary injunction or restraining order enjoining or
    restraining, during the period of the stay, violations by the defendant of any provision of the regulation or order involved in the proceeding. If any provision of a regulation or order is determined to be invalid by judgment of the supreme court
    which has become effective in accordance with subdivision b of this section, any proceeding pending in any court shall be dismissed, and any judgment in such proceeding vacated, to the extent that such proceeding or judgment is based upon violation
    of such provision. Except as provided in subdivisions c and d of this section and as heretofore provided in this subdivision e, the pendency of any protest under section 26-410 of this chapter before the city rent agency or judicial proceeding under
    this section, shall not be grounds for staying any proceeding brought pursuant to subdivision ten of section one of the state enabling act or section 26-413 of this chapter; nor, except as provided in this subdivision e, shall any retroactive effect
    be given to any judgment setting aside a provision of a regulation or order. f. The method prescribed herein for the judicial review of a regulation or order of the city rent agency shall be exclusive.</text>
</level>