<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-507</num>
  <heading>Mandatory penalties.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-507 Mandatory penalties. a. The commission or successor agency shall fine any driver, or suspend or revoke the driver's license of any driver, as provided in subdivision b of this section, who shall have been found in violation of any of the following:
    1. No driver of a taxicab shall seek to ascertain, without justifiable grounds, the destination of a passenger before such passenger shall be seated in the vehicle. 2. No driver of a taxicab shall refuse, without justifiable grounds, to take any passenger
    or prospective passenger to any destination within the city. 3. No driver of a vehicle the fares of which are set by the commission or successor agency shall charge or attempt to charge a fare above the fare set by the commission or successor agency.
    4. No driver of a for-hire vehicle, other than a driver operating a for-hire vehicle with a valid HAIL license, shall accept passengers unless the passengers have engaged the use of the for-hire vehicle on the basis of telephone contract or prearrangement.
    b. 1. Any driver who has been found to have violated a provision of paragraph one, two or three of subdivision a of this section, or any combination thereof, shall be fined not less than two hundred dollars nor more than five hundred dollars for the
    first offense. Any driver who has been found in violation of any of the provisions of such paragraphs, or any combination thereof, for a second time within a twenty-four month period shall be fined not less than three hundred fifty dollars nor more
    than one thousand dollars, and the commission may suspend the driver's license of such driver for a period not to exceed thirty days. Any driver who has been found to have violated any of the provisions of paragraph one, two or three of such subdivision,
    or any combination thereof, three or more times within a thirty-six month period shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars for each such third or subsequent offense, and the commission shall revoke the driver's license of such driver. Any
    driver who has been found to have violated any of the provisions of paragraph four of subdivision a of this section shall be fined not less than two hundred dollars nor more than three hundred fifty dollars for the first offense. Any driver who has
    been found in violation of any of the provisions of such paragraph for a second time within a twenty-four month period shall be fined not less than three hundred fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars, and the commission may suspend the
    driver's license of such driver for a period not to exceed thirty days. The commission shall revoke the driver's license of any driver who has been found to have violated any of the provisions of paragraph four of such subdivision three or more times
    within a thirty-six month period. 2. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph one of this subdivision, the commission shall revoke the driver's license of any person found to have violated paragraph three of subdivision a of this section by charging
    or attempting to charge a fare of ten dollars or more above the approved rate of fare for taxicabs. 3. Any driver or vehicle owner of a vehicle licensed by the commission or base station licensee who facilitates sex trafficking with a vehicle shall
    be liable for a civil penalty of ten thousand dollars, and the commission shall revoke the license of such driver, the license of the vehicle used to commit such facilitation when the person who facilitated sex trafficking is the owner of such vehicle,
    and the license of the base station licensee when such base station licensee committed such facilitation and the vehicle used to commit such facilitation was affiliated with the base station licensed by such licensee at the time such offense was committed.
    c. The commission shall not issue any license under this chapter to any person who has had his or her driver's license revoked pursuant to subdivision b of this section prior to a period of one year from the date of such revocation. d. 1. Each owner
    shall make a reasonable good faith effort, by a driver education program or other affirmative measures, to deter the commission of violations of paragraphs one, two and three of subdivision a of this section by drivers of taxicabs for which such owner
    holds a vehicle license. A finding that a driver has committed a violation of any such paragraph shall create a rebuttable presumption that the owner holding the vehicle license for the taxicab in which such violation was committed has failed to make
    a reasonable good faith effort to deter the commission of such violation. In any proceeding for a violation of this paragraph, it is an affirmative defense that the owner made a reasonable good faith effort, by a driver education program or other
    affirmative measures, to deter the commission of violations of paragraphs one, two and three of subdivision a of this section. The commission shall advise an owner in writing of his or her potential liability pursuant to this subdivision upon a finding
    that a violation of such paragraph was committed in a taxicab for which such owner holds a vehicle license. 2. If the owner holding a vehicle license for a taxicab or taxicabs in which a driver or drivers have been found to have committed violations
    of paragraphs one, two or three of subdivision a of this section, or any combination thereof, is found not to have made a reasonable good faith effort to deter such violation, the owner shall be liable for a violation of paragraph one of this subdivision
    as follows: (i) for the second violation of paragraphs one, two or three of subdivision a of this section, or any combination thereof, committed in a taxicab or taxicabs for which the owner holds a vehicle license or licenses, the commission shall
    fine the owner two hundred dollars; (ii) for the third violation of paragraphs one, two or three of subdivision a of this section, or any combination thereof, committed in a taxicab or taxicabs for which the owner holds a vehicle license or licenses,
    the commission shall fine the owner not less that two hundred dollars nor more than three hundred fifty dollars; (iii) for the fourth and each subsequent violation of paragraphs one, two or three of subdivision a of this section, or any combination
    thereof, committed in a taxicab or taxicabs for which the owner holds a vehicle license or licenses, the commission shall fine the owner not less than three hundred fifty nor more than five hundred dollars; (iv) for the fifth and each subsequent violation
    of paragraphs one, two or three of subdivision a of this section, or any combination thereof, committed in a taxicab or taxicabs for which the owner holds a vehicle license or licenses, the commission shall suspend the vehicle license of the taxicab
    used in the commission of the most recent violation for a period not to exceed sixty days. For purposes of this paragraph, the obligation to have made a "reasonable good faith effort" shall be met if the owner, upon the hiring of each new driver and
    for all drivers, shall, at least once annually, distribute a copy of applicable commission rules to each driver and obtains a written receipt therefore. The commission shall supply owners with a copy of all such applicable rules. In addition, such
    rules shall be conspicuously posted by the owner at the owner's place of business so that they are readily visible to all drivers. 3. The commission shall promulgate rules and regulations setting forth the procedure for an administrative adjudication
    of violations of paragraph one of this subdivision, which shall include provision for notice and a hearing. e. The term "without justifiable ground" used in paragraphs one and two of subdivision a of this section shall mean that standard of behavior
    which fails to conform to that of a reasonable and prudent person acting in compliance with any regulations promulgated by the commission. f. The commission may suspend or revoke the license of any person whom it determines has obtained a license
    by fraud or false representation, or willful misstatement or omission of a material fact.</text>
</level>