<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-255</num>
  <heading>Inspection; registration plate.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-255 Inspection; registration plate. a. It shall be unlawful for a pedicab business to operate or authorize the operation of, or for a pedicab driver to operate, a pedicab unless: 1. it has been inspected by the department; 2. it has been issued
    a registration plate that indicates on such plate the expiration date of the current registration; and 3. such registration is in effect. b. The registration shall be valid for a period no longer than one year and the expiration date of such registration
    plate shall be a date specified by the commissioner by rule, except that the registrations issued prior to November 1, 2010 shall expire on November 1, 2010. c. If the commissioner determines after such inspection that a pedicab is equipped with the
    features set forth in subdivision a of section 20-254, and complies with the requirement set forth in subdivision b of section 20-254, upon payment of the registration fee provided by section 20-250 of this subchapter, the department shall issue a
    registration plate to the pedicab business that authorized the operation of such pedicab. d. Such registration plate shall be securely affixed by the department to a conspicuous and indispensable part of each pedicab. e. The registration plate shall
    be of such material, form, design and dimension and set forth such distinguishing number or other identification marks as the commissioner shall prescribe. f. A pedicab business shall pay an additional fifty-five dollars as the re-inspection fee for
    any pedicab that fails to appear at an inspection scheduled by the department or that is determined upon inspection not to meet the requirements of this section and such business re-applies for a registration plate. The commissioner shall also have
    the authority to determine the circumstances under which reinspections of pedicabs shall be permitted. g. It shall be unlawful for a person to whom a registration plate has been issued to transfer any interest in such plate to any other person unless:
    1. the pedicab, if intended to be transferred with the registration plate, complies with all applicable requirements imposed by this subchapter; 2. such transfer will not result in a violation of subdivision d of section 20-251; and 3. the commissioner
    approves such transfer.</text>
</level>