<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-263</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-263 Penalties. a. It is a traffic infraction to violate any provision of this subchapter and such traffic infractions shall be punishable in accordance with section eighteen hundred of the New York state vehicle and traffic law. b. Any person who
    violates any provision of this subchapter or any rules promulgated pursuant to this subchapter shall be subject to a civil penalty that shall not be: (1) less than two hundred nor more than five hundred dollars for the first violation and for each
    additional violation committed on the same day; (2) less than five hundred nor more than one thousand dollars for the second violation committed, and each additional violation committed on the same day, within a one year period; (3) less than one
    thousand nor more than four thousand dollars for the third violation committed, and each additional violation committed on the same day, within a one year period. The pedicab business that authorizes the operation of such pedicab shall be jointly
    and severally liable with the pedicab driver thereof, for the penalties imposed by this section. c. A violation of section 20-250 or 20-257 or paragraph 6 of subdivision b of section 20-259 of this subchapter or any rules promulgated thereunder shall
    constitute a violation punishable by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars or imprisonment of up to fifteen days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. d. Any police or peace officer or authorized officer or employee of the department, upon
    service on the pedicab business or pedicab driver of a notice of violation for the failure of the pedicab business to obtain the required inspection of a pedicab or have a valid registration plate affixed to the pedicab pursuant to section 20-255
    or for the failure of a pedicab driver to be licensed pursuant to section 20-257, may seize such pedicab. Any pedicab seized pursuant to this subdivision shall be delivered into the custody of the department or other appropriate agency. The commissioner
    shall hold a hearing to adjudicate the violation of subdivision a of section 20-255 or section 20-257 within two business days after the date of the seizure and shall render his or her determination within two business days after the conclusion of
    the hearing. e. A pedicab business shall be eligible to obtain release of a pedicab seized pursuant to subdivision d of this section prior to the hearing provided for in such subdivision, if such business has not been found liable for a violation
    of subdivision a of section 20-255 or section 20-257 within a five-year period prior to the violation resulting in seizure. The pedicab shall be released to such business upon the posting of an all cash bond in a form satisfactory to the commissioner
    in an amount sufficient to cover the maximum civil penalties which may be imposed for a violation of subdivision a of section 20-255 or section 20-257 and all reasonable costs for removal and storage of such vehicle. f. Where the commissioner, after
    adjudication of the violation of subdivision a of section 20-255 or section 20-257, finds that the pedicab business has not violated such subdivision, the department shall promptly release such pedicab upon written demand of the pedicab business.
    g. Where the commissioner, after adjudication of the violation of subdivision a of section 20-255 or section 20-257, finds a violation of such subdivision or such section, then (i) if the pedicab is not subject to forfeiture pursuant to paragraph
    one of subdivision i of this section, the department shall release such pedicab to the pedicab business upon payment of all applicable civil penalties and all reasonable costs of removal and storage; or (ii) if the pedicab is subject to forfeiture
    pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision i of this section, the department may release such pedicab to the pedicab business upon payment of all civil penalties and all reasonable costs of removal and storage, or may commence a forfeiture action within
    ten days after the written demand by such business for such pedicab. h. The department shall establish by rule the time within which pedicabs that are not redeemed may be deemed abandoned and the procedures for disposal. i. 1. In addition to any other
    penalty or sanction provided for in section 20-261 or in this section, a pedicab seized pursuant to subdivision d of this section, and all rights, title and interest therein shall be subject to forfeiture to the city upon notice and judicial determination
    thereof if the pedicab business that owns such pedicab has been found liable at least two times within a five-year period for failing to have such pedicab inspected as required by subdivision a of section 20-255 or for permitting operation by an unlicensed
    pedicab driver in violation of section 20-257. 2. A forfeiture action pursuant to this subdivision shall be commenced by the filing of a summons with a notice or a summons and complaint in accordance with the civil practice law and rules. Such summons
    with notice or a summons and complaint shall be served in accordance with the civil practice law and rules on the pedicab business that owns such pedicab, and on any person listed on an application or other record of the department as an owner of
    such pedicab. A pedicab which is the subject of such action shall remain in the custody of the department or other appropriate agency pending the final determination of the forfeiture action. 3. Any person who receives notice of the institution of
    a forfeiture action who claims an interest in the pedicab subject to forfeiture may assert a claim in such action for the recovery of the pedicab or satisfaction of such owner's interest in such pedicab. 4. Forfeiture pursuant to this subdivision
    shall be made subject to the interest of a person who claims an interest in such pedicab pursuant to subdivision three of this subdivision, where such person establishes that: (i) such pedicab was operated without having been inspected as required
    by subdivision a of section 20-255 or operated in violation of section 20-257 without the knowledge of such person, or if such person had knowledge of such operation, that such person did not consent to such operation by doing all that could reasonably
    have been done to prevent such operation, or (ii) that the operation of such pedicab without having been inspected as required by subdivision a of section 20-255 or operated in violation of section 20-257 was conducted by any person other than such
    person claiming an interest in the pedicab, while such pedicab was unlawfully in the possession of a person who acquired possession thereof in violation of the criminal laws of the United States or any state. 5. The department or agency having custody
    of the pedicab, after judicial determination of forfeiture, shall, by public notice of at least five days, sell such forfeited pedicab at public sale. The net proceeds of any such sale shall be paid into the general fund of the city. 6. In any forfeiture
    action commenced pursuant to this subdivision, where the court awards a sum of money to one or more persons in satisfaction of such person's interest in the forfeited pedicab, the total amount awarded to satisfy such interest or interests shall not
    exceed the amount of the net proceeds of the sale of the forfeited vehicle after deduction of the lawful expenses incurred by the city, including reasonable costs of removal and storage of the pedicab between the time of the seizure and the date of
    sale. j. The penalties provided by subdivisions a, b, c, d and i of this section shall be in addition to any other penalty imposed by any other provision of law or rule promulgated thereunder.</text>
</level>