<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-118</num>
  <heading>Littering prohibited.</heading>
  <text>ยง 16-118 Littering prohibited. 1. No person shall litter, sweep, throw or cast, or direct, suffer or permit any servant, agent, employee, or other person under his or her control, to litter, sweep, throw or cast any ashes, garbage, paper, dust or other
    rubbish and refuse of any kind whatsoever, in or upon any street or public place, vacant lot, air shaft, areaway, backyard court or alley. 2. (a) Every owner, lessee, tenant, occupant or person in charge of any building or premises shall keep and
    cause to be kept the sidewalk, flagging and curbstone abutting said building or premises free from obstruction and nuisances of every kind, and shall keep said sidewalks, flagging, curbstones, and air shafts, areaways, backyards, courts and alleys
    free from garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other offensive material. Such persons shall also remove garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other offensive material between the curbstone abutting the building or premises and the roadway
    area extending one and one-half feet from the curbstone into the street on which the building or premises front. Such persons shall not, however, be responsible for cleaning the garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other offensive material
    which accumulates at catch basins located within the one and one-half foot distance from the curbstone into the street. (b) Every owner, lessee, tenant or person in charge of any vacant lot shall keep and cause to be kept the sidewalk, flagging and
    curbstone abutting said vacant lot free from obstruction and nuisances of every kind, and shall keep said sidewalks, flagging and curbstones free from garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other offensive material. Every owner, lessee, tenant
    or person in charge of any vacant lot shall keep and cause to be kept said vacant lot free from garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other offensive material. Such persons shall also remove garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other
    offensive material between the curbstone abutting the vacant lot and the roadway area extending one and one-half feet from the curbstone into the street on which the vacant lot fronts. Such persons shall not, however, be responsible for cleaning the
    garbage, refuse, rubbish, litter, debris and other offensive material which accumulates at catch basins located within the one and one-half foot distance from the curbstone into the street. 3. No lime, ashes, coal, dry sand, hair, waste paper, feathers,
    or other substance that is in a similar manner liable to be blown by the wind, shall be sieved, agitated, or exposed, nor shall any mat, carpet, or cloth be shaken or beaten, nor shall any cloth, yarn, garment, material or substance be scoured or
    cleaned, nor shall any rags, damaged merchandise, barrels, boxes, or broken bales of merchandise or goods be placed, kept, or exposed in any place where they or particles therefrom will pass into any street or public place, or into any occupied premises,
    nor shall any usual or any reasonable precautions be omitted by any person to prevent fragments or any substances from falling to the detriment or peril of life or health, or dust or light material flying into any street, place, or building, from
    any building or erection, while the same is being altered, repaired or demolished, or otherwise. In demolishing any building or part thereof, the material to be removed shall be properly wet in order to lay dust incident to its removal. 4. No one,
    being the owner, or in charge or in control of any vehicle, or of any receptacle, shall litter, drop or spill, or permit to be littered, dropped or spilled any dirt, sand, gravel, clay, loam, stone or building rubbish, hay, straw, oats, sawdust, shavings
    or other light materials of any sort, or manufacturing, trade or household waste, refuse, rubbish of any sort, or ashes, manure, garbage, or other organic refuse or other offensive matter, in or upon any street or public place. 5. No person shall
    throw, cast or distribute, or cause or permit to be thrown, cast or distributed, any handbill, circular, card, booklet, placard or other advertising matter whatsoever, in or upon any street or public place, or in a front yard or courtyard, or on any
    stoop, or in the vestibule of any hall in any building, or in a letter box therein; provided that nothing herein contained shall be deemed to prohibit or otherwise regulate the delivery of any such matter by the United States postal service, or prohibit
    the distribution of sample copies of newspapers regularly sold by the copy or by annual subscription. This section is not intended to prevent the lawful distribution of anything other than commercial and business advertising matter. 6. No swill, brine,
    offensive animal matter, noxious liquid, or other filthy matter of any kind, shall be allowed by any person to fall upon or run into any street, or public place, or be taken to or put therein. 7. No person shall prevent, or otherwise interfere with,
    the sweeping or cleaning of any street, the removal of snow or ice from any street or the collection or removal of any solid waste or recyclable material from any street, by any employee of the department. 8. The violation of any provision of this
    section shall constitute an offense punishable by a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than two hundred fifty dollars, or by imprisonment not to exceed ten days, or both. 9. Any person violating the provisions of this section shall be liable
    for a civil penalty of not less than fifty dollars nor more than two hundred fifty dollars, except that for a second violation of subdivision one, three, four, or six of this section within any twelve-month period, such person shall be liable for
    a civil penalty of not less than two hundred fifty dollars nor more than three hundred fifty dollars and for a third or subsequent violation of subdivision one, three, four or six of this section within any twelve-month period such person shall be
    liable for a civil penalty of not less than three hundred fifty dollars nor more than four hundred fifty dollars. 10. In the instance where the notice of violation, appearance ticket or summons is issued for breach of the provisions of this section
    and sets forth thereon civil penalties only, such process shall be returnable to the environmental control board, which shall have the power to impose the civil penalties hereinabove provided in subdivision nine of this section. 11. In the event that
    a violator fails to answer such notice of violation, appearance ticket or summons within the time provided therefor by the rules and regulations of the environmental control board, he or she shall become liable for additional penalties. The additional
    penalties shall not exceed four hundred fifty dollars for each violation.</text>
</level>