<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3005</num>
  <heading>Jurisdiction, powers and duties of the commissioner.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-3005 Jurisdiction, powers and duties of the commissioner. a. The commissioner is authorized to exercise all powers necessary to enforce the electrical code and the electrical code technical standards, including but not limited to the power to:
    1. Promulgate rules respecting the installing, altering, maintaining or repairing of (i) electric wires and wiring apparatus and other appliances used or to be used for the transmission of electricity for electric light, heat, power, signaling, communication,
    alarm or data transmission and (ii) low voltage electrical wiring in or on any building, premises or lot in the city of New York. 2. Cause any wiring or appliances for electrical light, heat or power to be examined and inspected, and the approval
    thereof to be certified in writing, (a) by an officer or employee of the department designated by him or her for that purpose, or (b) by any inspection agency certified by the commissioner in accordance with rules promulgated by the commissioner,
    or (c) when such wiring or appliances are located in a building owned by the city or any city agency, (i) by a licensed professional engineer, or (ii) by a person with a baccalaureate degree in electrical engineering, or (iii) by any person who holds
    the job title of electrical inspector or any job title equivalent thereto, as classified by the commissioner of citywide administrative services pursuant to section eight hundred fourteen of the charter; provided, however, that such licensed professional
    engineer or person with a baccalaureate degree in electrical engineering or person holding the job title of electrical inspector shall not have performed the work to be inspected and shall be an officer or employee of the city agency which contracted
    for such work. 3. Order the remedying of any defect or deficiency in the installing, altering or repairing of electric wires and wiring apparatus and other appliances used or to be used for the transmission of electricity for electric light, heat,
    power, signaling, communication, alarm or data transmission. 4. Cause any order issued by him or her which has not been complied with to be enforced and to take any civil or criminal proceedings or actions for its enforcement. 5. Order any person
    or corporation engaged in supplying electrical energy to discontinue such supply as specified in such order if the wiring or appliances for electric light, heat, power, signaling, communication, alarm or data transmission shall be dangerous to persons
    or property therein. 6. (a) Promulgate rules fixing the date, scope and subject matter of examinations of applicants to become licensed as master electricians and special electricians and, upon recommendation of the license board, promulgate rules
    respecting the issuance, suspension and revocation of such licenses. (b) Promulgate rules fixing the date, scope and subject matter of examinations of applicants for certification as low voltage installer and respecting the issuance, suspension and
    revocation of such certification. 7. Appoint, in accordance with the rules of the department and at his or her discretion, special boards or committees to provide advice or assistance in the implementation, interpretation, variation or amendment of
    any provision of the electrical code or the electrical code technical standards or any rule promulgated pursuant to this chapter. 8. Promulgate rules regarding the issuance of approvals for the use of electrical appliances and materials and the granting
    of special permission to use wiring or appliances in cases involving the exercise of his or her discretion and in cases not covered by this chapter. 9. Designate as prescribed in section 14-106 of title fourteen of the code, with the consent of the
    police commissioner, certain electrical inspectors as special patrolmen of the police department. Such special patrolmen shall possess powers to perform the duties of and be subject to the orders, rules and regulations of the police department in
    the same manner as regular patrolmen. Each special patrolman shall have a badge and card, as furnished by the police department. He or she shall have power to issue summonses returnable in the New York city criminal court, covering violations of this
    chapter. b. The foregoing provisions are detailed statements of certain powers possessed by the commissioner and shall not be construed as limiting his or her authority.</text>
</level>