<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-436</num>
  <heading>Conduct of games of chance.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-436 Conduct of games of chance. 1. No person, firm, association, corporation or organization, other than a licensee under the provisions of this subchapter, shall conduct such game or shall lease or otherwise make available for conducting games
    of chance a hall or other premises for any consideration whatsoever, direct or indirect, except as provided in section 20-437 of this subchapter. 2. No game of chance shall be held, operated or conducted on or within any leased premises if rental
    under such lease is to be paid, wholly or partly, on the basis of a percentage of the receipts or net profits derived from the operation of such game. 3. No authorized organization licensed under the provisions of this subchapter shall purchase or
    receive any supplies or equipment specifically designed or adapted for use in the conduct of games of chance from other than a supplier licensed by the board or from another authorized organization. 4. The entire net proceeds of any game of chance
    and of any rental shall be exclusively devoted to the lawful purposes of the organization permitted to conduct the same. 5. No prize shall exceed the sum or value of one hundred dollars in any operation or conducting of a single game of chance as
    defined in section 20-435 of this subchapter. No single wager shall exceed ten dollars. 6. No series of prizes on any one occasion of games of chance shall aggregate more than one thousand dollars as defined in section 20-435 of this subchapter. 7.
    No person except a bona fide member of any such organization, its auxiliary or affiliated organization, shall participate in the management or operation of such game, as set forth in section 20-444 of this subchapter. 8. No person shall receive any
    remuneration for participating in the management or operation of any such game. 9. The unauthorized conduct of a game of chance shall constitute and be punishable as a misdemeanor.</text>
</level>