<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-1501</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 17-1501 Definitions. As used in this Chapter the following terms shall have the following meanings: a. "Consultative inspection" means an educational sanitary inspection of a food service establishment that shall not result in fines or a grade. b.
    "Covered languages" means Chinese, English, Haitian Creole, Korean, Bengali, Russian and Spanish, and any other language determined by the department. c. "Critical violations" shall have the meaning it is given in section 23-01 of title 24 of the
    rules of the city of New York. d. "Food service establishment" means any establishment inspected pursuant to the restaurant grading program established pursuant to subdivision a of section 81.51 of the health code of the city of New York. e. "Food
    service establishment inspector" means any individual employed by the department who as part of his or her duties conducts inspections of food service establishments pursuant to subdivision a of section 81.51 of the health code of the city of New
    York. f. "General violations" shall have the meaning it is given in section 23-01 of title 24 of the rules of the city of New York. g. "Imminent health hazard or public health hazard" shall have the meaning it is given in section 81.03 of the health
    code of the city of New York. h. "Initial inspection" means the first sanitary inspection within an inspection cycle. i. "Inspection cycle" means a series of related inspections of food service establishments consisting of at least an initial inspection
    and including, if triggered by the initial or any subsequent inspections within that cycle, a reinspection and any compliance inspections conducted by the department because of a previous inspection score in that cycle. j. "Notice of violation" means
    a written notice issued by a food service establishment inspector alleging that there was a violation of law or regulation at the food service establishment on the day of the food service establishment inspection. k. "Sanitary inspection" means any
    on-site review by the department of a food service establishment's physical facilities, food handling operations, equipment, sanitary condition, maintenance, and worker hygiene practices. The term may include, but shall not be limited to include,
    initial, reinspection, compliance and pre-permit inspections.</text>
</level>