<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2115</num>
  <heading>Imposition of civil penalty.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2115 Imposition of civil penalty. (a) A person who violates any law relating to housing standards shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than ten dollars nor more than fifty dollars for each non-hazardous violation, not less than twenty-five
    dollars nor more than one hundred dollars and ten dollars per day for each hazardous violation, fifty dollars per day for each immediately hazardous violation, occurring in a multiple dwelling containing five or fewer dwelling units, from the date
    set for correction in the notice of violation until the violation is corrected, and not less than fifty dollars nor more than one hundred fifty dollars and, in addition, one hundred twenty-five dollars per day for each immediately hazardous violation,
    occurring in a multiple dwelling containing more than five dwelling units, from the date set for correction in the notice of violation until the violation is corrected. A person wilfully making a false certification of correction of a violation shall
    be subject to a civil penalty of not less than fifty dollars nor more than two hundred fifty dollars for each violation falsely certified, in addition to the other penalties herein provided. (b) The department shall serve a notice of violation upon
    the owner, his or her agent or other person responsible for its correction. The notice shall identify the condition constituting the violation, the provision of law applicable thereto, the department's order number, the classification of the violation
    according to its degree of hazard, the time for certifying the correction of such violation, and the amount of the possible penalty. It shall also advise that the department will, if requested, confer with the owner or his or her representative concerning
    the nature and extent of the work to be done to insure compliance and the methods of financing such work. In any case where the provisions of this section authorize the service of such notice by mail, the statement of any officer, clerk, or agent
    of the department, or of anyone authorized by the department to mail such notice of violation, subscribed and affirmed by such person as true under the penalties of perjury, which describes the mailing procedure used by the department, or by the department's
    mailing vendor, or which states that these procedures were in operation during the course of mailing a particular cycle of notices of violation, shall be admitted into evidence as presumptive evidence that a regular and systematic mailing procedure
    is followed by the department for the mailing of its notices of violation. Where the department introduces into evidence the business records which correspond to the various stages of the mailing of a particular cycle of notices of violation, pursuant
    to subdivision (c) of rule forty-five hundred eighteen of the civil practice law and rules, then a presumption shall have been established that the mailing procedure was followed in the case of such cycle, and that such notice of violation has been
    duly served. (c) The said notice of violation shall also specify the date by which each violation shall be corrected. Such date shall be: (1) ninety days from the date of mailing of the notice in the case of non-hazardous violations; (2) thirty days
    from the date of mailing of the notice in the case of hazardous violations; and (3) twenty-four hours in the case of immediately hazardous violations in which case the notice shall be served by personal delivery to a person in charge of the premises
    or to the person last registered with the city as the owner or agent, or, by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, to the person in charge of the premises or to the person last registered with the department as the owner or agent;
    provided that where a managing agent has registered with the department, such notice shall be served on the managing agent. Service of the notice shall be deemed completed five days from the date of mailing. The department may postpone the date by
    which a violation shall be corrected upon a showing, made within the time set for correction in the notice, that prompt action to correct the violation has been taken but that full correction cannot be completed within the time provided because of
    technical difficulties, inability to obtain necessary materials, funds, or labor, or inability to gain access to the dwelling unit wherein the violation occurs or such other part of the building as may be necessary to make the required repair. In
    the case of immediately hazardous violations such showing must be made prior to the close of business on the next full day the department is open following the period set for correction. The department may condition such postponement upon the applicant's
    written agreement to correct all violations placed against the premises by the department or other appropriate governmental agency and to satisfy within an appropriate period of time, all sums owing to the department for repairs made to said premises.
    The department may require such other conditions as are deemed necessary to insure correction of the violations within the time set by the postponement. The department shall prepare a written statement signed and dated by the person making such decision
    setting forth the reasons for the postponement of the date by which a violation shall be corrected or the reason for the denial of such application for postponement and said written statement shall be part of the record of the department. (d) On or
    before September first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, the department shall classify all violations of the multiple dwelling law, the housing maintenance code and other applicable state and local laws as non-hazardous, hazardous and immediately hazardous,
    secure the approval thereof by the advisory council to the housing part of the civil court of the city of New York and publish such classification in the City Record. Such classification shall be based on the effect of the violation upon the life,
    health or safety of the occupants of the building and upon the public. After October first, nineteen hundred seventy-two and prior to October fifteenth, nineteen hundred seventy-two, the department shall hold a public hearing on the proposed classifications.
    Notice of such public hearing shall be published in the City Record not less than thirty days prior to the hearing. Within fifteen days after the conclusion of the said hearing, the department shall forward to the advisory council the list with such
    proposed changes as it may recommend for their approval. Within ten days of the receipt of such list, the advisory council shall advise the department as to which changes they have approved. The department shall thereupon, within five days, cause
    the list, together with such changes as have been approved to be published once each week for two successive weeks in the City Record. Any person who may be aggrieved as an owner or tenant may, within thirty days of such first publication seek a review
    of the department's action, provided that no such review shall stay the effectiveness of such list or the operation of the housing part of the civil court of the city of New York. Thereafter, and from time to time, the department may modify the list
    with the approval of the advisory council after publication, and public hearing as provided for the original list. (e) In the event the department fails to promulgate such list as above provided, or to take any step in connection therewith within
    the time provided, the administrative judge of the civil court and the judicial conference may take such action as they deem necessary to insure the establishment of the housing part of the New York city civil court and its operation on April first,
    nineteen hundred seventy-three, as provided by law. (f) (1) The notice of violation shall direct that when any violations of a particular class have been corrected, they may be certified at one time to the department or, in the alternative, each violation
    may be separately and independently certified. Such certification shall be made in writing, under oath by the registered owner, a registered officer or director of a corporate owner or by the registered managing agent except that, in the alternative,
    such certification may be submitted in an electronic form in accordance with the rules of the department which shall provide a mechanism for authenticating the source of the electronic submission; the department shall be required to accept such electronic
    submissions if submitted in accordance with such rules on and after the effective date of the local law that added these provisions authorizing such electronic submissions. Such certification shall be delivered to the department in person or electronically
    and acknowledgement of receipt therefor obtained or shall be mailed to the department by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, no later than fourteen days after the date set for correction in the case of non-hazardous and hazardous
    violations, and no later than five days after the date set for correction in the case of immediately hazardous violations, and shall include the date when each violation was corrected. Such certification of correction shall be supported by a sworn
    statement, which may be submitted in an electronic form in accordance with the rules of the department, by the person who performed the work if performed by an employee or agent of the owner. (2) A copy of such certification shall then be mailed not
    more than twelve calendar days from the date of receipt of notification to any complainant by the department. (3) Such violation shall be deemed corrected seventy days from the date of receipt of such certification by the department unless the department
    has determined by a reinspection made within such period that the violation still has not been corrected and has recorded such determination upon its records and has notified the person who executed the certification by registered or certified mail
    to the address stated in the certification that it has been set aside and the reasons therefor; a copy of such notice shall be sent to the complainant. (4) If the department does not inspect the premises after notification by the complainant that
    a violation has not been corrected, any tenant affected by such false certification shall have the right to apply to the court for a determination of violation as provided in subdivision (h) of this section, at which time the court shall assess appropriate
    penalties as provided in this section for any wilfully false certification it finds. (5) Upon receipt of notice that the certification has been set aside the owner or his or her agent shall then have a right to apply to the court for a determination
    that such violation was corrected. Notice of such right shall appear on each notice that a certification has been set aside. (6) Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event an owner files with his or her certification a copy of a contract of sale
    or letter of commitment for a mortgage or refinancing of a mortgage covering the premises and further certifies that such sale or mortgage transaction is to occur within one hundred days of such certification, such violation shall be deemed corrected
    thirty days from the date of receipt of such certification by the department, unless the department has determined by reinspection made within such period that the violation still has not been corrected, has recorded such determination upon its records
    and has given notice of such determination to the owner, and has thereafter brought an action within thirty days to set aside such certification, to impose a penalty for false certification and to collect such other penalties as have accrued, provided
    that in all such cases, the department shall make such reinspection. (7) Failure to file such certification of compliance shall establish a prima facie case that such violation has not been corrected. (g) When there are a number of separate instances
    of a single condition which violates any housing standard established by law, such separate instances shall be treated collectively as a single violation with respect to any one dwelling unit, or with respect to the public area of a building, but
    nothing contained in this subdivision shall limit the number of violations for which a penalty under this section may be collected with respect to each dwelling unit or the public area of a building. (h) (1) Should the department fail to issue a notice
    of violation upon the request of a tenant or group of tenants within thirty days of the date of such request, or if there is a notice of violation outstanding respecting the premises in which the tenant or group of tenants resides, or, if there is
    a claim of harassment pursuant to subdivision d of section 27-2005 of this chapter, the tenant or any group of tenants, may individually or jointly apply to the housing part for an order directing the owner and the department to appear before the
    court. Such order shall be issued at the discretion of the court for good cause shown, and shall be served as the court may direct. If the court finds a condition constituting a violation exists, it shall direct the owner to correct the violation
    and, upon failure to do so within the time set for certifying the correction of such violation pursuant to subdivision (c) of this section, it shall impose a penalty in accordance with subdivision (a) of this section. Nothing in this section shall
    preclude any person from seeking relief pursuant to any other applicable provision of law. (2)(i) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph one of this subdivision, where one or more allegations of harassment pursuant to subparagraphs b, c and g
    of paragraph 48 of subdivision a of section 27-2004 of this chapter is made, to the extent that any such allegation is based on physical conditions of a dwelling or dwelling unit, such allegation must be based at least in part on one or more violations
    of record issued by the department or any other agency. Where any allegation of harassment is based on more than one physical condition, the existence of at least one violation of record with respect to any such physical condition shall be deemed
    sufficient to meet the requirements of this paragraph. (ii) The provisions of subparagraph i of this paragraph shall apply to any counterclaim or defense presented by a tenant in any proceeding in the housing part of the civil court if such counterclaim
    or defense is based on one or more allegations of harassment. In the event there is no violation of record with respect to at least one physical condition alleged by such tenant such counterclaim or defense shall be dismissed without prejudice. (i)
    In the event an owner fails to correct a violation within the time specified in a notice of violation sent to the owner, his or her agent or other person responsible for its correction pursuant to subdivision (b) of this section, or within any additional
    time granted pursuant to subdivision (c) of this section, and no certification of correction with respect to such violation has been filed by the owner or his or her registered managing agent in accordance with the provisions of subdivision (f) hereof,
    then at any time after thirty days have elapsed from the date such violation was to be corrected, any tenant or group of tenants who requested that the violation be issued may apply individually or jointly, to the housing part for an order directing
    the owner and the department to appear before the court. Where the violation is hazardous or immediately hazardous, the thirty-day requirement shall be waived. Said order shall be issued by the court for good cause shown. If the court finds that the
    violation has not been corrected, that more than thirty days have elapsed since the time to correct same has expired where a violation is non-hazardous, and that no certification of correction has been filed in accordance with the provisions of subdivision
    (f) hereof, then it shall direct the owner to correct the violation and shall assess penalties as provided in subdivision (a) of this section. (j) If a tenant seeks an order directing the owner and the department to appear before the court pursuant
    to subdivision (h) or (i) of this section, the court may allow service of the order by the tenant by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested. (k) (1) (i) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person who violates section 27-2028,
    subdivision a of section 27-2029, section 27-2031 or section 27-2032 of this chapter shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than two hundred fifty nor more than five hundred dollars per day for each violation from and including the date the
    notice is affixed pursuant to paragraph two of this subdivision until the date the violation is corrected and not less than five hundred nor more than one thousand dollars per day for each subsequent violation of such sections at the same dwelling
    or multiple dwelling that occurs within two consecutive calendar years or, in the case of subdivision a of section 27-2029, during two consecutive periods of October first through May thirty-first. A person who violates subdivision b of section 27-2029
    of this chapter shall be subject to a civil penalty of twenty-five dollars per day from and including the date the notice is affixed pursuant to paragraph two of this subdivision until the date the violation is corrected but not less than one thousand
    dollars. There shall be a presumption that the condition constituting a violation continues after the affixing of the notice. (ii) Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (i) of this paragraph and section 27-2116 of this chapter, the civil
    penalties set forth in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be deemed satisfied for a first violation of section 27-2028, subdivision a of section 27-2029, section 27-2031 or section 27-2032 of this chapter if a notice, in a form prescribed by
    the department, that such violation has been corrected by the owner or an agent or employee of the owner within twenty-four hours of the affixing of the notice of such violation pursuant to paragraph two of this subdivision, and a payment of two hundred
    fifty dollars, are submitted to the department within ten days of affixing the notice of such violation. A person who submits a false notice of correction shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than two hundred fifty dollars for each false
    notice of correction, in addition to the other penalties herein provided. If the notice of correction and payment are not received within such ten-day period then the penalties set forth in subparagraph (i) of this paragraph shall be applicable to
    such violations and the department may commence a proceeding for an order to correct and to recover such penalties in accordance with this section and section 27-2116 of this chapter. A person who has violated section 27-2028, subdivision a of section
    27-2029, section 27-2031 or section 27-2032 of this chapter may allege as a defense or in mitigation of liability for civil penalties, compliance with the notice of correction and payment requirements of this subparagraph in any proceeding brought
    by the department seeking civil penalties under this subdivision. The process for submission of the notice of correction and payment set forth in this subparagraph shall not be available if a violation of section 27-2028, section 27-2031 or section
    27-2032 of this chapter occurred at the same dwelling or multiple dwelling during the prior calendar year or, in the case of subdivision a of section 27-2029 of this chapter, if a violation of such subdivision occurred at the same dwelling or multiple
    dwelling during the prior period of October first through May thirty-first. (iii) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, within five business days from the date of receipt of the notice of correction by the department, the department shall mail
    to the occupant of any dwelling unit for which such violation was issued notification that the owner has submitted a notice of correction for such violation. The notification to the occupant shall include information on when the violation was reportedly
    corrected and how the occupant may object to such notice of correction. In addition, the provisions of paragraphs 4 and 5 of subdivision f of this section shall also be applicable to a notice of correction submitted in compliance with subparagraph
    (ii) of this paragraph. (iv) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person who, after inspection by the department, is issued an immediately hazardous violation for a third or any subsequent violation of section 27-2028, section 27-2031 or
    section 27-2032 of this chapter at the same dwelling or multiple dwelling within the same calendar year or, in the case of subdivision a of section 27-2029 of this chapter, at the same dwelling or multiple dwelling within the same period of October
    first through May thirty-first, shall be subject to a fee of two hundred dollars for each inspection that results in the issuance of such violation as well as any civil penalties that may be due and payable for the violation, provided, however, that
    such fee shall not be applicable to inspections performed in a multiple dwelling that is included in the alternative enforcement program pursuant to article ten of subchapter five of this chapter. All fees that remain unpaid shall constitute a debt
    recoverable from the owner and a lien upon the premises, and upon the rents and other income thereof. The provisions of article eight of subchapter five of this chapter shall govern the effect and enforcement of such debt and lien. (2) Notwithstanding
    any other provision of law, the department shall serve a notice upon the owner, his or her agent or other person responsible for the correction of violations by affixing such notice in a conspicuous place on the premises. The notice shall identify
    the condition constituting the violation, the provision of law applicable thereto, the date the violation was reported and set the penalty attendant thereto. (3) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the owner shall be responsible for the correction
    of all violations placed pursuant to article eight of subchapter two of this code, but in an action for civil penalties pursuant to this article may in defense or mitigation of such owner's liability for civil penalties show: (i) That the condition
    which constitutes the violation did not exist at the time the violation was placed; or (ii) That he or she began to correct the condition which constitutes the violation promptly upon discovering it but that full correction could not be completed
    expeditiously because of technical difficulties, inability to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor, or inability to gain access to the dwelling unit wherein the violation occurs, or such other portion of the building as might be necessary to
    make the repair; or (iii) That he or she was unable to obtain a permit or license necessary to correct the violation, provided that diligent and prompt application was made therefor; or (iv) That the violation giving rise to the action was caused
    by the act or negligence, neglect or abuse of another not in the employ or subject to the direction of the owner; or (v) That in addition to any other defense or mitigation set forth in subparagraphs (i) through (iv) of this paragraph, with respect
    to an owner who may be subject to the penalty of not less than five hundred nor more than one thousand dollars per day with respect to a subsequent violation pursuant to paragraph one of this subdivision, documentation of prompt and diligent efforts
    to correct the conditions that gave rise to an initial violation and that such conditions were corrected. Where demonstrated, such subsequent violation shall be treated as though it was an initial violation. However, this defense or mitigation may
    not be asserted or demonstrated where the initial and subsequent violations occurred in the same calendar year or, in the case of violations of subdivision a of section 27-2029, during the same period of October first through May thirty-first. Where
    the aforesaid allegations are made by way of mitigation of penalties, the owner shall show, by competent proof, pertinent financial data, and efforts made to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor or to gain access, or to obtain a permit or license
    and such other evidence as the court may require. If the court finds that sufficient mitigating circumstances exist, it may remit all or part of any penalties arising from the violation, but may condition such remission upon a correction of the violation
    within a time period fixed by the court. (l)(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, when the department serves a notice of violation to correct and certify a condition that constitutes a violation of article fourteen of subchapter two of this
    chapter, the notice of violation shall specify the date by which the violation shall be corrected, which shall be twenty-one days after service of the notice of violation, and the procedure by which the owner, for good cause shown pursuant to this
    subdivision, may request a postponement. The notice of violation shall further specify that the violation shall be corrected in accordance with the work practices established in accordance with section 27-2056.11 of this code. The notice of violation
    shall be served by personal delivery to a person in charge of the premises or to the person last registered with the department as the owner or agent, or by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, or by certified mail with proof of
    delivery, to the person in charge of the premises or to the person last registered with the department as the owner or agent; provided that where a managing agent has registered with the department, such notice of violation shall be served on the
    managing agent. Service of the notice of violation shall be deemed completed three days from the date of mailing. Notification, in a form to be determined by the department, of the issuance of such violation shall be sent simultaneously by regular
    mail to the occupant at the dwelling unit that is the subject of such notice of violation. The department may postpone the date by which a violation shall be corrected upon a showing, made within the time set for correction in the notice, that prompt
    action to correct the violation has been taken but that full correction cannot be completed within the time provided because of serious technical difficulties, inability to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor, inability to gain access to the
    dwelling unit wherein the violation exists, or such other portion of the building as may be necessary to make the required repair. Such postponement shall not exceed fourteen days from the date of correction set forth in the notice of violation. The
    department may require such other conditions as are deemed necessary to insure correction of the violations within the time set for the postponement. The department may grant one additional postponement of no more than fourteen days for the reasons
    authorized by this section so long as the paint or other condition which is the subject of the violation has been stabilized. The department is also authorized to promulgate rules establishing criteria for a postponement of the time to correct for
    a longer period of time where such postponement is requested because of one or more substantial capital improvements will be made that will, when completed, significantly reduce the presence of lead-based paint in such multiple dwelling or dwelling
    unit including, but not limited to, a requirement that the paint which is the subject of the violation is stabilized. The department shall provide to the owner and the occupant a written statement signed and dated by the person making such decision
    setting forth the reasons for each postponement of the date by which a violation shall be corrected or the reason for the denial of such application for a postponement. Said written statement shall be part of the records of the department. (2) Notwithstanding
    any other provision of law, the notice of violation shall direct that the correction of each violation cited therein shall be certified to the department. Such certification shall be made in writing, under oath by the registered owner, a registered
    officer or director of a corporate owner or by the registered managing agent. Such certification shall include a statement that the violation was corrected in compliance with paragraph one of subdivision a of section 27-2056.11 of this code and shall
    include a copy of the lead-contaminated dust clearance test results. All certifications shall be delivered to the department and acknowledgment of receipt therefor obtained or shall be mailed to the department by certified or registered mail, return
    receipt requested, no later than five days after the date set for correction, and shall include the date when each violation was corrected. Such certification of correction shall be supported by a sworn statement by the person who performed the work
    if performed by an employee or agent of the owner. A copy of such certification shall be mailed to the complainant by the department not more than twelve full calendar days from the date of receipt of such certification by the department. Failure
    to file such certification shall establish a prima facie case that such violation has not been corrected. (3) Whenever the department shall issue a notice of violation to correct a condition that constitutes a violation of section 27-2056.6 of article
    fourteen of subchapter two of this chapter, the department shall within fourteen days after the date set for the correction of such violation conduct a final inspection to verify that the violation has been corrected. Where, upon conducting an inspection,
    the department determines that a violation has not been corrected, the department shall correct such violation within forty-five additional days of such inspection or in such shorter time as is practicable. (4) Notwithstanding any other provision
    of law, the department shall not remove a violation from its records nor shall it be deemed that such violation has been corrected unless the records of the department contain written verification that the department has conducted a final inspection
    of the premises and that such inspection verifies that the violation has been corrected, and copies of lead-contaminated dust clearance test results whenever such tests are required by applicable law, rule or regulation. A copy of the report of the
    final inspection of a dwelling unit and the status of the violation shall be mailed or delivered to the occupant and the owner. (5) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person making a false certification of correction of a violation issued
    pursuant to article 14 of subchapter 2 of this chapter, in addition to any other civil penalty, shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than one thousand dollars nor more than three thousand dollars for each false certification made, recoverable
    by the department in a civil action brought in a court of competent jurisdiction. If the person making such false certification is an employee of the owner then such owner shall be responsible for such civil penalty. In addition, any such person making
    a false certification of correction shall be guilty of a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of up to one thousand dollars or imprisonment for up to one year or both. (6) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person who violates article fourteen
    of subchapter two of this chapter by failing to correct such violation in accordance with paragraph one of subdivision a of section 27-2056.11 of this code shall be subject to a civil penalty of two hundred fifty dollars per day for each violation
    to a maximum of ten thousand dollars from the initial date set for correction in the notice of violation until the date the violation is corrected and certified to the department, and in addition to any civil penalty shall, whenever appropriate, be
    punished under the provisions of article three of subchapter five of this code. There shall be a presumption that the condition constituting a violation continues after the service of the notice of violation. The owner shall be responsible for the
    correction of all violations noticed pursuant to article fourteen of subchapter two of this chapter, but in an action for civil penalties pursuant to this subdivision may in defense or mitigation of such owner's liability for civil penalties show:
    (i) That the condition which constitutes the violation did not exist at the time the violation was placed; or (ii) That he or she began to correct the condition which constitutes the violation promptly upon discovering it but that full correction
    could not be completed expeditiously because of serious technical difficulties, inability to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor, or inability to gain access to the dwelling unit wherein the violation exists, or such other portion of the building
    as might be necessary to make the repair, provided that a postponement was granted pursuant to this subdivision; or (iii) That he or she was unable to obtain a permit or license necessary to correct the violation, provided that diligent and prompt
    application was made therefor; or (iv) That the violation giving rise to the action was caused by the act of negligence, neglect or abuse of another not in the employ or subject to the direction of the owner, except that the owner shall be precluded
    from showing in defense or mitigation of such owner's liability for civil penalties evidence of any acts occurring, undertaken, or performed by any predecessor in title prior to the owner taking control of the premises. Where the aforesaid allegations
    are made by way of mitigation of penalties, the owner shall show, by competent proof, pertinent financial data and efforts made to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor or to gain access, or to obtain a permit or license and such other evidence
    as the court may require. If the court finds that sufficient mitigating circumstances exist, it may remit all or part of any penalties arising from the violations, but may condition such remission upon a correction of the violation within a time period
    fixed by the court. (7) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, failure by the department to comply with any time period provided in this section relating to responsibilities of the department shall not render null and void any notice of violation
    issued by the department or the department of health and mental hygiene pursuant to such article or section, and shall not provide a basis for defense or mitigation of an owner's liability for civil penalties for violation of such article. (m)(1)
    Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a violation of subdivision d of section 27-2005 of this code shall be a class c immediately hazardous violation and a penalty shall be imposed in accordance with this section, provided, however, that such
    violation shall not be deemed a continuing class c violation of record beyond the time that the conduct constituting such violation occurred. (2) If a court of competent jurisdiction finds that conduct in violation of subdivision d of section 27-2005
    of this chapter has occurred, it may determine that a class c violation existed at the time that such conduct occurred. Notwithstanding the foregoing, such court may also issue an order restraining the owner of the property from violating such subdivision
    and direct the owner to ensure that no further violation occurs, in accordance with section 27-2121 of this chapter. Such court shall impose a civil penalty in an amount not less than one thousand dollars and not more than five thousand dollars for
    each dwelling unit in which a tenant or any person lawfully entitled to occupancy of such unit has been the subject of such violation, and such other relief as the court deems appropriate. It shall be an affirmative defense to an allegation by a tenant
    of the kind described in subparagraphs b, c and g of paragraph forty-eight of subdivision a of section 27-2004 of this chapter that (i) such condition or service interruption was not intended to cause any lawful occupant to vacate a dwelling unit
    or waive or surrender any rights in relation to such occupancy, and (ii) the owner acted in good faith in a reasonable manner to promptly correct such condition or service interruption, including providing notice to all affected lawful occupants of
    such efforts, where appropriate. (3) An owner may seek an order by the court enjoining a tenant from initiating any further judicial proceedings against such owner pursuant to this section claiming harassment without prior leave of the court if (i)
    within a ten-year period such tenant has initiated two judicial proceedings pursuant to this section against such owner claiming harassment that have been dismissed on the merits and (ii) a third or subsequent proceeding initiated by such tenant against
    such owner pursuant to this section claiming harassment during such ten-year period is determined at the time of its adjudication to be frivolous. Except for an order on consent such order may be sought by such owner simultaneously with the adjudication
    of such third or subsequent judicial proceeding. (4) Where the court determines that a claim of harassment by a tenant against an owner is so lacking in merit as to be frivolous, the court may award attorneys fees to such owner in an amount to be
    determined by the court. (5) Nothing in paragraphs three or four of this subdivision shall be construed to affect or limit any other claims or rights of the parties. n. The provisions of subdivision d of section 27-2005 of this chapter, subdivision
    m of this section and subdivision b of section 27-2120 of this chapter shall not apply where a shareholder of record on a proprietary lease for a dwelling unit, the owner of record of a dwelling unit owned as a condominium, or those lawfully entitled
    to reside with such shareholder or record owner, resides in the dwelling unit for which the proprietary lease authorizes residency or in such condominium unit, as is applicable, or to private dwellings.</text>
</level>