<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>16-472</num>
  <heading>Registration.</heading>
  <text>ยง 16-472 Registration. a. On or after January 1, 2014, no person shall, while using a motor vehicle, accept, receive, transfer from one motor vehicle to another motor vehicle, or otherwise collect recyclable containers in bulk from more than two persons
    on private property in the city of New York without registering with the department pursuant to the provisions set forth in this section. Any application for registration or for renewal of a registration submitted to the department shall include the
    following: i. name and address of each such person and owner of such motor vehicle used for acceptance of recyclable containers in bulk; and ii. the location, including the street address or nearest street address of the property, and tax block and
    lot number or numbers if more than one lot, or other information identifying specifically where such motor vehicle will accept recyclable containers in bulk and the name of the owner of such property and a signed certification from such owner approving
    the use of such property for the purpose of in bulk container acceptance. b. Such registration shall be conspicuously posted in such motor vehicle. c. Prior to issuing a registration pursuant to this section, the department shall confirm that any
    location where a motor vehicle proposes to collect recyclable containers in bulk as specified pursuant to paragraph ii of subdivision a of this section is zoned for such use. d. The commissioner may establish, by rule, a fee to process applications
    for registration pursuant to this section. e. Any registration issued by the department pursuant to this section shall expire one year from its issuance, and may be renewed thereafter. A request for renewal shall be reviewed by the department prior
    to such expiration of such registration, if such request is submitted to the department no later than forty-five days prior to the expiration of such registration.
  </text>
</level>