<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-342</num>
  <heading>Openings in fire divisions and separations.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-342 Openings in fire divisions and separations. Openings in fire divisions and fire separations that are required to have a fire-resistance rating, shall be protected by opening protectives having the fire-resistance ratings prescribed in table
    5-3, shall not exceed the limits in size and area herein prescribed, and shall comply with the provisions of section 27-329 of article three of this subchapter. Door and other openings in enclosures of vertical exits, exit passageways, corridors,
    and places of assembly shall be protected by opening protectives as required by the provisions of subchapters six and eight of this chapter. When such enclosures also serve as fire divisions or fire separations, openings therein shall be protected
    as required by the provisions of this subchapter. (a) Size of opening. In buildings that are not sprinklered no opening through a fire division or fire separation shall exceed one hundred twenty square feet in area, with no dimension greater than
    twelve feet, and the aggregate width of all openings at any level shall not exceed twenty-five percent of the length of the wall. Where the areas on both sides of a fire division or fire separation are sprinklered in accordance with the construction
    provisions of subchapter seventeen of this chapter, the size of the opening may be one hundred fifty square feet in area, with no dimension greater than fifteen feet. In buildings fully sprinklered in compliance with the provisions of subchapter seventeen
    of ths chapter, the size and aggregate width of openings through fire divisions or fire separations shall be unlimited. When a fire division or fire separation serves as a horizontal exit also, it shall have no opening other than door openings not
    exceeding fifty-six square feet in area, the aggregate width of all openings at any level shall not exceed twenty-five percent of the length of the wall, and shall comply with the provisions of section 27-373 of article five of subchapter six of this
    chapter. (b) Conveyor openings. Where fire doors or shutters are impractical for the protection of conveyor openings in fire divisions or fire separations, a system of water spray nozzles may be used. At least four nozzles shall be provided on each
    side of the opening so as to give complete coverage of the opening. Nozzles shall be controlled by an automatic valve actuated by a heat detector. Nozzles shall be located at an angle not more than thirty degrees between the centerline of nozzle discharge
    and a line perpendicular to the plane of the opening. The water discharge rate shall be at least three gallons per square foot per minute. When conveyor openings through floors are protected by this method, the openings shall also be provided with
    a noncombustible enclosure constructed around the conveyor from the floor up to or slightly beyond the spray nozzles, and draft curtains shall be provided extending twenty-four inches below and around the floor opening. Table 5-3 Opening Protectives
    for Fire Divisions and Fire Separations Fire-Resistance Rating of Fire Fire Protection Rating Division or Fire Separation of Opening Protective in which Opening Occurs (hr.) 3 or 4 3 hr. (Class A)* 2 or 1-1/2 1-1/2 hr. (Class B) 1 3/4 hr. (Class C)
    * Note--Shall consist of two one and one-half hour (class B) opening protectives, with one protective installed on each face of a fire division or fire separation.</text>
</level>