<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-261</num>
  <heading>Emergency suspension of registration and photo identification card.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-261 Emergency suspension of registration and photo identification card. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or rules promulgated thereto, the commissioner may, if he or she has reasonable cause to believe that the operation of any
    business or the presence of any person in a public wholesale market creates an imminent danger to life or property or to the orderly and lawful operation of the market, or that there has likely been false or fraudulent information submitted in an
    application made pursuant to this chapter, immediately suspend a registration or a permanent photo identification card without a prior hearing, provided that provision shall be made for an immediate appeal of such suspension to a deputy commissioner
    of the department who shall determine such appeal forthwith. In the event that the deputy commissioner upholds the suspension, an opportunity for a hearing shall be provided on an expedited basis, within a period not to exceed four business days and
    the commissioner shall issue a final determination no later than four business days following the conclusion of such hearing; and provided further that the commissioner may, upon application by a business whose registration has been suspended, permit
    such business to remain in the market for such time as is necessary to allow for the expeditious sale, consignment or removal of a perishable product if, in the commissioner's best judgment, such permission is consistent with the orderly operation
    and safety of the market. Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the emergency suspension of a photo identification card of an employee who is a member of a labor union or labor organization solely for the reason that such person is
    seeking or has sought to engage in the lawful exercise within a public wholesale market of an activity protected by the provisions of the National Labor Relations Act, 29 U.S.C. ยง141 et seq. The commissioner shall consult with the commissioner of
    labor relations prior to reaching any determination that an activity by a representative of a labor union or labor organization is not lawful under the National Labor Relations Act.</text>
</level>