<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-128.2</num>
  <heading>Bryant Park.</heading>
  <text>ยง 18-128.2 Bryant Park. a. Notwithstanding the provisions of section three hundred eighty-three of the New York city charter and section twenty of the general city law or any other law prohibiting the alienation of park lands, the city, acting by the
    commissioner with the approval of the board of estimate, is hereby authorized and empowered to lease to Bryant Park Restoration Corporation ("BPRC"), a not-for-profit corporation organized under the laws of the state of New York for the purpose of
    assisting the city in restoring and maintaining Bryant Park, for the purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section, upon such terms and conditions and for such duration as shall be agreed upon by the city, The New York Public Library, Astor,
    Lenox and Tilden Foundations ("NYPL") and BPRC, all or part of the tract of land situated in the borough of Manhattan known as the west terrace of the New York Public Library (the "West Terrace"), and more particularly described as follows: ALL THAT
    CERTAIN PLOT, piece or parcel of land, comprising a portion of that land known as Bryant Park, with the buildings and improvements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in the Borough of Manhattan, City and State of New York, bounded and described
    as follows: BEGINNING at a point lying along the south side of West 42nd Street, 482 feet west of the intersection formed by the said south side of West 42nd Street and the west side of Fifth Avenue, and running thence easterly along the south side
    of West 42nd Street 119 feet to a point lying along said southerly side of West 42nd Street; thence southerly, along the rear wall of the New York Public Library Building, 455 feet to the northerly side of West 40th Street; thence westerly along the
    northerly side of West 40th Street 119 feet; thence northerly 455 feet to the point or place of BEGINNING. Notwithstanding the foregoing provision, such grant shall not include any portion of the building erected, constructed, equipped and furnished
    pursuant to chapter five hundred fifty-six of the laws of eighteen hundred ninety-seven (the "NYPL Building"), including appurtenances thereto, except upon the written approval of NYPL. b. The grant referred to in subdivision a of this section may
    authorize BPRC to sublease all or any portion of the West Terrace for the construction of a structure which may be used for the operation of a restaurant and related purposes, and for such other uses as may be consistent with the purposes of BPRC
    and NYPL, upon such terms and conditions, for such duration and for such consideration as shall be agreed upon by the city, BPRC and NYPL; provided, however, that no portion of any such structure shall extend beyond sixty feet west of the western
    most portion of the NYPL Building. It is hereby declared that all of the purposes referred to in this subdivision are for the benefit of the people of the city and are public purposes.</text>
</level>