<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-241</num>
  <heading>Emergency signal devices.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-241 Emergency signal devices. (a) No person shall operate or use or cause to be operated or used any emergency signal device, except on an authorized emergency vehicle when such vehicle is in the act of responding to an emergency; provided that
    such device shall not be operated for a period of time longer than is necessary to respond to such emergency. Notwithstanding the foregoing, such a device on a motor vehicle shall be lawful if designed and used solely as an audible motor vehicle burglar
    alarm in accordance with section 24-238 and a device attached to a vehicle for the purpose of providing an audible warning when the vehicle is backing up shall be permitted even though the audible warning may consist of a gong or bell sound. (b) No
    person shall operate or permit to be operated an emergency signal device installed on an authorized emergency vehicle that when operated at the maximum level creates a sound level in excess of 90 dB(A) when measured at a distance of fifty feet from
    the center of the forward face of such vehicle. Within one year after the effective date of this subdivision and every two years thereafter, emergency signal devices installed on authorized emergency vehicles shall be tested and certification shall
    be submitted, in a form approved by the department, that such devices meet the standard set forth in this subdivision for operation at maximum level. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions, where compliance with the provisions of this subdivision
    would create an undue hardship, the owner or operator of an authorized emergency vehicle may submit a plan to the commissioner for emergency signal devices to meet the standard set forth in this subdivision within two years after the effective date
    of this subdivision. Such plan shall be submitted within one year after the effective date of this subdivision in lieu of the required certification. This subdivision shall not apply to authorized emergency vehicles of the police department, fire
    department or authorized emergency vehicles responding to medical emergencies.</text>
</level>