<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-113</num>
  <heading>Construction generally.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 19-113 Construction generally. Streets of twenty-two feet in width and upward shall have sidewalks on each side thereof. The materials and construction of streets, including the width of the sidewalks thereon, shall fully conform to department specifications
    for such work, all of which shall be prescribed by the commissioner and kept on file in his or her office. * NB Effective until January 1, 2015 * ยง 19-113 Construction generally. a. Streets of twenty-two feet in width and upward shall have sidewalks
    on each side thereof. b. The materials and construction of streets, including the width of the sidewalks thereon, shall fully conform to department specifications for such work, all of which shall be prescribed by the commissioner and kept on file
    in his or her office. c. Department specifications for streets shall include a requirement that asphaltic concrete, other than I-4 mix or other heavy duty asphaltic concrete mix approved by the commissioner, shall contain not less than thirty percent
    reclaimed asphalt pavement, as measured by weight, and I-4 mix or other approved heavy duty asphaltic concrete mix shall contain not less than ten percent reclaimed asphalt pavement, as measured by weight. In setting forth such specifications, the
    department shall make best efforts to encourage the greatest use of reclaimed asphalt pavement possible. This subdivision shall not apply to asphaltic concrete used in a project where the content of asphaltic concrete is governed by a federal or state
    law, rule, regulation, guideline or specification that requires a different composition. The commissioner may waive compliance with this subdivision if the commissioner, after consulting with the commissioner of buildings and the owners or persons
    in charge of all asphalt plants located within the city, finds that a sufficient supply of reclaimed asphalt pavement is not available. * NB Effective January 1, 2015</text>
</level>