<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-344</num>
  <heading>Investigation; matters to be determined; issuance of license; fees; duration of license.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-344 Investigation; matters to be determined; issuance of license; fees; duration of license. a. The commissioner shall make an investigation of the qualifications of each applicant and the merits of each application, with due expedition after the
    filing of the application, and if he or she shall determine that the applicant is duly qualified to be licensed to conduct bingo under this subchapter and article fourteen-H of the general municipal law; that the member or members of the applicant
    designated in the application to conduct bingo are bona fide active members of the applicant and are persons of good moral character and have never been convicted of a crime; that such game is to be conducted in accordance with the provisions of this
    subchapter, article fourteen-H of the general municipal law and in accordance with the rules and regulations of the commission, and that the proceeds thereof are to be disposed of as provided by this subchapter and article fourteen-H of the general
    municipal law, and if the commissioner is satisfied that no commission, salary, compensation, reward or recompense whatever will be paid or given to any person holding, operating or conducting or assisting in the holding, operation and conduct of
    any such games except as in this subchapter or article fourteen-H of the general municipal law otherwise provided; and that no prize will be offered and given in excess of the sum or value of two hundred fifty dollars in any single game and that the
    aggregate of all prizes offered and given in all of such games conducted on a single occasion, under said license shall not exceed the sum or value of one thousand dollars, he or she shall issue a license to the applicant for the conduct of bingo
    upon payment of a license fee of ten dollars for each bingo occasion; provided, however, that he or she shall refuse to issue a license to an applicant seeking to conduct bingo in premises of a licensed commercial lessor where he or she determines
    that the premises presently owned or occupied by said applicant are in every respect adequate and suitable for conducting bingo games. b. Issuance of licenses to commercial lessors. If the commissioner shall determine that the applicant seeking to
    lease a hall or premises for the conduct of bingo to an authorized organization is duly qualified to be licensed under this subchapter and article fourteen-H of the general municipal law; that the applicant satisfies the requirements for an authorized
    commercial lessor as defined in article fourteen-H of the general municipal law; that the schedule of proposed rentals provides a fair and reasonable return on the applicant's investment; that the applicant has filed a schedule of proposed rentals
    in accordance with the rules and regulations of the commission and that the commission has approved such schedule as fair and reasonable and as the maximum rentals the applicant may charge to any authorized organization; that there is no diversion
    of the funds of the proposed lessee from the lawful purposes as defined in article fourteen-H of the general municipal law; and that such leasing of a hall or premises for the conduct of bingo is to be in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter,
    article fourteen-H of the general municipal law and in accordance with the rules and regulations of the commission, he or she shall issue a license permitting the applicant to lease said premises for the conduct of bingo to the authorized organization
    or organizations specified in the application during the period therein specified or such shorter period as he or she shall determine, but not to exceed one year, upon payment of a license fee of ten dollars plus an amount based upon the aggregate
    rent specified in the license and determined in accordance with the schedule set forth therefor in article fourteen-H of the general municipal law. c. On or before the thirtieth day of each month, the commissioner of finance shall transmit to the
    state comptroller a sum equal to fifty percent of all license fees collected by the city pursuant to this section during the preceding calendar month. d. No license shall be issued under this subchapter and article fourteen-H of the general municipal
    law which shall be effective for a period of more than one year.</text>
</level>