<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-706</num>
  <heading>Facility inventory reporting.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-706 Facility inventory reporting. (a) A responsible party of a facility shall file a completed facility inventory form for such facility with the department for each substance on the hazardous substance list or the special health hazard list present
    within a facility that has been present in the preceding calendar year in a quantity which exceeds the threshold reporting quantity established under section 24-703 of this chapter, on or before March first of each year, beginning in nineteen hundred
    eighty-nine. A responsible party of a facility shall also be required to file with the department a facility inventory update, on a form approved by the department through regulation, if a previously unreported hazardous substance is added at a facility
    or if an already reported quantity of a hazardous substance increases by twenty-five percent or more, within thirty days of the occurrence of such event. (b) A responsible party of a facility shall also be required to file a completed material safety
    data sheet for each hazardous substance at the facility with the department and with the fire department on or before March first of each year, beginning in nineteen hundred eighty-nine. (c) A responsible party shall make copies of all information
    filed with the department pursuant to this section available at the facility to emergency response personnel undertaking response measures at such facility. (d) On or before December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-three, the commissioner shall
    by rule establish a schedule of fees that shall be paid upon the filing of the facility inventory form required by this chapter. Such fees shall be based on the amount of hazardous substances present, the number of different hazardous substances present
    and the type of hazardous substances present, including the presence or absence of substances classified as extremely hazardous in rules and regulations promulgated by The United States environmental protection agency pursuant to 42 U.S.C. section
    11001, et seq.</text>
</level>