<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-806</num>
  <heading>First opportunity to purchase.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-806 First opportunity to purchase. (a) A tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, shall notify the owner and the department in writing of its intent to exercise its right of first opportunity to purchase within sixty days from
    receipt of notice from the owner pursuant to subdivision a of section 26-802 of this chapter. (b) The tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, following notice by the owner in compliance with subdivision a of section 26-802 of this
    chapter, shall have one hundred twenty days from the date of the notice of the determination of the appraised value to submit its offer to purchase. (c) If through no fault of a tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, or the owner,
    the time period provided for in subdivision b of this section needs to be extended, then such time period may be extended by the department. Should such time period be extended past the notice period provided for in subdivision a of section 26-802
    of this chapter, then the provisions of the applicable assisted rentalhousing program shall remain in full force and effect to the extent permitted by law. (d) Except where the owner and a tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity,
    agree to a purchase price of the assisted rental housing at an amount below the appraised value, any offer made pursuant to this section shall be accepted by the owner. (e) If a tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, does not submit
    its offer in writing to the owner and the department within the time periods stated in subdivision b of this section following notice by the owner in compliance with subdivision a of section 26-802 of this chapter, then such right will be deemed waived
    and the owner shall have no further obligations under this section. However, where a tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, has previously submitted a notice in accordance with subdivision a of this section decides not to exercise
    such right, it may withdraw such notice by giving written notice to that effect to the owner and to the department.</text>
</level>