<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-708</num>
  <heading>Criminal and civil penalties; enforcement.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-708 Criminal and civil penalties; enforcement. a. Except as otherwise provided in subdivision b of this section, any person who knowingly violates or assists in the violation of any section of this chapter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon
    conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred nor more than one thousand dollars. Except as otherwise provided in subdivision b of this section, any person who violates or assists in the violation of any section of this
    chapter shall be subject to a civil penalty of one hundred dollars per day per unit for each day that a building is not in compliance with the provisions of such sections; provided, however, that such civil penalty shall not exceed one thousand dollars
    per unit. b. Any person who knowingly violates or assists in the violation of section 26-703 of this chapter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine not more than two times the amount required to be
    reserved by section 26-703 of this chapter which was not so reserved. Any person who violates or assists in the violation of section 26-703 of this chapter shall also be subject to a civil penalty of one thousand dollars per day for each day that
    the reserve fund required by section 26-703 of this chapter is not established; provided, however, that such civil penalty shall not exceed the amount required to be reserved pursuant to section 26-703 of this chapter. c. In addition, any other action
    or proceeding in any court of competent jurisdiction that may be appropriate or necessary for the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter may be brought in the name of the city, including actions to secure permanent injunctions enjoining any
    acts or practices which constitute a violation of any provision of this chapter, mandating compliance with the provisions of this chapter or for such other relief as may be appropriate. In any such action or proceeding the city may apply to any court
    of competent jurisdiction, or to a judge or justice thereof, for a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction enjoining and restraining all persons from violating any provision of this chapter, mandating compliance with the provisions of
    this chapter, or for such other relief as may be appropriate, until the hearing and determination of such action or proceeding and the entry of final judgment or order therein. The court, or judge or justice thereof, to whom such application is made,
    is hereby authorized forthwith to make any or all of the orders above specified, as may be required in such application, with or without notice, and to make such other or further orders or directions as may be necessary to render the same effectual.
    No undertaking shall be required as a condition of the granting or issuing of such order, or by reason thereof. d. Nothing contained in this section shall impair any rights, remedies or causes of action accrued or accruing to purchasers of cooperative
    shares or condominium units. e. The department of housing preservation and development is empowered to enforce the provisions of this chapter.</text>
</level>