<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2065</num>
  <heading>Light and ventilation of water closet compartments.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2065 Light and ventilation of water closet compartments. a. In every water closet compartment, bathroom and general toilet room one of the following requirements for light and ventilation shall be met: (1) There shall be a window opening upon a
    street, yard, court, partially enclosed balcony or space above a setback, on an offset or recess which may be less than six feet in width. Every such window shall be at least three square feet in area and one-half of its area shall open. (2) If the
    water closet compartment, bathroom or general toilet room is either located on the top story or is underneath the bottom of a lawful shaft or court, it may be lighted and ventilated by a skylight in the roof. Such skylight shall contain three square
    feet of glazed area and shall open. (3) There shall be a system of mechanical ventilation, approved for construction and arrangement by the department. In a multiple dwelling such system of ventilation shall be maintained and operated continuously
    to provide at least four changes per hour of the air volume of each water closet, bathroom or general toilet room daily from six o'clock in the morning until midnight in all residential parts of a dwelling and from seven o'clock in the morning until
    seven o'clock at night in any nonresidental parts of a dwelling. In a private dwelling the approved system of mechanical ventilation may be switch-operated. b. Nothing in this section shall require any change to be made in the lighting or ventilation
    of water closets, bathrooms, or general toilet rooms in any portion of any old law tenement or any converted dwelling if such lighting or ventilation was lawful on July first, nineteen hundred sixty-one and in one or two family dwellings if such lighting
    or ventilation was lawful on August second, nineteen hundred sixty-seven.</text>
</level>