<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-373</num>
  <heading>Horizontal exits.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-373 Horizontal exits. A horizontal exit to an area of refuge may consist of doors through walls or partitions having at least a two hour fire-resistance rating; of a balcony or exterior vestibule leading around the end of a fire division to another
    fire area or building; or it may be a bridge or tunnel between two buildings. Horizontal exits shall comply with the following: (a) Capacity. The capacity of horizontal exits shall be as listed in table 6-1. Only the widths of doors swinging in the
    direction of exit travel to the area of refuge shall be counted. (b) Door requirements. Doors shall be swinging, self-closing doors having a fire protection rating of one and one-half hours, except that door in fire divisions having a three hour or
    four hour fire-resistance rating shall have opening protective as required by table 5-3. Each swinging door shall swing in the direction of exit travel, and when travel is in both directions, as when two areas of refuge serve as areas of refuge for
    each other, at least two door openings shall be provided, the doors of which shall swing in opposite directions. Signs shall be placed over each door on the side from which egress is made, indicating the exit door. (c) Balconies, bridges and tunnels.
    When serving as horizontal exits, balconies, bridges, and tunnels shall comply with the following: (1) Their width shall be equal to at least the width of the doors opening on them, but in no case less than three feet eight inches. (2) They shall
    be enclosed at each end by doors complying with subdivision (b) of this section. (3) The floor level at doors shall be the same as that of the building except that the floor level of open balconies or open bridges shall be approximately seven and
    one-half inches lower. (4) Where there is a difference in level between the areas connected, the floors of the horizontal exit shall be ramped not more than one inch in ten inches. (5) Exterior wall openings within thirty feet horizontally of any
    open bridge or balcony or below any open bridge or balcony shall be provided with opening protectives having a three-quarter hour fire protection rating. (6) Balconies shall not face or open on yards or courts less than twelve feet wide, and shall
    be constructed as required for exterior corridors. (7) Exterior bridges shall be constructed of noncombustible materials. Interior bridges or tunnels shall be constructed of materials providing a two hour fire-resistance rating.</text>
</level>