<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-601</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-601 Definitions. As used in this section. a. "Commissioner" means the commissioner of housing and community renewal of the state of New York. b. "Dwelling unit" means that part of a dwelling in which an eligible head of the household resides and
    which is subject to the provisions of either article II, IV, V, or XI of the private housing finance law, or that part of a dwelling which was or continues to be subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government pursuant
    to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended, in which an eligible head of the household resides. c. "Eligibility date" means the later of (1) January first, nineteen hundred seventy-five, or (2) the last day of the month
    in which a person became an eligible head of a household in the dwelling unit in which such person resides at the time of filing the most recent application for benefits hereunder, or in the case of a dwelling subject to a mortgage insured or initially
    insured by the federal government pursuant to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended, "eligibility date" means the later of (1) July first, nineteen hundred seventy-seven, or (2) the last day of the month in which a person
    became an eligible head of a household in the dwelling unit in which such person resides at the time of filing the most recent application for benefits hereunder. d. "Eligible head of the household" means a person or his or her spouse who is sixty-two
    years of age or older or who qualifies as a person with a disability pursuant to section 26-617 of this chapter and is entitled to the possession or to the use and occupancy of a dwelling unit, provided, however, that with respect to a dwelling which
    was subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government pursuant to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended, "eligible head of the household" shall be limited to that person or his or her spouse
    who was entitled to possession or the use and occupancy of such dwelling unit at the time of termination of such mortgage, and whose income when combined with the income of all other members of the household whose head of household is sixty-two years
    of age or older does not exceed twenty-five thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand five, twenty-six thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand six, twenty-seven thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand seven, twenty-eight
    thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand eight, and twenty-nine thousand dollars beginning July first, two thousand nine, for the taxable period, or whose income for the current income tax year when combined with the income of all members
    of the household residing in the housing accommodation whose head of the household is a person with a disability does not exceed the maximum income above which such head of the household would not be eligible to receive cash supplemental security
    income benefits under federal law during such tax year. e. "Housing company" means any limited-profit housing company, limited dividend housing company, redevelopment company or housing development fund company incorporated pursuant to the private
    housing finance law and operated exclusively for the benefit of persons or families of low income, or any corporate owner of a dwelling which is or was subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government pursuant to section
    two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended. f. "Income" means income received by the eligible head of the household combined with the income of all other members of the household from all sources after deduction of all income and
    social security taxes and includes without limitation, social security and retirement benefits, supplemental security income and additional state payments, public assistance benefits, interest, dividends, net rental income, salary and earnings, and
    net income from self-employment, but shall not include gifts or inheritances, payments made to individuals because of their status as victims of Nazi persecution, as defined in P.L. 103-286, or increases in benefits accorded pursuant to the social
    security act or a public or private pension paid to any member of the household which increase, in any given year, does not exceed the consumer price index (all items United States city average) for such year which take effect after the eligibility
    date of an eligible head of the household receiving benefits hereunder, whether received by the eligible head of the household or any other member of the household. When the eligible head of a household has retired on or after the commencement of
    the taxable period and prior to the date of making an application for a rent increase exemption order/tax abatement certificate pursuant to this chapter, such person's income shall be adjusted by excluding salary or earnings and projecting such person's
    retirement income over the entire taxable period. g. "Income tax year" means a twelve month period for which the head of the household filed a federal personal income tax return, or if no such return is filed, the calendar year. h. "Increase in maximum
    rent" means any increase in the maximum rent for the dwelling unit becoming effective on or after the eligibility date, including capital assessments and voluntary capital contributions but excluding any increase in maximum rent attributable to gas
    or electrical utility charges or an increase in dwelling space, services or equipment, provided, however, that with respect to any dwelling unit in a dwelling which is or was subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government
    pursuant to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended, "increase in maximum rent" shall not include any increase in maximum rent attributable to capital assessments or voluntary capital contributions. i. "Maximum rent" means
    the maximum rent, excluding gas and electric utility charges, which has been authorized or approved by the commissioner or the supervising agency or the legal regulated rent established for the dwelling unit pursuant to the provisions of either article
    II, IV, V or XI of the private housing finance law, or the rental established for a cooperatively owned dwelling unit previously regulated pursuant to the provisions of article II, IV, V or XI of the private housing finance law, or the rental established
    for a dwelling unit, in a dwelling subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government pursuant to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended or such rent established for a dwelling unit which was
    subject to a mortgage insured or initially insured by the federal government pursuant to section two hundred thirteen of the national housing act, as amended. j. "Members of the household" means the head of the household and any person, permanently
    residing in the dwelling unit. k. "Supervising agency" means the department of housing preservation and development. l. "Taxable period" means the income tax year immediately preceding the date of making application for a rent increase exemption order/tax
    abatement certificate.</text>
</level>