<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-292.10</num>
  <heading>Usable spaces.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-292.10 Usable spaces.--(a) Functional spaces and rooms. (1) Except as otherwise provided in section 27-292.5, spaces and rooms intended for general public and occupant use shall be accessible and usable. Such spaces and rooms include but are not
    necessarily limited to the following: Mercantile spaces Industrial spaces Business spaces Assembly spaces Educational spaces Institutional spaces Toilet rooms Bathrooms, bathing facilities, shower rooms. (2) Doors and floor surfaces in usable spaces
    shall comply with the requirements set forth in reference standard RS 4-6. (3) Where seating, tables and/or work stations are provided in usable spaces, at least one and not less than five percent shall comply with the requirements set forth in reference
    standard RS 4-6. (b) Toilet rooms.--(1) The location and number of water closets, urinals and lavatories shall be provided in accordance with the requirements set forth in table RS 16-5. (2) Except where exempted in subdivision (i) of section 27-292.5
    or section 27-292.6, facilities for people having physical disabilities shall be provided in toilet rooms or in a readily accessible location. Where such toilet room is designed for use by not more than one person at a time and has provision for locking
    from the inside, such toilet room shall be permitted to be used by either sex. (3) Where toilet rooms are not accessible by elevator, they shall be located so that people having physical disabilities need not travel more than one story thereto by
    ramp. (c) Bathing facilities.--(1) The location and number of plumbing fixtures shall be provided in accordance with the requirements set forth in table RS 16-5 and in reference standard RS 4-6. (2) Each required bathing facility shall be accessible
    and at least one of each type of fixture or accessory that is provided in such bathing facility shall comply with the requirements set forth in table RS 16-4 and in reference standard RS 4-6.</text>
</level>