<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-228.5</num>
  <heading>General requirements.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-228.5 General requirements. (a) Owners of all existing buildings which are required to comply with the provisions of subdivision (a) of section 27-353.1 (elevator vestibules), section 27-381 and subdivision (b) of section 27-382 (exit lighting),
    subdivision (b) of section 27-384 (exit signs), section 27-396.3 (signs in sleeping rooms), section 27-777.2 (ventilation in J-1 buildings), subdivision (b) of section 27-929 (sprinklers, fire alarm systems, fire command and communication systems),
    paragraph two of subdivision (c) of section 27-989 (elevators in readiness), section 27-996.1 (locks on hoistway doors) and section 27-996.2 (firemen's service) shall file with the department a report on or before April first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven
    certifying to the installation of the required fire protection systems in accordance with approved plans and appropriate permits prior to such date. Owners of all existing buildings not already subject to the requirements of article nine of subchapter
    six of this chapter as of January eighth, nineteen hundred seventy-three shall file with the department a report on or before October first, nineteen hundred eighty-five certifying to the installation of stair and elevator signs meeting the requirements
    of article nine of subchapter six of this chapter prior to such date. Owners of all existing buildings that are required to comply with the provisions of subdivision (c) of section 27-384 (power source of exit signs) shall file with the department,
    on or before July 1, 2007, a report of an architect or engineer certifying that all required exit and/or directional signs are connected to an emergency power source or to storage battery equipment in compliance with such subdivision except that no
    such report shall be required to be filed if an owner of a building submits an affidavit to the department, within ninety days after the effective date of this sentence, certifying that all required exit and/or directional signs are connected to an
    emergency power source or to storage battery equipment as required by such subdivision. Such reports shall be on such forms and in such manner as prescribed by the commissioner. Failure to file such report by such dates shall be a violation of this
    section, which shall be punishable pursuant to section 26-125 of title twenty-six of the administrative code. (b)(1) Owners of all buildings one hundred feet or more in height required to comply with the provisions of subdivision (a) of section 27-929.1
    (sprinklers) shall file with the department on or before July 1, 2019 a final report prepared by an architect or engineer certifying to the installation of the required sprinklers in accordance with such provisions and, pending the filing of such
    final report, such owner shall be required to file the following interim reports as described below. Failure to file such final report and/or, where required, such interim reports by the dates indicated or within any extended period of time granted
    by the commissioner pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subdivision shall be a violation of this section, which shall be punishable pursuant to section 26-125 of the code. Such reports shall be on such forms and in such manner as prescribed by the commissioner
    and shall be filed as follows: Unless a final report is filed The one year report shall contain an on or prior to such date, a affidavit by the owner of the one year report shall be filed building acknowledging that no later than July 1, 2005. sprinklers
    are required to be installed in such building on or before July 1, 2019 in compliance with subdivision (a) indicating his or her intention to section 27-929.1 of this code acomply with such requirement. Unless a final report is filed Such seven year
    report shall contain on or prior to July 1, 2011, a a certification by an architect or seven year report shall be engineer of the percentage of the filed no earlier than January building in which sprinklers have 1, 2011 and no later than July been
    installed as of the date of such 1, 2011. report and an implementation plan prepared by such architect or engineer detailing when and how the remaining portions of the building will be made fully compliant. Unless a final report is filed Such fourteen
    year report shall on or prior to July 1, 2018, a contain a certification by an fourteen year report shall be architect or engineer of the filed no earlier than January percentage of the building in which 1, 2018 and no later than July sprinklers have
    been installed as of 1, 2018. the date of such report and an implementation plan, prepared by such architect or engineer detailing when and how the remaining portions of the building will be made fully compliant. Except as otherwise provided Such
    final report shall contain a in paragraph (2) of this certification by an architect or subdivision, a final report engineer that the building is fully shall be filed no later than compliant. July 1, 2019. (2) Where the owner of a building is unable
    to comply with the requirements of subdivision (a) of section 27-929.1 on or before July 1, 2019 because of undue hardship, and where such owner timely filed all interim reports as required in paragraph (1) of this subdivision and has obtained approval
    of all required applications, plans and permits relating to the required work, such owner may submit to the department an application for additional time to comply with such requirements. Such application shall be submitted to the department on or
    before July 1, 2018, along with supporting documents indicating the basis for such claim of undue hardship. The commissioner shall appoint a committee consisting of employees of the department and the fire department and a representative of the real
    estate industry to review such application. Such committee shall issue findings and recommendations relating to the application. After reviewing such findings and recommendations, if the commissioner finds that the owner has made a good faith effort
    to complete the required work and has substantiated his or her claim of undue hardship, the commissioner may grant an extension of time in which to complete the work and submit the final report.</text>
</level>