<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-415</num>
  <heading>Laboratories.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-415 Laboratories. All laboratories required to register under the requirements of the New York city health code shall comply with the following: (a) Construction. All buildings in which such laboratories occur shall be of noncombustible group I
    construction. (b) Floors. All floors shall comply with the fire-resistance requirements for the class of construction, and provide the degree of radioactive resistance required by applicable city, state, and federal regulations. A finished material
    shall be applied to provide a continuous nonporous surface which may be readily removed. (c) Interior finish. All insulation of acoustical treatments and interior partitions shall be of noncombustible material. Walls and ceilings shall have nonporous
    finishes of class A rating. (d) Sprinkler protection. Automatic sprinkler protection complying with the construction provisions of subchapter seventeen of this chapter shall be provided, and such protection shall be designed for the type of combustible
    materials wherever such material is used, and for the radioactive material that may be expected to melt, vaporize, or oxidize under fire conditions. Laboratory equipment susceptible to damage from water or other materials used in the sprinkler system
    may be shielded by hoods except when the equipment provides a source of combustion. Where sprinkler protection uses water, or small water-spray installations are used to fight small isolated fires, floors shall be provided with drainage so that water
    may be carried to retention tanks for later disposal as required by the New York city health code when contamination of the water is to be anticipated. (e) Electrical controls. Electrical controls and equipment shall be installed in accordance with
    the requirements of the electrical code of the city of New York. (f) Ventilation. Exhaust air from areas in which radioactive materials are used or stored shall be exhausted to the outdoors in such manner as not to create a health hazard, and shall
    not be recirculated to other areas of the building. Air pressure in rooms in which radioactive materials are used or stored shall be maintained below the the air pressure of adjoining rooms, so that there is no flow of radioactive gases or dusts into
    adjoining rooms. (1) Ducts shall be of sheet steel of not less than No. 16 manufacturers' standard gauge or of other equivalent noncombustible material having a melting point above eighteen hundred degrees Fahrenheit. Exhaust ducts within the building,
    on the discharge side of the fan, shall be welded airtight. Exhaust ducts within the building, on the suction side of the fan shall have laps in the direction of air flow with smoke-tight joints, and shall be subjected to a smoke test in accordance
    with the requirements for chimneys in subchapter fifteen of this chapter. Access hatches with tight-closing covers shall be provided for cleaning and for fire-fighting in the exhaust system ducts. (2) Fume hoods shall be exhausted to the outdoors.
    Controls for hood fans shall be interlocked so that contaminated air cannot be drawn into any space from a hood where the exhaust fan is not in operation. (3) Fan equipment other than the impeller and impeller housing shall be located outside the
    exhaust stream. (4) When the degree of contamination of the exhaust stream exceeds the concentration limits permitted by the health code, the duct system shall be equipped with devices to decontaminate the air to a safe level before discharging to
    the outdoor air. (g) Plumbing. Drainage lines from sinks used for radioactive wastes shall be without traps, and shall lead to retention tanks when required by the provisions of the New York city health code.</text>
</level>