<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-292.5</num>
  <heading>Accessibility.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-292.5 Accessibility.--(a) Primary entrance(s).--The primary entrance(s) for buildings shall be accessible, except for buildings classified in occupancy group A, J-3 and/or other spaces which normally are not frequented by the public or employees
    of the facility. (b) Exterior accessible route.--Except as provided in this subarticle, buildings shall be provided with an exterior accessible route to permit entry at the primary entrance(s) of the building from the following locations: (1) Public
    street or sidewalk (2) Driveways (3) Parking areas (4) Passenger loading zones (5) Transportation stops (c) Interior accessible route.--Except as provided in this subarticle, in buildings having (an) interior route(s) to one or more of the following
    spaces or facilities, such route(s) shall be (an) interior accessible route(s) from the entrance(s) usable by all categories of people having physical disabilities to adaptable or usable dwelling units and other spaces and facilities on the same premises
    including but not limited to: (1) Laundry rooms (2) Refuse disposal locations (3) Mailbox areas (4) Recreational, assembly and tenants' meeting rooms (5) Storage rooms (6) Management offices (7) Stores (8) Dining areas (9) Parking areas Where the
    only route to one or more of such spaces or facilities is an exterior route, such route shall be accessible. (d) Path of travel.--The path of travel in exterior and interior accessible routes shall provide unobstructed safe access and applicable items
    in such path of travel shall comply with the requirements set forth in reference standard RS 4-6. (e) Elevators.--Where provided, all elevators shall comply with subchapter eighteen, reference standard RS 18-1, where an interior accessible route is
    required. (f) Assembly occupancies.--For assembly occupancies having a mezzanine or balcony which provides a similar view as that from the main floor, accessibility to the mezzanine or balcony shall not be required provided toilet rooms are on the
    main floor. (g) Restaurants--For restaurants, dining rooms and similar occupancies having the same services on levels other than the main floor, accessibility to such levels shall not be required provided that toilet rooms are on the main floor. (h)
    Storage.--For buildings in which the intended use is the storage of goods or merchandise, the only requirement shall be accessibility at the primary entrance and an interior accessible route to offices where business may be conducted. (i) Non-grade
    stories of small non-residential buildings.--The following non-residential buildings or parts thereof are exempt from the provisions of this subarticle concerning requirements for people having physical disabilities, to the extent set forth in subdivisions
    (1) and (2) of this subsection: (1) construction of such new buildings the total floor area of which is two thousand five hundred square feet or less; (2) alterations to such building already existing where the alterations are being made to an above-grade
    story having a total floor area of two thousand five hundred square feet or less or to a below-grade story having a total floor area of two thousand square feet or less. Notwithstanding the foregoing, floor areas frequented by the public for assembly,
    governmental, public utility or health facility purposes shall not be exempted unless equivalent functional accessible facilities are provided on the first story. (j) Where the floor area is more than two thousand five hundred square feet but less
    than five thousand square feet, a vertical wheelchair lift enclosed in construction having the required fire-resistance rating and connecting not more than two contiguous levels is permitted in lieu of an accessible route as set forth in reference
    standard RS 4-6. (k) Where the below-grade cumulative floor area is more than two thousand square feet but not more than five thousand square feet, a vertical wheelchair lift enclosed in construction having the required fire-resistance rating and
    connecting not more than two contiguous levels is permitted in lieu of an accessible route as set forth in reference standard RS 4-6.</text>
</level>