<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-971</num>
  <heading>Classification and general requirements of fire alarm systems.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-971 Classification and general requirements of fire alarm systems. Fire alarms shall be classified as follows and shall meet the following general requirements: (a) Uncoded closed circuit fire alarm system. Consisting of manually operated sending
    stations and audible signaling devices, so arranged that the operation of any station will automatically sound continuously the signaling devices throughout all portions of the building. (b) Master coded closed circuit fire alarm systems. Consisting
    of manually operated pull-lever type sending stations and audible signaling devices, so arranged that the operation of any station will automatically sound the signaling devices giving a common code of signals throughout all portions of the building.
    The code shall consist of four rounds of a series of single strokes of the signaling devices, each round consisting of "3-3-3-3". (c) Individually coded closed circuit general fire alarm systems. Consisting of manually operated pull-lever type sending
    stations and audible signaling devices, so arranged that the operation of any station will automatically sound the signaling devices, throughout all portions of the building, for a minimum of four rounds of a distinctive code of signals particular
    to the station at which the signal has been initiated. The code numbers that are used shall be subject to the approval of the fire commissioner. (d) Individually coded closed circuit presignal fire alarm systems. Consisting of manually operated pull-lever
    type sending stations and signal devices so arranged that the operation of any station will cause the sound of only the signal devices located in the engine room and basement and other places in the building where the members of a fire brigade work
    or assemble. The signaling device shall give four rounds of the particular code signal of the station at which the signal has been initiated. Approved equipment shall be provided at each station so that the operation of any station performed with
    the aid of a key or plug will sound all of the signal devices located in the building with four rounds of the particular coded signal of the station initiated. The code numbers used shall be subject to the approval of the fire commissioner. The presignal
    key or plug shall be so designed that it can be readily identified. Presignal type systems will not generally be approved; however, approval may be obtained from the fire commissioner where special type occupancies may warrant such a system. (e) Combination
    unit or zone, and general alarm coded closed circuit fire alarm systems. Consisting of manually operated pull-lever type sending stations and signal devices so arranged that the operation of any station will cause all of the signaling devices in that
    unit or zone to sound four rounds of the particular coded signal of the station initiated, and simultaneously will cause all of the signaling devices on the general alarm circuit to sound four rounds of the coded signal designating the unit or zone
    in which the station is located. An approved register and time stamp may be used in connection with this system when approved by the fire commissioner. The register, if of the closed circuit type, shall be operated from a separate closed circuit control
    board or panel isolated by a barrier from the main control panel in the main fire alarm control cabinet. An approved closed circuit unit annunciator with trouble alarm circuit shall be installed as part of this system when required by the fire commissioner.
    (f) Special systems. Consisting of the above systems as required, supplemented by special circuits for the operation of other fire alarm or detection devices in the systems, or electric control systems for stopping machinery, closing doors or ventilators,
    or shutting down fans as may be required by the commissioner or the code, or to call the central station of a private operating company of the fire department. Automatic fire detecting systems may be connected to operate an interior fire alarm system
    when connected thereto by an approved coded transmitter. In no case shall the transmitter be considered to replace the standard approved interior fire alarm station, except where a transmitter has been approved for both purposes. The special control
    circuits and devices shall be separate and distinct from the fire alarm system but shall be brought into action whenever the fire alarm system is set in operation. (g) Class E system.--Consisting of a class E fire alarm signal system as described
    in subdivision (f) of section 27-972 of article five of this subchapter and reference standard RS17-3A. Such systems shall be exempt from the provisions of section 27-973 of article five of this subchapter, except that compliance with paragraph two
    of subdivision (a) and subdivision (e) of such section shall be required. (h) Modified class E system.--Consisting of a modified class E fire alarm signal system as described in subdivision (g) of section 27-972 of article five of this subchapter
    and reference standard RS17-3B. Such systems shall be exempt from the provisions of section 27-973 of article five of this subchapter, except that compliance with paragraph two of subdivision (a) and subdivision (e) of such section shall be required.
    (i) Class C system.--Consisting of a class C fire alarm signal system as described in subdivision (k) of section 27-972 and reference standard RS 17-3A. Such systems shall be exempt from the provisions of section 27-973 of article five of this subchapter,
    except that compliance with paragraph two of subdivision (a) and subdivision (e) of such section shall be required. (j) Class J system.--Consisting of a class J fire alarm signal system as described in subdivision (l) of section 27-972 of article
    five of this subchapter and reference standard RS 17-3A. Such systems shall be exempt from the provisions of section 27-973 of article five of this subchapter, except that compliance with paragraph two of subdivision (a) and subdivision (e) of such
    section shall be required. (k) Modified class J system.--Consisting of a modified class J fire alarm signal system as described in subdivision (m) of section 27-972 of article five of this subchapter and reference standard RS 17-3B. Such systems shall
    be exempt from the provisions of section 27-973 of article five of this subchapter, except that compliance with paragraph two of subdivision (a) and subdivision (e) of such section shall be required. (l) Modified class J-1 system.--Consisting of a
    modified class J-1 fire alarm signal system as described in paragraph two of subdivision (j) of section 27-972 of article five of this subchapter.</text>
</level>