<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-358</num>
  <heading>Occupant load.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-358 Occupant load. The number of occupants for whom exit facilities shall be provided shall be established either (1) by the actual number of occupants for whom each occupied space, floor, or building, as the case may be, is designed, or (2) by
    using the appropriate occupant-area ratios from table 6-2, whichever is larger. The occupant load of any space shall include the occupant load of all spaces that discharge through it in order to gain access to an exit. Table 6-2 Occupant Load Requirements
    Net Area Table ======================================================================== Net Floor Area per Occupant Occupancy (sq. ft.) ------------------------------------------------------------------------ Billiard rooms....................................
    50 Bowling alleys.................................... 50 Classrooms........................................ 20 Dance floors...................................... 10 Dining spaces (nonresidential).................... 12 Exhibition spaces.................................
    10 Garages and open parking structures............... 250 Gymnasiums........................................ 15 Habitable rooms................................... 140 Industrial shops.................................. 200 In schools................................
    30 Institutional sleeping rooms Adults.................................... 75 Children (except as listed below)......... 50 Day Care a. under 6 mos........................... 50 b. 6 mos. - 2 yrs........................ 40 c. 2 yrs. - 6 yrs........................
    30 Institutional staff, all.................. 30 Kindergartens..................................... 35 Kitchens (nonresidential)......................... 200 Laboratories...................................... 50 Preparation rooms.........................
    100 Libraries......................................... 25 Locker rooms...................................... 12 Offices........................................... 100 Passenger terminals or platforms.................. 1.5xC Sales areas (retail) 1st
    floor or basement..................... 25 All other floors.......................... 50 Seating areas (audience) in all places of assembly Fixed seats............................... D Moveable seats............................ 10 Skating rinks.....................................
    15 Stages (See subchapter eight) Standing room (audience) in all places of assembly........................................ 4 Storage rooms..................................... 200 ========================================================================
    Notes: C--capacity of all passenger vehicles that can be unloaded simulta- neously. D--designed number of seats or occupants. (a) Unlisted occupancies. Where data regarding the sq. ft. per person for an occupancy is not listed in table 6-2, the occupant
    load shall be established by an architect or engineer, subject to the approval of the commissioner. (b) Modifications. (1) When the actual occupant load of any space will be significantly lower than that listed in table 6-2, the commissioner may establish
    a lower basis for the determination of the occupant load. (2) When a building existing on December sixth, nineteen hundred sixty-eight is altered or changed in occupancy or use so as to require enlarged exit facilities, the commissioner may authorize
    the alteration or change in occupancy or use without an enlargement of exit facilities, provided the occupant load is limited to that accommodated by the existing exit facilities as determined by the provisions of this code, and the building or space
    is posted accordingly with a sign. Such signs shall be at least twelve inches in width and sixteen inches in height. The lettering shall be red on a white background. The letters shall be not less than one inch high and the numerals not less than
    one and one-quarter inches high. (c) Nonsimultaneous occupancy. The occupant load of toilets, locker rooms, meeting rooms, storage rooms, employee cafeterias, and similar rooms or spaces that are not occupied at the same time as other rooms or spaces
    on the same floor of a building, may be omitted from the occupant load calculation of the floor on which they are located to the extent that such spaces serve occupied rooms on the same floor.</text>
</level>