<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-104</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-104 Definitions. When used in the New York city air pollution control code: (1) Air contaminant means any particulate matter or any gas or any combination thereof in the open air, other than uncombined water or air. (2) Air contaminant detector
    means a device or combination of devices which cause audible and/or visible signals in the presence of an air contaminant of a particular concentration, density or opacity. (3) Air contaminant recorder means an apparatus which produces a record of
    the time, duration, concentration and density or opacity of an air contaminant. (4) Alteration means any modification or change of the design, capacity, process or arrangement, or any increase in the connected load of equipment or apparatus which
    will affect the kind or amount of air contaminant emitted. Alteration does not include replacement or repair of wornout or defective equipment. (5) Anthracite coal means the current definition of anthracite coal as classified by the American society
    for testing and materials. (6) Apparatus means any device which prevents, controls, detects, or records the emission of any air contaminant. (7) Bituminous coal means the current definition of bituminous coal and subbituminous coal as classifed by
    the American society for testing and materials. (8) Board means the environmental control board of the city of New York. (9) Boiler means equipment which is used to heat water for the purpose of generating hot water and/or steam. (10) Btu input means
    the quantity of heat generated by a fuel fed into a furnace under conditions of complete combustion, measured in British thermal units. Btu input includes sensible heat, calculated above sixty degrees F., available from materials introduced into the
    combustion zone. (11) Capacity rating means the fuel burning equipment manufacturer's guaranteed maximum Btu input rating in millions of Btu per hour, or the maximum four-hour average actual rate, whichever is higher. (12) Certificate means an operating,
    sulfur exemption, temporary operating, or temporary sulfur exemption certificate. (13) Charter means the New York city charter, including all of its amendments. (14) City means the city of New York. (15) Combustion controller means an apparatus which
    automatically continually maintains the proper fuel to air ratio for the optimum combustion of fuel. (16) Combustion shutoff means an apparatus which is designed to halt automatically a combustion process when proper combustion conditions are not
    being maintained. (17) Commissioner means commissioner of environmental protection. (18) Control apparatus means any device which prevents or controls the emission of any air contaminant. (19) Department means department of environmental protection.
    (20) Dust means solid particulate matter which has been released into the open air by natural forces or by mechanical processes. (21) Emission means dispersion of an air contaminant into the open air of the city. (22) Emission rate potential means
    the rate in pounds per hour at which air contaminant would be emitted to the open air in the absence of air pollution control facilities or other control measures. The emission rate potential for cyclic operations shall be determined by considering
    both the instantaneous emission potential and the total emission potential over the time period of the cycle. (23) Emission source means a point at which an emission occurs. (24) Environmental rating means a rating indicated by the letters A, B, C
    or D in table 1, section 24-153 of the code. (25) Equipment means any device capable of causing the emission of an air contaminant into the open air, or any stack, conduit, flue, duct, vent or similar device connected or attached to, or serving such
    device. * (26) Equipment used in a process means equipment (except refuse burning equipment or fuel burning equipment) used in any industrial, commercial, agricultural or other activity, or in any operation, manufacture or treatment in which chemical,
    biological or physical properties of materials are changed. * NB Amended L.L. 49/85 ยง 1, language juxtaposed per Ch. 907/85 ยง 14 (27) Excess air means the quantity of air which exceeds the theoretical quantity of air required for complete combustion.
    (28) Exhaust and ventilation source means a system which removes and transports air contaminant to the exterior of a building or other structure. (29) Fuel burning equipment means equipment, other than a motor vehicle, designed to burn fuel. (30)
    Installation means the placement, assemblage or construction of equipment or apparatus at the premises where the equipment or apparatus will be used, and includes all preparatory work at such premises. (31) Major deficiency means a defect in the design
    and/or installation that may cause the equipment to generate unnecessary air pollution. (32) Minor deficiency means a defect in the design and/or installation that does not accomplish or provide the monitoring or maintenance capability required by
    the permit issued to install or alter the equipment. (33) Motor vehicle means equipment which is propelled by an engine in or upon which a person or material may be transported on the ground. (34) Odorous air contaminant means any air contaminant
    which is released in sufficient concentrations to be detected by the human olfactory sense. (35) Open air means all the air available for human, animal, or plant respiration, but shall not include the air in equipment and private dwellings. (36) Open
    fire means any fire wherein the products of combustion are emitted directly into open air and are not directed thereto through a stack, conduit, flue, duct, vent or similar device. (37) Owner means and includes the owner of the freehold of the premises
    or lesser estate therein or mortgagee thereof, a lessee or an agent of any of the above persons, a lessee of the equipment or his or her agent, a tenant, operator, or any other person who has regular control of equipment or apparatus. (38) Particulate
    matter means any liquid, other than water, or any solid which is or tends to be capable of becoming windblown or being suspended in air, or other gas or vapor which becomes a solid or liquid at standard conditions of thirty-two degrees F. and 14.7
    psia. Particular matter measured on a dry basis shall be comprised of all materials collected at two hundred fifty degrees F. on and prior to the dry filter medium which achieves an efficiency greater than 99.9 per cent for particles 0.3 microns in
    diameter based on dioctyl phthalate smoke. (39) Permissible emission rates means the maximum rate in lbs. hr. at which air contaminant may be emitted to the open air. (40) Permit means an installation or alteration permit. (41) Person means individual
    or partnership, company, corporation, association, firm, organization, governmental agency, administration or department, or any other group of individuals, or any officer or employee thereof. (42) Portable equipment means equipment designed to be
    transported from place to place for temporary operation, other than a motor vehicle, or lawn mower, snowblower or other similar domestic, non-commercial equipment. (43) Process weight means total weight of the materials including solid fuels introduced
    into any specific process but excluding liquid and gaseous fuels and combustion air. (44) Process weight per hour means process weight divided by the number of hours from the beginning of any specific process to the completion of the process, excluding
    any time during which the equipment used in the process is idle. (45) Professional certification means certification by a professional engineer or registered architect who is licensed to practice engineering or architecture under section seven thousand
    two hundred two or seven thousand three hundred two of the education law. (46) Refuse burning equipment means equipment designed to burn waste material, garbage and refuse. (47) Refuse compacting system means any machine or system of machines capable
    of reducing waste material and garbage by means other than burning. So that it reduces by a volume to be determined by the commissioner and is suitable for collection by the department. (48) Refuse containerization system means any system for the
    disposal of waste material and garbage jointly approved as to specifications by the department of health and mental hygiene, the department of housing preservation and development and the department pursuant to section 27-2021 of the code, which utilizes
    containers compatible with mechanical loading systems on vehicles operated for the collection of refuse. (49) Residual fuel oil means a fuel oil meeting the current definition of fuel oil grades No. 5 and 6 as classified by the American society for
    testing and materials. (50) Scrubber means a control apparatus which uses water or other fluids to remove air contaminant from a gas stream. (51) Solid fuels means anthracite and bituminous coal, or coke as currently defined by the American society
    for testing and materials. (52) Standard smoke chart means the Ringelmann chart, as published by the United States bureau of mines, photographically reduced to 1/18th in size for use in the field. (53) This code means the air pollution control code.</text>
</level>