<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-146</num>
  <heading>Preventing particulate matter from becoming air-borne; spraying of asbestos prohibited; spraying of insulating material and demolition regulated.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-146 Preventing particulate matter from becoming air-borne; spraying of asbestos prohibited; spraying of insulating material and demolition regulated. (a) No person shall cause or permit particulate matter to be handled, transported or stored without
    taking such precautions as may be ordered by the commissioner to prevent particulate matter from becoming air-borne. (b) Six months after August twentieth, nineteen hundred seventy-one no person shall cause or permit the spraying of any substance
    containing asbestos in or upon a building or other structure during its construction, alteration or repair, except if permitted by a variance granted pursuant to subdivision (e) of section 24-110 of this chapter. (c) No person shall cause or permit
    a building or its appurtenances or a road to be constructed, altered or repaired without taking such precautions as may be ordered by the commissioner to prevent particulate matter from becoming air-borne. (d) No person shall cause or permit untreated
    open areas located within the boundaries of a zoning lot as defined by section 12-10 of the zoning resolution of the city of New York to be maintained without taking reasonable precautions to prevent particulate matter from becoming air-borne. (e)
    No person shall cause or permit the spraying of any insulating material, not otherwise prohibited by this section, in or upon any building or other structure during its construction, alteration or repair, unless he or she complies with the following
    precautions: (1) Before the start of spraying operations, all floor areas shall be shoveled clean. Before the application of insulating material commences, the floor of the areas shall be cleared of all objects, material and equipment other than that
    employed in the application of the insulating material, or all objects, material, and equipment shall be covered with plastic or other approved tarpaulins in a manner that precludes the subsequent dispersal of particulate matter. (2) The entire floor,
    or the part of the floor to be insulated, shall be enclosed with plastic or other approved tarpaulins in a manner which shall preclude the escape of particulate matter from the enclosure. All interior open areas, such as elevator shafts and stairwells
    shall be enclosed in a manner which shall prevent the escape of particulate matter from the working area. Stack effect of the shafts and stairwells shall be considered in providing proper enclosures. An enclosure will be considered satisfactory only
    if visible insulating material cannot escape from the enclosure. (3) Wet insulating material which has fallen to the floor shall be swept up to prevent dispersal of dried material. Under no condition shall this material be removed later than at the
    end of the working day. Swept-up material shall be placed in a heavy plastic bag strong enough to resist tearing or breaking under normal handling conditions and clearly marked as containing insulating material waste. The contents of the aforementioned
    plastic bags shall not be transferred to another container. The plastic bags shall be placed upon a vehicle for disposal at a site approved by the commissioner. (4) All floors shall be vacuumed shortly after drying. The contents of the vacuum bag
    shall be carefully placed in a container of the type described in paragraph three of this subdivision and shall thereafter be placed on a vehicle for removal and disposal at a site approved by the commissioner. (5) The materials used to form the enclosure
    shall be thoroughly vacuumed upon completion of the application of the insulation in the area. The entire floor area and ledges and surfaces including tarpaulins upon which waste insulation material may have fallen, shall then be vacuumed or revacuumed
    before removal of the enclosures. (6) Enclosures shall not be dismantled until the area has been thoroughly vacuumed after completion of spraying and clean-up. (7) All areas used for opening bags containing insulating material and/or changing of hoppers
    shall be enclosed in such a manner that insulating material shall not be permitted to escape from the immediate area in which such activity takes place. (8) Signs shall be posted outside enclosures warning persons of the hazards of entering the enclosure
    without appropriate apparel. (9) All persons involved in the spraying of insulating material at the site must be furnished with suitable coveralls which must be left at the site. No person shall be permitted in an area in which spraying or handling
    of insulating material has taken place until the final vacuuming referred to in paragraph five of this subdivision has been accomplished, unless such person is furnished with or wears coveralls of the type described herein. Facilities shall be provided
    and procedures instituted and supervised that preclude the removal and dispersal of insulating material from the construction site on the clothing or other appurtenances of persons leaving the area. (10) Any plenum or other structures coated with
    insulating material which are intended for use in circulation of air in the building must be thoroughly cleaned of all debris, dust and waste insulation. All applied insulation material within a plenum or duct must be coated with a sealant approved
    by the commissioner which precludes exposure of the material to the circulating air whenever the commissioner after ordering tests to be conducted by the manufacturer in accordance with section 24-107, determines that the insulation material needs
    such a sealant. (11) A person shall be assigned the full time responsibility of supervising the spraying and related operations to assure that no insulating material is released from the construction site. (12) In case of emission of insulation material
    from the construction site, immediate steps shall be taken to cause the cessation of such emissions by either effective control measures or work stoppage at the source of the emissions. There shall then be immediate and complete clean-up of all material
    that has escaped the construction site by measures that will insure that no further dispersal of any insulating material into the atmosphere can occur. (f) No person shall cause or permit a building or other structure to be demolished, except pursuant
    to chapter one of title seventeen or article eight of subchapter three of chapter one of title twenty-six of the code, unless he or she complies with the following precautions: (1) Demolition by toppling of walls shall not occur except when approved
    by the commissioner. (2) Before the demolition of any section of wall, floor, roof, or other structure, adequate wetting procedures to lay the dust shall be employed. All debris shall be thoroughly wetted before loading and while dumping into trucks,
    other vehicles or containers. In all cases and at all stages of demolition, wetting procedures shall be adequate to lay the dust. Trucks shall be adequately covered or enclosed to prevent dust dispersion while in transit to point of disposal. (3)
    No structural members shall be dropped or thrown from any floor but shall be carefully lowered to ground level by hoists. (4) Effective January first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, debris shall not be dropped or thrown from any floor to any floor
    below. In buildings twelve stories or greater in height debris shall be transported from the upper floors via enclosed, dust-tight chutes or via buckets. Where chutes are used, a water soaking spray shall be employed to saturate the debris before
    it reaches the point of discharge from the chute. Where buckets are used, the debris shall be adequately wetted to preclude dust dispersion when buckets are dumped. (5) Effective January first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, in the event particulate
    matter becomes airborne for a continuous period of fifteen minutes, despite the application of the above procedures, or because freezing temperatures preclude the use of water for laying the demolition dust, the work of demolition shall cease at once
    until other adequate measures can be taken. Alternate procedures shall be evaluated by the commissioner before initiation thereof.</text>
</level>