<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-101.4</num>
  <heading>Online accessible list of pedestrian safety projects.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-101.4 Online accessible list of pedestrian safety projects. a. For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall be defined as follows: 1. "Accessible pedestrian signal" shall mean a device that communicates information about pedestrian
    signal timing in a nonvisual format. 2. "Accessible to people with disabilities" shall mean: i. A text equivalent for every non-text element is provided; ii. equivalent alternatives for any multimedia presentation are synchronized with the presentation;
    iii. web pages are designed so that all information conveyed with color is also available without color; iv. documents are organized so they are readable without requiring an associated style sheet; v. redundant text links are provided for each active
    region of a server-side image map; vi. client-side image maps are provided instead of server-side image maps except where the regions cannot be defined with an available geometric shape; vii. row and column headers are identified for data tables;
    viii. markup is used to associate data cells and header cells for data tables that have two or more logical levels of row or column headers; ix. frames are titled with text that facilitates frame identification and navigation; x. pages are designed
    to avoid causing the screen to flicker with a frequency greater than 2 HZ and lower than 55 Hz; xi. a text-only page, with equivalent information or functionality shall be provided to make a web site comply with the provisions of this part, when compliance
    cannot be accomplished in any other way. The content of the text-only page shall be updated whenever the primary page updates; xii. when pages utilize scripting languages to display content, or to create interface elements, the information provided
    by the script is identified with functional text that can be read by assistive technology; xiii. when pages require that an applet, plug-in or other application be present on the client system to interpret page content, the page must provide a link
    to that plug-in or applet; xiv. when electronic forms are designed to be completed on-line the form shall allow people using assistive technology to access the information, field elements, and functionality required for completion and submission of
    the form, including all directions and cues; xv. a method shall be provided that permits users to skip repetitive navigation links; and xvi. when a timed response is required, the user is alerted and given sufficient time to indicate more time is
    required. 3. "Bicycle lane" shall mean a portion of the roadway that has been marked off or separated for the preferential or exclusive use of bicycles. 4. "Exclusive pedestrian signal" shall mean a pedestrian control signal that allows pedestrians
    an exclusive interval at which to cross while traffic is stopped in all directions. 5. "Leading pedestrian signal" shall mean a pedestrian control signal that displays a walk indicator before a green indicator of a traffic control signal within the
    same intersection is displayed. 6. "Major transportation project" shall mean any project that, after construction, will alter four or more consecutive blocks or 1,000 consecutive feet of street, whichever is less, involving a major realignment of
    the roadway, including either removal of a vehicular lane(s) or full time removal of a parking lane(s) or addition of vehicular travel lane(s). 7. "Pedestrian plaza" shall mean an area designated by the New York city department of transportation for
    use as a plaza located within the bed of a roadway, which may contain benches, tables or other facilities for pedestrian use. b. The department shall post on its website, in a format accessible to people with disabilities: i. The location of all major
    transportation projects and all installations or removals of bicycle lanes, pedestrian plazas, leading pedestrian signals, exclusive pedestrian signals and accessible pedestrian signals. Such posting shall be made not less than seventy-two hours prior
    to the expected completion date of each project, installation or removal. ii. The location of all major transportation projects subject to section 19-101.2 of this code completed on or after January 1, 2010 and all bicycle lanes, pedestrian plazas,
    leading pedestrian signals, exclusive pedestrian signals and accessible pedestrian signals in existence on the effective date of this section. Such posting shall be made on or before the effective date of this section, except that all such leading
    pedestrian signals and exclusive pedestrian signals shall be posted on or before December 31, 2012.</text>
</level>