<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-350</num>
  <heading>Ceiling construction.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-350 Ceiling construction. Ceilings that are to be suspended below floor or roof construction by means of a framing system shall consist of supporting hangers, carrying channels and a supporting grid complying with reference standard RS 5-16 or
    shall have supporting hangers and carrying channels and a supporting grid that can be demonstrated to the satisfaction of the commissioner to be of strength adequate to support the ceiling material. The hangers and supporting grid shall be of noncombustible
    materials. In buildings of construction group II, every other hanger supported from wood members shall be attached by a through bolt or clinched through nail. Where, in table 3-4, floor or roof construction is required to have a fire-resistance rating,
    a ceiling having no fire-resistance rating may be suspended below the fire-resistance construction. (a) Luminous ceilings. For the purpose of this section, a luminous ceiling shall be defined as a ceiling consisting of translucent, louvered, egg-crated,
    mesh, or similar light-diffusing material suspended from the ceiling or structural framework. A suspended ceiling containing less than twenty square feet of translucent, louvered, egg-crated, mesh, or similar material in any one hundred square feet
    of ceiling area shall not be considered a luminous ceiling, and shall be constructed and installed in accordance with department of buildings requirements for lighting fixtures. Luminous ceilings shall, in addition to the requirements of this section,
    conform to all of the requirements of section 27-348 of this article for interior finish. (1) LUMINOUS CEILINGS OF NONCOMBUSTIBLE MATERIAL. Luminous ceilings constructed of glass and/or metal or other noncombustible materials may be used in any location.
    a. Glass used in luminous ceilings, unless it is wire glass or heat-resistant glass as specified below, shall not weigh more than two psf, nor shall any pane be larger than eight square feet in area. If glass used in luminous ceilings is wire glass,
    or is heat resistant by reason of having a maximum coefficient of expansion of 36 x 10-7 in. per in. per degree C, the glass may be of any weight and any size, limited only by considerations of structural safety. b. Luminous ceilings installed below
    sprinkler heads shall be constructed of a type of noncombustible louver, mesh, or other open material that will not impede the flow of water from the sprinkler heads over the intended area of coverage. The luminous ceiling shall be constructed so
    as to provide access to all heads and valves. (2) LUMINOUS CEILINGS OF COMBUSTIBLE MATERIAL. Luminous ceilings constructed of combustible materials shall not be installed in: a. Any exit or corridor. b. Any room classified in occupancy group H, or
    any room leading therefrom as defined in note b of table 5-4. c. Any room in which the net floor area per occupant is twenty square feet or less, or any room leading therefrom as defined in note b of table 5-4. d. Luminous ceilings constructed elsewhere
    than in the spaces listed in subparagraphs a, b, and c above shall be exempt from the provisions of section 27-348 of this article, provided that: 1. The panels of such ceilings are of slow-burning plastic; 2. The panels are installed above or below
    sprinklers that are constructed in accordance with the provisions of subchapter seventeen of this chapter; 3. No individual plastic panel exceeds ten feet in maximum dimension. Where installed below sprinkler heads, the plastic shall be a material
    that will fall from its mounting at a temperature at least fifteen degrees lower than the temperature at which the sprinkler heads are designed to operate or are constructed of open material which will not impede the flow of water from the sprinkler
    heads. Luminous ceilings shall be installed so as to provide ready access to all heads and valves. (b) Suspension of new ceilings below existing suspended ceilings. In construction group I a new ceiling may be suspended below not more than one existing
    suspended ceiling and shall be supported directly from the ceiling carrying channels adjacent to the hangers. In construction group II, an existing suspended ceiling shall be completely removed before a new ceiling may be suspended.</text>
</level>