<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-507.2</num>
  <heading>Critical driver program.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-507.2 Critical driver program. a. Any taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver who has been found guilty of violations such that six or more points have been assessed by the department of motor vehicles or an equivalent licensing agency of the driver's
    state of residence against the driver license issued to such taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver within any fifteen-month period and whose taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver's license has not been revoked shall have his or her taxicab or for-hire vehicle
    driver's license suspended for thirty days. The provisions of this subdivision shall apply only to violations issued on or after February 15, 1999. b. Any taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver who has been found guilty of violations such that ten or
    more points have been assessed by the department of motor vehicles or an equivalent licensing agency of the driver's state of residence against the driver license issued to such taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver within any fifteen-month period shall
    have his or her taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver's license revoked. The provisions of this subdivision shall apply only to violations issued on or after February 15, 1999. c. (1) On or after September 1, 1999, a taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver
    shall be eligible to receive a two point reduction in the number of points assessed pursuant to the critical driver program upon the submission to the commission of proof of the satisfactory completion of a motor vehicle accident prevention course
    approved by the department of motor vehicles. Such point reduction shall be considered in computing the total number of points accumulated by such driver as a result of violations which occurred within fifteen months prior to the date of the completion
    of the course. (2) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph one of this subdivision no point reduction shall affect any suspension or revocation action which may be taken by the commission pursuant to this program prior to the completion of the
    course. No person shall receive a point reduction more than once in any eighteen month period and no person shall receive a point reduction unless attendance at the course is voluntary on the part of the driver. (3) Notwithstanding the provisions
    of paragraphs one and two of this subdivision, any taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver who voluntarily attends and satisfactorily completes one motor vehicle accident prevention course approved by the department of motor vehicles between the effective
    date of this local law and August 31, 1999, shall have two points deducted from the total number of points assessed pursuant to the critical driver program against his or her taxicab or for-hire vehicle driver's license. No point reduction shall affect
    any suspension or revocation action which may be taken by the commission pursuant to this program prior to the completion of the course.</text>
</level>