<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-251</num>
  <heading>Applications for, and issuance of, registration plates.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-251 Applications for, and issuance of, registration plates. a. The commissioner shall accept application for registration plates, pursuant to section 20-255, provided that the total number of registration plates shall not exceed eight hundred and
    fifty. The commissioner shall conduct an annual review of pedicab registrations, and if the number of registration plates issued falls below eight hundred and forty, the Commissioner shall issue additional registration plates in such manner as is
    consistent with the provisions of this subchapter as he or she by rule shall prescribe. b. The department has the authority to inspect pedicabs to determine whether the pedicabs are equipped with the features set forth in subdivision a of section
    20-254 and comply with the requirement set forth in subdivision b of section 20-254. c. The commissioner shall issue registration plates only to a pedicab owner who has submitted the materials required by subdivision b of section 20-250 to obtain,
    amend or renew a pedicab business license or to a pedicab owner who has already obtained a pedicab business license. d. The commissioner shall not issue registration plates to more than thirty pedicabs for any pedicab business. No pedicab business
    or pedicab owner shall hold more than thirty registration plates at any one time. A pedicab business shall be deemed to have more than thirty pedicab registration plates if: (1) an owner of such pedicab business has a direct or indirect beneficial
    interest in one or more other pedicab businesses and the businesses together have more than thirty pedicab registration plates; (2) a family member of the owner of such business has a direct or indirect beneficial interest in one or more other pedicab
    businesses and the businesses together have more than thirty registration plates; (3) a person who has a direct or indirect beneficial interest in such pedicab business has a direct or indirect beneficial interest in one or more other pedicab businesses
    and the businesses together have more than thirty registration plates; or (4) a family member of a person who has a direct or indirect beneficial interest in such pedicab business has a direct or indirect beneficial interest in one or more other pedicab
    businesses and the businesses together have more than thirty registration plates. e. The commissioner shall issue registration plates only to a pedicab business or owner with respect to pedicabs listed and identified in accordance with paragraph 1
    of subdivision b of section 20-250 on the application of such business or owner for a pedicab business license. f. A pedicab registration plate shall become void upon the revocation or suspension of the pedicab owner's pedicab business license.</text>
</level>