<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-758</num>
  <heading>Kitchens.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-758 Kitchens. Kitchens shall be ventilated as follows: (a) Kitchens located within dwelling units and having a floor area of greater than fifty-nine square feet shall have natural ventilation as prescribed in article six of this subchapter. When
    the floor area is fifty-nine square feet or less, the kitchen shall be ventilated by either of the following: (1) Natural means complying with article six of this subchapter and further that the windows shall have a minimum width of twelve inches,
    a minimum area of thee square feet or ten per cent of the floor area of the space whichever is greater and so constructed that at least one-half of their required area may be opened. When the space is located at the top story the window or windows
    may be replaced with a skylight whose minimum width shall be twelve inches, whose minimum area shall be four square feet or one-eighth the floor area of the space whichever is greater and shall have ventilating openings of at least one-half of the
    required area of the skylight. (2) Mechanical means exhausting at least two cfm of air per square foot of floor area. Where doors are used to separate the space the lower portion of each door shall have a metal grille containing at least forty-eight
    square inches of clean openings or in lieu of such grille two clear open spaces may be provided, each of at least twenty-four square inches, one between the bottom of each door and the floor and the other between the top of each door and the head
    jamb. (b) Kitchens, except those located within dwelling units, and side spaces, where cooking of any kind is done, shall be ventilated by either of the following; provided that in no instance may there be any violation of the nuisance provisions
    of the health code. (1) Natural means complying with article six of this subchapter and supplemented with auxiliary mechanical supply and exhaust ventilation adequate to remove the fumes and smoke from the cooking equipment when operating. (2) Mechanical
    means exhausting at least three cfm of air per square foot of floor area, but in no case less than one hundred fifty cfm. Such air shall be exhausted through duct or chimney constructed in accordance with the provisions of subchapters thirteen through
    fifteen of this chapter. (c) Kitchens, snack bars, or pantries, where the operation consists of heating or warming previously prepared food that was cooked elsewhere, or preparation of food in vending machines may be ventilated by either of the following:
    (1) Natural ventilation complying with article six of this subchapter. (2) Mechanical ventilation complying with article seven of this subchapter.
  </text>
</level>