<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-307</num>
  <heading>Interagency coordinating council.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-307 Interagency coordinating council. a. There shall be an interagency coordinating council established by the mayor which shall consist of representatives of each city agency providing transitional housing or services to eligible homeless persons
    and other homeless individuals and families. Such interagency coordinating council shall include, but shall not be limited to, representatives of the department of homeless services, the department of social services, the department of housing preservation
    and development and such other agencies as the mayor shall designate. The mayor shall designate a deputy mayor to serve as chairperson of the interagency coordinating council. The commissioner of the department of homeless services shall provide appropriate
    personnel to assist the interagency coordinating council in the performance of its functions. b. The interagency coordinating council shall: 1. Not later than October 1, 1995 and each year thereafter, prepare, in consultation with the office of management
    and budget, an annual breakdown of each member agency's expenditures for housing and services to the homeless in the adopted budget; 2. review the organization and operations of member agencies with respect to contracted service providers to the homeless,
    including service delivery, management and evaluation of performance; 3. recommend means by which the duplication and fragmentation of the provision of housing for, and delivery of services to, the homeless may be reduced and the efficiency, effectiveness
    and economy of service delivery may be enhanced; 4. consider proposals for the improvement of transitional and permanent housing programs and service delivery to the homeless; and 5. recommend to the mayor and the city council joint agency projects
    or programs which could facilitate more efficient use of existing resources. c. The interagency coordinating council shall meet at least quarterly and shall hold at least one public hearing annually, at which public testimony shall be taken. A report
    on each such public hearing shall be submitted in writing to the speaker of the city council within ten days of the date on which such public hearing shall have been held. Where the interagency coordinating council fails to hold such meetings or public
    hearings as required pursuant to this subdivision, a report shall be submitted in writing to the speaker of the city council including an explanation of the failure to hold such meetings or public hearings.</text>
</level>