<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-101.2</num>
  <heading>Review of major transportation projects.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-101.2 Review of major transportation projects. a. For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall be defined as follows: 1. "Affected council member(s) and community board(s)" shall mean the council member(s) and community board(s)
    in whose districts a proposed major transportation project is to be located, in whole or in part. 2. "Major transportation project" shall mean any project that, after construction will alter four or more consecutive blocks, or 1,000 consecutive feet
    of street, whichever is less, involving a major realignment of the roadway, including either removal of a vehicular lane(s) or full time removal of a parking lane(s) or addition of vehicular travel lane(s). b. If an agency of the city other than the
    department implements a major transportation project, such agency, in lieu of the department, shall provide the notice required by this section. c. Prior to the implementation of a major transportation project, the department shall forward notice
    of such project, including a description of such project, to affected council member(s) and community board(s) by electronic mail. d. Within ten business days after receipt of such notice: (i) the affected council member(s) may submit recommendations
    and/or comments on such notice to the department; and (ii) the affected community board(s) may either submit recommendations and/or comments on such notice to the department and/or request a presentation of the major transportation project plan by
    the department, which shall be made to the community board within thirty days of such community board's request. e. Each presentation shall include, at a minimum, the project limits, a description, and a justification of such plan, and a map showing
    the streets affected by such plan and, within three days of such presentation, shall be forwarded to the affected council member(s). f. The department shall consider recommendations and/or comments, if any, made under the provisions of subdivision
    d of this section and/or within seven days of the presentation to the community board, from the affected council member(s) and affected community board(s), and may incorporate changes, where appropriate, into the plan. g. The department may implement
    its plan fourteen or more days after it sends an amended plan or notice that it will proceed with its original plan to the affected council member(s) and community board(s). h. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the department
    from providing notice of its major transportation projects on its website and to affected council member(s) and community board(s) and other interested parties by other means in addition to those specified in this section. i. Nothing in this section
    shall be construed to require the department to provide notification of major transportation projects requiring immediate implementation to preserve public safety. j. Prior to the implementation of a major transportation project, the department shall
    consult with the police department, the fire department, the department of small business services and the mayor's office for people with disabilities. The department shall include a certification of such consultations in the notice required by subdivision
    c of this section.</text>
</level>