<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-247</num>
  <heading>Information required for applications for operating certificates and for tunneling permits.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-247 Information required for applications for operating certificates and for tunneling permits. (a) Each application for an operating certificate shall contain such information as the commissioner may require in order to determine whether a device
    covered by the application is or will operate in compliance with the provisions of this code, including but not limited to: (1) The model number and operating characteristics of the device covered by the application; (2) A report certified by an approved
    testing laboratory as to the sound level generated by the device when operated under normal operating conditions or a manufacturer's warranty as to sound level provided that the device is regularly tested in accordance with procedures established
    by the American national standards institute or other appropriate professional standard-setting organization listed in section 24-242; and (3) The proposed means, if any, for the prevention or control of unreasonable noise. (b) Each application for
    a tunneling permit shall contain such information as the commissioner may require to determine whether tunneling activities and the devices operated therein will be undertaken in compliance with the provisions of this code, including but not limited
    to: (1) The types and operating characteristics of the devices employed in such tunneling; (2) A detailed description of proposed tunneling; and (3) The proposed means for the prevention of unreasonable noise. (c) Information concerning secret processes
    which may be required, ascertained or discovered by the department shall not be disclosed by any department employee, except that the information may be disclosed by the commissioner if the department is subpoenaed for the information or if in the
    course of a departmental court proceeding or departmental or board hearing, the information is relevant to the proceeding or hearing.</text>
</level>