<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-269</num>
  <heading>Criminal penalties.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-269 Criminal penalties. (a) Any person who shall knowingly make a false statement or who shall knowingly falsify or allow to be falsified any certification, registration, form, signed statement, application or report required under the provisions
    of this code or regulation promulgated by the commissioner or the board shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment
    not to exceed five months, or both. (b) Any person, other than a corporation, who violates any order of the commissioner or the board or any provision of section 24-245 of this code or who illegally breaks a seal on equipment, upon conviction shall
    be punished for each offense by a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than thirty days or by both. Any corporation which violates any order of the commissioner or the board or any
    provision of section 24-245 of this code, or which illegally causes a seal to be broken, upon conviction shall be punished for each offense by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars nor more than two thousand dollars. Every day during which such
    violation occurs constitutes a separate offense. (c) Any person, other than a corporation, convicted of willful failure to pay a civil penalty imposed by the board pursuant to section 24-257 of this code shall be punished by a fine of double the amount
    of the civil penalty imposed by the board, or by imprisonment for not more than sixty days, or by both. Any corporation convicted of a wilful failure to pay a civil penalty imposed by the board pursuant to section 24-257 of this code shall be punished
    by a fine of double the amount of the civil penalty imposed by the board, but not more than two thousand dollars. (d) The failure of any person or corporation against whom an action has been brought to collect a civil penalty pursuant to subdivision
    (b) of section 24-267 of this code, who has been found liable by a court for such civil penalty and who does not pay such penalty after the judgment of such becomes final, shall be deemed guilty of a willful failure to pay a civil penalty. (e) Any
    person convicted of violating any of the provisions of this code or any regulation of the board not otherwise provided for by this section shall be punished by a fine of not less than fifty dollars nor more than five hundred dollars for the first
    offense, or by imprisonment for twenty days, or both; and by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than thirty days, or both, for a second offense; and by a fine of not less
    than four hundred dollars nor more than five thousand dollars, or by imprisonment for not more than four months or both for a third or subsequent offense. (f) Twenty-five percent of any fine that is imposed pursuant to this section may be paid to
    the person or persons giving information which shall lead to conviction.</text>
</level>