<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-308</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-308 Definitions. Whenever used in this subchapter, the following terms shall mean and include: 1. "Sale." A sale or an offer to sell to the public goods, wares, and merchandise of any and all kinds and descriptions on hand and in stock in connection
    with a declared purpose, as set forth by advertising on the part of the seller that such sale is: a. Anticipatory to the termination, closing, liquidation, wind-up, discontinuance, removal, conclusion, or abandonment of the business, and advertised
    in the following phrases and in any other phrase or phrases of like or similar language which reasonably convey to the public that the sale is being conducted for such purpose: "going out of business sale," "trustee's sale," "liquidation sale," "executor's
    sale," "administrator's sale," "insolvent sale," "mortgage sale," "adjustor's sale," "receiver's sale," "loss of lease sale," "forced out of business sale," "branch store discontinuance sale," "removal sale," "warehouse removal sale." b. Pursuant
    to the execution of a legal right by a party other than the original owner or owners of the goods, wares and merchandise, without court order, and advertised in the following phrases and in any other phrase or phrases of like or similar language which
    reasonably convey to the public that the sale is of such a nature: "adjustment sale," "reorganization sale," "creditors' committee sale," "assignee's sale." c. Pursuant to an intention to renovate, restore, rebuild or alter the premises in which the
    sale is taking place, and advertised in the following phrases and in any other phrase or phrases of like or similar language which reasonably convey to the public that the sale is conducted for such purposes: "alteration sale," "remodeling sale,"
    "renovation sale." d. A result of damage or alteration to the goods, wares and merchandise being offered for sale by reason of a disaster or other fortuitous occurrence, and advertised in the following phrases and in any other phrase or phrases of
    like or similar language which reasonably convey to the public that the sale is being conducted as a result of such occurrence: "fire sale," "insurance salvage sale," "damaged goods sale," "smoke sale," "water damage sale." 2. "Publish," "publishing,"
    "advertisement," "advertising." Any and all means of conveying to the public notice of sale or notice of intention to conduct a sale, whether by word of mouth, by newspaper advertisement, by magazine advertisement, by handbill, by written notice,
    by printed notice, by printed display, by billboard display, by poster, by radio announcement, by television announcement, and any and all means including oral, written or printed.</text>
</level>