<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-180</num>
  <heading>Performance indicators.</heading>
  <text>ยง19-180 Performance indicators. a. For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall be defined as follows: 1. "Bicycle screen lines" shall mean locations where bicycles are ridden, including but not limited to greenways, roadways and bridge
    crossings. 2. "Borough screen lines" shall mean locations where roadways cross between boroughs. 3. "City screen lines" shall mean locations where roadways enter the city. 4. "High performance modes" shall mean a form of surface transportation other
    than automobiles, including buses, ferries, bicycling and walking, that more efficiently uses roadways and waterways to move people. 5. "Key corridors" shall mean major arterial roadways where changes in street operations, such as lane reapportionments,
    lane reconfigurations, significant adjustments in traffic and parking regulations and changes in traffic signal timing have been completed, are being implemented or are being studied. b. The department shall develop and monitor performance indicators
    that will assist in assessing and reducing the amount of traffic on transportation infrastructure and promote high performance modes citywide and within each borough. Such indicators shall include: 1. vehicle volume data at city screen lines, borough
    screen lines and river crossings. 2. vehicle volume data and other data where appropriate, including but not limited to vehicle speed, bus speed and ridership, pedestrian, bicycle and crash data, on key corridors. 3. vehicle speed data to be determined
    utilizing available global positioning systems data. 4. bicycle volume data based on bicycle screen lines. 5. ferry volume data based upon information on ridership from city-operated and private ferry services. c. The performance indicators developed
    pursuant to this section shall be measured and reported citywide and by borough by the department, submitted in a written report to the speaker of the council and the mayor and posted on the department's official website by November 1st of each following
    calendar year. Where such report provides information for a key corridor, such report shall provide performance indicators before and after construction or project implementation. Such report shall include information for each indicator from the prior
    calendar year and shall describe departmental assessments about the projects where appropriate.
  </text>
</level>