<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-112</num>
  <heading>Ramps on curbs.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-112 Ramps on curbs. In the construction and installation of all new and reconstructed curbs at corner located street intersections and pedestrian crosswalks not located at street intersections, provision shall be made for the installation of the
    following: two ramps at corners located at street intersections and one ramp at pedestrian crosswalks not located at street intersections. Such ramps shall be no less than four feet wide and shall blend to a common level with the roadway. If a common
    level is unobtainable, then the lip of such ramps shall not exceed a maximum of five-eighths of an inch and shall have a rounded edge. The slope of such ramp shall not exceed eight per cent. This section shall apply to all construction of new curbs
    and to all replacement of existing curbs. The commissioner shall have discretion to waive one of the two mandatory ramps at corners located at street intersections where any of the following obstacles exists preventing construction of such ramp within
    an intersection: fire hydrants, light poles, traffic signals, fire alarms, or free-standing police alarms, underground vaults, tunnels, utility maintenance holes (manholes), chambers or where the gradient of the street on which the ramp is to be located
    or an intersecting street exceeds a gradient of 1:8. The commissioner may waive the construction of both such ramps where the existence of underground vaults, tunnels, utility maintenance holes (manholes) and chambers would either prevent the safe
    construction of such ramps or render impossible the construction of such ramps to proper specifications without removal of said underground installations. A certification to such effect shall be made part of the engineering design documents for such
    construction, and a copy thereof shall be filed with the city clerk. Curbs for non-pedestrian routes, such as, but not limited to, service paths for highways and pedestrian restricted traffic islands shall not be subject to the provisions of this
    section.</text>
</level>