<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-389</num>
  <heading>Designation of required means of egress.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-389 Designation of required means of egress. (a) Except for spaces classified in occupancy J-2 and J-3, the location of each required means of egress on every floor of every structure shall be clearly indicated by exit signs. Such signs shall be
    placed at an angle with the exit doorway if such placement shall be required for such signs to serve their purpose adequately. These signs shall be of an approved phosphorescent material, which after exposure to normal lighting conditions shall be
    capable of remaining visible in total darkness for a period of at least eight hours. They shall also be washable, non-toxic, non-radioactive, and if subjected to fire must be self-extinguishing when the flame is removed. Except for illuminated signs,
    these signs shall have a phosphorescent background and opaque text. Where means of egress were required to be indicated by an illuminated sign, there shall be either (1) an illuminated exit sign with the lettering thereon made of the approved phosphorescent
    material, or (2) a supplemental exit sign made of the approved phosphorescent material with an opaque text, and placed adjacent to or as close as possible to such illuminated sign. (b) Except for spaces classified in occupancy groups J-2 and J-3,
    in long corridors, in open floor areas and in all other situations where the location of the means of egress may not be readily discernible or understood by the occupants, directional signs shall be provided and maintained to serve as guides from
    all portions of the floor or corridor. These signs shall be of an approved phosphorescent material which after exposure to normal lighting conditions shall be capable of remaining visible in total darkness for a period of at least eight hours. They
    shall also be washable, non-toxic, non-radioactive, and if subjected to fire must be self-extinguishing when the flame is removed. Except for illuminated signs these signs shall have a phosphorescent background and opaque text. Where a directional
    sign was required to be illuminated there shall be either (1) an illuminated directional sign with the lettering, indicator, symbol or other device thereon made of the aforesaid phosphorescent material, or (2) a supplemental directional sign with
    the same lettering, indicator, symbol or device as appears on the illuminated sign, but opaque, on a background made of the aforesaid phosphorescent material and placed adjacent to or as close as possible to such illuminated sign. (c) Except where
    otherwise permitted by the provisions of any law, the lettering of exit signs shall be of letters of at least eight inches high. (d) In those buildings not provided with artificial lighting, in those buildings which maintain one or more auxiliary
    systems for emergency exit lighting in the event of a public utility failure, and in those buildings for which the installation of one or more such auxiliary systems is commenced on or before August sixth, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, the signs need
    not be phosphorescent but shall otherwise conform to this section.</text>
</level>