<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-128</num>
  <heading>Renting of tennis stadium and center in Flushing Meadows-Corona Park.</heading>
  <text>§ 18-128 Renting of tennis stadium and center in Flushing Meadows-Corona Park. a. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, general, special or local, the city, acting by the commissioner is hereby authorized and empowered to enter into contracts,
    long-term leases or rental agreements with, or grant licenses, permits, concessions or other authorizations to, the USTA National Tennis Center Incorporated, its affiliates, successors or mortgagees, or assigns in connection with or pursuant to a
    mortgage or other financing (including an assignment by a mortgagee) ("NTC") upon such terms and conditions, for such consideration, and for such term of duration as may be agreed upon by the city and the NTC, whereby the NTC is granted the right,
    for any purpose or purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section, to use, occupy or carry on activities on certain tracts of land described in subdivision c of this section, including the facilities constructed on such tracts of land, being
    a part of Flushing Meadows-Corona Park and situated in the borough of Queens, city and state of New York, title to which tracts is now in the city, with rights of ingress and egress thereto and therefrom, together with appurtenant rights to use areas
    within the park other than those described in subdivision c of this section, upon such terms and conditions as agreed upon by the commissioner, for up to sixty days in any calendar year for ancillary parking to support the U.S. Open Tennis Championships
    or other similar competitive tennis events. Prior to or after the expiration or termination of the terms of duration of any contracts, leases, rental agreements, licenses, permits, concessions or other authorizations entered into or granted pursuant
    to the provisions of this subdivision and subdivision b of this section, the city, in accordance with the requirements and conditions of this subdivision and subdivision b of this section, may from time to time enter into amended, new, additional
    or further contracts, leases or rental agreements with, and grant new, additional or further licenses, permits, concessions or other authorizations to the NTC or other person for any purpose or purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section;
    provided however, that any such lease entered into with a person other than the NTC shall not exceed a period of more than one year and shall not be renewable; and provided further that upon the expiration of such one year period, the city may not
    enter into any further leases for the lands and facilities described in this section. b. Any contract, lease, rental agreement, license, permit, concession or other authorization referred to in subdivision a of this section may grant to the NTC or
    other person, the right to use, occupy or carry on activities in, the whole or any part of such tracts of land, including such facilities constructed on such tracts of land, (1) for any purpose or purposes which is of such nature as to furnish to,
    or foster or promote among, or provide for the benefit of, the people of the city, recreational use and activities including entertainment, amusement, education, enlightenment, cultural development or betterment, and improvement of trade and commerce,
    including professional, amateur and scholastic sports and athletic events, theatrical, musical or other cultural and entertainment presentations, and meetings, assemblages, conventions and exhibitions, including those held for business or trade purposes,
    and other events of charitable, civic, community and general public interest, and/or (2) for any charitable, business or commercial purpose which aids in the operation of the facilities constructed on such tracts of land and which does not interfere
    with the accomplishment of the purposes referred to in paragraph (1) of this subdivision. Any such lease, rental agreement, license, permit, concession or other authorization shall contain provisions with respect to: the establishment of a fund by
    the NTC to be used by the city, with the approval of the commissioner after consultation with the borough president, for park improvement purposes; the operation of expanded public programs designed to meet the needs of the community, and to encourage
    broad participation by the public in the sport of tennis as agreed to by the commissioner; and the implementation of non-discrimination and affirmative action policies. It is hereby declared that all of the purposes referred to in this subdivision
    are for the benefit of the people of the city and for the improvement of their health, welfare, recreation and prosperity, for the promotion of competitive sports for youth and the prevention of juvenile delinquency, lessening of the burdens of government,
    and for the improvement of trade and commerce, and are hereby declared to be public purposes. c. The tracts of land referred to in subdivision a of this section are more particularly described as follows: All that certain lot, piece or parcel of land,
    with the buildings and improvements thereon erected, situate, lying and being in Flushing Meadows-Corona Park in the borough of Queens, city and state of New York bounded and described as follows: 1. BEGINNING at a point being the corner formed by
    the intersection of the southeasterly side of the Long Island Rail Road R.O.W. (Flushing and North Side Division) with the northeasterly side of the Grand Central Parkway, said Point of Beginning being N.Y.C. Monument No. 23945 as laid out on N.Y.C.
    Alteration Maps number 4164, 4179 and 4496; Running thence North 36°-13'-30" East, along the southeasterly side of the Long Island Rail Road R.O.W., a distance of 1,223.44 feet to a point; Running thence North 49°-26'-52" East, a distance of 245.50
    feet to a point of curvature; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 13°-13'-20" and a radius of 610.00 feet, a distance of 140.77 feet to a point of tangency; Running thence North 36°-13'-33" East, a distance
    of 211.45 feet to a point; Running thence South 54°-01'-05" East, a distance of 245.89 feet to a point; Running thence South 35°-58'-51" West, a distance of 7.98 feet to a point; Running thence South 54°-01'-05" East, a distance of 39.78 feet to a
    point; Running thence North 35°-46'-36" East, a distance of 8.27 feet to a point; Running thence South 54°-01'-05" East, a distance of 25.80 feet to a point of non-tangency; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle
    of 58°-23'-39", a radius of 130.00 feet and a radial bearing of North 65°-23'-12" East, a distance of 132.49 feet to a point of non-tangency; Running thence South 11°-06'-58" East, a distance of 860.65 feet to a point; Running thence South 21°-52'-59"
    West, a distance of 55.13 feet to a point; Running thence South 51°-38'-00" West, a distance of 13.36 feet to a point of tangency; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 13°-18'-06", a radius of 467.00 feet
    and a distance of 132.49 feet to a point; Running thence South 38°-20'-00" West, a distance of 251.91 feet to a point; Running thence South 37°-02'-43" West, a distance of 88.98 feet to a point; Running thence South 38°-20'-00" West, a distance of
    297.32 feet to a point; Running thence South 38°-23'-12" West, a distance of 211.85 feet to a point; Running thence South 38°-32'-31" West, a distance of 200.00 feet to a point; Running thence North 55°-21'-03" West, a distance of 14.76 feet to a
    point; Running thence South 38°-45'-41" West, a distance of 32.45 feet to a point of non-tangency; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right and having a central angle of 5°-34'-27", a radius of 7,000.00 feet and a radial bearing of North
    33°-38'-33" East, a distance of 681.01 feet to a point of tangency; Running thence North 50°-47'-00" West, a distance of 403.24 feet to the POINT AND PLACE OF BEGINNING. The area of this parcel is 1,855,082 sq. ft. (42.5868 acres) and the total perimeter
    is 5,500.45 feet. 2. BEGINNING at a point being the following courses and distances from the corner formed by the intersection of the southeasterly side of the Long Island Rail Road R.O.W. (Flushing and North Side Division) with the northeasterly
    side of the Grand Central Parkway, said Point of Beginning being N.Y.C. Monument No. 23945 as laid out on N.Y.C. Alteration Maps numbers 4164, 4179 and 4496; (1) Running thence North 36°-13'-30" East, along the southeasterly side of the Long Island
    Rail Road R.O.W., a distance of 1,223.44 feet to a point; (2) Running thence North 49°-26'-52" East, a distance of 245.50 feet to a point of curvature; (3) Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 13°-13'-20"
    and a radius of 610.00 feet, a distance of 140.77 feet to a point of tangency; (4) Running thence North 36°-13'-33" East, a distance of 460.50 feet to a point; (5) Running thence South 53°-51'-28" East, a distance of 89.31 feet to the POINT OR PLACE
    OF BEGINNING; Running thence North 35°-59'-23" East, a distance of 168.81 feet to a non tangent point of curvature; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 5°-13'-58", a radius of 588.03 feet and a radial bearing
    of North 57°-54'-08" West, a distance of 53.70 feet to a point of tangency; Running thence North 26°-51'-55" East, a distance of 67.58 feet to a point of curvature; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right and having a central angle of 10°-03'-52"
    and a radius of 329.01 feet, a distance of 57.80 feet to a point (not a point of tangency); Running thence South 53°-51'-27" East, a distance of 136.54 feet to a non tangent point of curvature; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right, having
    a central angle of 21°-10'-31", a radius of 1,000.00 feet and a radial bearing of North 83°-57'-07" West, a distance of 369.58 feet to a point (not a point of tangency); Running thence North 53°-51'-28" West, a distance of 237.41 feet to the POINT
    OR PLACE OF BEGINNING. The area of this parcel is 67,357 sq.ft. (1.546 acres) and the total perimeter is 1,262.48 feet. d. The tracts of land required by this act to be surrendered by the NTC from the tracts of land previously granted and rededicated
    as park lands are as follows: 1. BEGINNING at a point being the following courses and distances from the corner formed by the intersection of the southeasterly side of the Long Island Rail Road R.O.W. (Flushing and North Side Division) with the northeasterly
    side of the Grand Central Parkway, said Point of Beginning being N.Y.C. Monument No. 23945 as laid out on N.Y.C Alteration Maps numbers 4164, 4179 and 4496 (1) Running thence North 36°-13'-30" East, along the southeasterly side of the Long Island
    Rail Road R.O.W., a distance of 1,233.44 feet to a point; (2) Running thence North 49°-26'-52" East, a distance of 245.50 feet to a point of curvature; (3) Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 13°-13'-20"
    and a radius of 610.00 feet, a distance of 140.77 feet to a point of tangency; (4) Running thence North 36°-13'-33" East, a distance of 460.50 feet to a point; (5) Running thence South 53°-51'-28" East, a distance of 89.31 feet to a point; (6) Running
    thence North 35°-59'-23" East, a distance of 168.81 feet to a non tangent point of curvature; (7) Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 05°13'58" and a radius of 588.03 feet and a radial bearing of North 57°54'08"
    West, a distance of 53.70 feet to a point of tangency; (8) Running thence North 26°-51'-55" East, a distance of 67.58 feet to a point of curvature; (9) Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right and having a central angle of 10°-03'-52" and
    a radius of 329.01 feet and a distance of 57.80 feet to a POINT OR PLACE OF BEGINNING; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right and having a central angle of 15°-58'-37" and a radius of 329.01 feet and a radial bearing of South 53°-04'-11"
    East, a distance of 91.74 feet to a point (not a point of tangency); Running thence North 54°-51'-58" East, a distance of 30.77 feet to a non tangent point of curvature; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right, having a central angle of
    113°-46'-56", a radius of 15.62 feet and a radial bearing of South 36°-25'-54" East, a distance of 31.03 feet to a point (not a point of tangency); Running thence South 01°-03'-39" East, a distance of 71.24 feet to a non tangent point of curvature;
    Running thence along a curve, bearing to the right, having a central angle of 04°-44'-42", a radius of 1,000.00 feet and a radial bearing of North 88°-41'-48" West, a distance of 82.81' feet to a point (not a point of tangency); Running thence North
    53°-51'-27" West, a distance of 136.54 feet to the POINT OR PLACE OF BEGINNING. The area of this parcel is 10,923 sq. ft. (0.2510 acres) and the total perimeter is 444.13 feet. 2. BEGINNING at a point being the following courses and distances from
    the corner formed by the intersection of the southeasterly side of the Long Island Rail Road R.O.W. (Flushing and North Side Division) with the northeasterly side of the Grand Central Parkway, said Point of Beginning being N.Y.C. Monument No. 23945
    as laid out on N.Y.C. Alteration Maps numbers 4164, 4179 and 4496; (1) Running thence North 36°-13'-30" East, along the southeasterly side of the Long Island Rail Road R.O.W., a distance of 1,223.44 feet to a point; (2) Running thence North 49°-26'-52"
    East, a distance of 245.50 feet to a point of curvature; (3) Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left and having a central angle of 13°-13'-20" and a radius of 610.00 feet, a distance of 140.77 feet to a point of tangency; (4) Running thence
    North 36°-13'-33" East, a distance of 460.50 feet to a point; (5) Running thence South 53°-51'-28" East, a distance of 401.06 feet to a point (not a point of curvature); (6) Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left, having a central angle
    of 00°-59'-45", a radius of 1,073.50 feet and a radial bearing of N 62°-09'-41" West, a distance of 18.66 feet to the POINT OR PLACE OF BEGINNING; Running thence along the same curve, bearing to the left, having a central angle of 10°-34'-58", a radius
    of 1,073.50 feet and a radial bearing of North 63°-09'-27" West, a distance of 198.28 feet to a point; Running thence South 77°-26'-40" East, a distance of 69.89 feet to a point; Running thence South 52°-65'-05" East, a distance of 240.12 feet to
    a point; Running thence South 37°-03'-55" West, a distance of 147.20 feet to a point (not a point of curvature); Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left, having a central angle of 4°-37'-36", a radius of 2,600.00 feet and a radial bearing
    of South 10°-56'-00" West, a distance of 209.95 feet to a point of reverse curvature; Running thence along a curve bearing to the right, having a central angle of 60°-37'-23" and a radius of 15.00 feet, a distance of 15.87 feet to a point of reverse
    curvature; Running thence along a curve, bearing to the left, having a central angle of 16°-53'-47" and a radius of 145.00 feet, a distance of 42.76 feet to a point of reverse curvature; Running thence along a curve bearing to the right, having a
    central angle of 66°-48'-33" and a radius of 15.00 feet, a distance of 17.49 feet to POINT OR PLACE OF BEGINNING. The area of this parcel is 56,975.79 sq. ft. (1.31 acres) and the total perimeter is 941.56 feet. 3. Notwithstanding the opening paragraph
    and paragraphs one and two of this subdivision, the NTC shall have exclusive use of the parcels described in paragraphs one and two of this subdivision for the U.S. Open Tennis Championships, consisting of up to and including thirty days per year
    for the tournament, qualifying tournament, and for a reasonable amount of time before and after the U.S. Open Tennis Championships for the purpose of setting up and removing any equipment or structures necessary for the tournament.</text>
</level>