<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-120.3</num>
  <heading>Temporary task force on child care funding.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-120.3 Temporary task force on child care funding. a. Not later than thirty days from the effective date of this section as amended, there shall be a temporary task force on child care funding established by the mayor which shall consist of representatives
    of each city agency authorized to license, permit, fund, or otherwise regulate child care facilities or services and such other persons as shall be provided for in this section. City agency representatives to such task force shall include, but shall
    not be limited to, representatives of the human resources administration and the department of health and mental hygiene. The comptroller of the city of New York may designate a representative to serve on such task force. Additional members of such
    task force shall be appointed as follows: five members appointed by the speaker of the council and six, including the chairperson of the task force, by the mayor. Such additional members of the task force shall include, but shall not be limited to,
    representatives of child care providers. The members of the task force, including the chairperson, shall serve without compensation. b. Not later than seven months from the effective date of this section as amended, the temporary task force on child
    care funding shall submit a report to the mayor and the speaker of the council. Such report shall include, but shall not be limited to: (1) identification of the current public and private funding sources for child care facilities and services; (2)
    analysis of the allocation and use of the public funds provided to such child care facilities and services; (3) recommendations to improve the funding of such child care facilities and services; and (4) recommendations to eliminate or reduce the duplication
    and fragmentation of child care services and otherwise enhance the efficiency, effectiveness and economy of service delivery. c. During its deliberations, the task force may invite the participation of child care providers, parents of children enrolled
    in child care programs and not-for-profit child advocacy organizations. To facilitate such deliberations, the task force shall hold a minimum of two public hearings, one of which shall be held in the evening to permit greater parental participation.</text>
</level>