<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-107</num>
  <heading>Replacement of trees.</heading>
  <text>ยง 18-107 Replacement of trees. a. Any person that intends to remove any tree that is within the jurisdiction of the commissioner, shall obtain a permit from the department prior to such removal. b. The department shall charge a fee for each permit issued
    pursuant to this section, which shall be sufficient to cover the cost of replacing any tree proposed to be removed. In applying for a permit pursuant to this section, a person shall specify whether such person intends to plant replacement trees as
    directed by the department or have the department plant replacement trees. If replacement trees are to be planted by the person applying for the permit and are planted as directed by the department, then the department shall return such fee to such
    person upon completion of such planting. In all other cases, the department shall retain such fee for purposes of planting replacement trees. c. Upon determining that a person may be issued a permit pursuant to this section, the department shall inform
    such person in writing of the fee required, the number and size of the replacement trees to be planted, the method used in making these calculations, and the period of time prescribed by subdivision d or f of this section during which replacement
    trees shall be planted. Such information shall be provided to such person not more than ninety days following the filing of a completed application for such permit. d. The location of replacement tree planting and the timing of such planting shall
    be as determined by the department horticultural officer, provided, however, that such replacement shall be made within sixty days after the project is completed or in the next ensuing spring or fall season after the project is completed or earlier
    as agreed by such person and the department. To the extent practicable, replacement trees shall be planted within the same community district from which the trees that were the subject of the permit were removed. e. The department shall promulgate
    such rules as may be necessary to implement the provisions of this section, including but not limited to rules governing the fee to be paid to the department and any method used to calculate the number and size of the replacement trees required to
    be planted, provided that such replacement trees shall, at a minimum, equal one caliper inch of replacement tree for each caliper inch of tree removed. In promulgating such rules, the department shall substantially comply with guidelines set forth
    by the international society of arboriculture. f. The provisions of this section shall apply to all city agencies, including the department, provided, however, that (i) no city agency or city contractor or subcontractor shall be required to pay a
    fee to the department, (ii) a tree site plan shall be developed by the department in consultation with the responsible city agency or agencies regarding the location of replacement trees prior to issuance of the permit, and (iii) replacement of trees
    by any city agency or city contractor or subcontractor shall be made not more than eighteen months from the date the project is completed.</text>
</level>