<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-930</num>
  <heading>Existing standpipes.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-930 Existing standpipes. Standpipe systems existing on December sixth, nineteen hundred sixty-eight shall not be required to be altered to conform to the provisions of this subchapter, except as follows: (a) The existing installation shall meet
    the following minimum requirements: (1) WATER SUPPLIES. There shall be a reserve of at least twenty-five hundred gallons of water in a gravity or pressure tank for exclusive use of the standpipe; or there shall be a direct connection to a city main
    meeting the requirements of section 27-945 of article three of this subchapter. (2) GRAVITY TANKS. The gravity tank or tanks shall be filled by direct city water connection or by an automatic fill pump at a rate of at least forty-five gpm; and the
    bottom of the tank shall be located at least eleven feet six inches above the highest hose outlet under the main roof. (3) HOSE AND HOSE VALVES. Hose and hose valves shall be in good serviceable condition. Hose valve wheel handles shall be within
    six feet six inches of the floors or stair landings or the wheel handle may be within two feet horizontally from a stair tread and no more than six feet six inches vertically above the tread. Such hose may be omitted from hose racks in existing buildings
    in occupancy group J-2 provided that the provisions of paragraph five of subdivision (c) of section 27-942 of article three of this subchapter are complied with. (4) FIRE DEPARTMENT CONNECTIONS. There shall be a three inch by three inch siamese hose
    connection with approved caps, painted red. The word "Standpipe" shall be cast in the body of the siamese connection or on metal plates that are secured to the riser or to the face of the building behind the siamese connection. (5) NOZZLES. A five-eighths
    inch smooth bore nozzle with two and one-half inch hose shall be provided where the hydrostatic pressure at the hose valve is less than ten psig. (6) PROTECTION FROM FREEZING. All parts of the standpipe system that are exposed to freezing shall be
    protected in accordance with the requirements of subdivision (a) of section 27-949 of article three of this subchapter. (7) PRESSURE REDUCING VALVES. Pressure reducing valves shall be provided as required by section 27-944 of article three of this
    subchapter. (8) DRIP VALVES. Drip valves shall be provided between the siamese connection and the check valve. (b) When the building requires additional standpipe protection because of extension in height or in area, or the occupancy is changed to
    a use requiring additional protection, the new or altered part of the system shall comply with this subchapter.</text>
</level>