<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-609</num>
  <heading>Licensed concrete testing laboratories.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-609 Licensed concrete testing laboratories. All strength tests of concrete and testing of concrete materials required by the provisions of this section shall be performed by concrete testing laboratories licensed in accordance with the requirements
    of article nine of subchapter two of chapter one of title twenty-six of the administrative code and rules promulgated by the commissioner. The licensed concrete testing laboratory shall, among other things, analyze, evaluate and test concrete materials;
    determine whether the materials comply with specifications and pertinent referenced national standards in reference standard RS 10-3; select mix proportions for preliminary tests; recommend the mix proportions to be used on the project for which the
    tests were made; analyze data from previous projects and compute the standard deviation; and recommend the mix proportions to be used based on such field experience data. At the batch plant or at the job site, the licensed concrete testing laboratory
    shall, among other things, sample concrete and test for slump, entrained air content, unit weight and temperature, mold compression test specimens; store and cure such specimens on the job site; remove, transport and deliver such specimens to the
    laboratory; demold, store, cure, cap and test such specimens at the laboratory and furnish written reports of the results of all tests of the materials and concrete to the architect or engineer designated for controlled inspection and to the concrete
    producer. When tests of the hardened concrete are required, they shall be made by the licensed concrete testing laboratory in accordance with reference standard RS 10-3 and the national standards for making tests for penetration resistance, rebound
    number, pullout strength and of drilled cores. The architect or engineer designated for controlled inspection is authorized either to dismiss or to employ a particular licensed concrete testing laboratory at any time during the progress of the work.</text>
</level>