<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-801</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-801 Definitions. "Lobbying" or "Lobbying activities" shall mean "lobbying" or "lobbying activities" as defined in section 3-211 of this code. "Person or organization" shall be construed not to include the not-for-profit corporation under contract
    with the city to provide or administer economic development benefits on behalf of the city. ยง 22-802 Reporting of lobbying activities. a. A not-for-profit corporation of which a majority of its members are appointed by the mayor that is under contract
    with the city to provide or administer economic development benefits on behalf of the city shall be required to submit to the council quarterly reports identifying: 1. the contracted entity's retention or designation of a person or organization to
    engage in lobbying or lobbying activities before the council or any member thereof, the city planning commission, a borough president, a borough board or a community board and 2. the contracted entity's making or incurring an expenditure to, or on
    behalf of, a person or organization to engage in lobbying or lobbying activities before the council or any member thereof, the city planning commission, a borough president, a borough board or a community board. b. Such reports need not identify:
    1. any officer or employee of the city of New York or of such contracted entity and 2. any person or organization retained or designated by the contracted entity to provide advice and analysis directly applying any urban planning, urban design, engineering,
    scientific or similar technical discipline, or any legal, accounting, or other similar professional discipline. c. Each report shall set forth: 1. the name, address and telephone number of each person or organization so retained or designated; 2.
    a description of the subject or subjects on which the person or organization lobbied, including identification of the local law, resolution, real property or other matter on which the person or organization lobbied; 3. the person, and where applicable,
    the body before which the person or organization lobbied and the dates on which such lobbying occurred; and 4. the compensation paid or owed by the contacted entity to a person or organization for the purpose of engaging in lobbying or lobbying activities
    before the council or any member thereof, the city planning commission, a borough president, a borough board or a community board and any expenses expended, received or incurred by the person or organization for the purpose of lobbying before such
    bodies. d. The first such submission shall be provided no later than December 31, 2013 and shall cover the period from November 1, 2012 through November 30, 2013. All reports shall be filed thereafter within thirty days after the end of each quarter
    and simultaneously made available in a commonly available non-proprietary database format on the website of the contracted entity or, if no such website is maintained, on the website of the city of New York.</text>
</level>