<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-105</num>
  <heading>The City Record to print certain matters.</heading>
  <text>ยง 23-105 The City Record to print certain matters. a. There shall be published in the City Record, or as a supplement thereto, within the month of April in each year, or maintain as a public record in the municipal reference and research center, a list
    of all officials, employees and laborers of the city who have been or have become officials, employees or laborers during the preceding year. Such list shall contain the name, nature of position or service, year of cessation of service or employment
    (if occurring during the year), salary or wages of each such official, employee or laborer. b. The director shall have power to make requisition in writing upon the heads of agencies to furnish the information necessary to make up the list according
    to the rules prescribed by the director. Such information must be supplied by the agency within ten days after such requisition. c. It shall be the duty of the director, on or before the first day of May in each year, to certify to the comptroller
    that such information has been furnished to him or her by the heads of such agencies, and the comptroller shall withhold payment of the salaries of any such head of agency who has failed to furnish such information. d. All changes of such officials
    or employees, or the amount of their salaries, with a distinct statement of the increase or decrease, shall be published in the City Record within one week after changed or made. The director shall also cause to be printed in each issue of the City
    Record a separate statement of the hours during which all public offices in the city are open for business, and at which each court regularly opens and adjourns, as well as of the places where such offices are kept and such courts are held. e. The
    detailed canvass of votes, at every election, shall be published in the City Record or as a supplement thereto. f. The mayor may order the insertion of any official matter or report in the City Record. g. It shall be the duty of the heads of agencies
    to furnish to the director of the City Record and the director of the municipal reference and research center all information required to be inserted or maintained, respectively, therein.</text>
</level>