<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-528</num>
  <heading>Additional powers of the commission with respect to unlicensed activities.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-528. Additional powers of the commission with respect to unlicensed activities. a. It shall be unlawful for any person required to be licensed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter to engage in any trade, business or activity for which a license
    is required without such license. b. In addition to the enforcement procedures set forth in section 19-506 of this chapter, the commission, after notice and a hearing, shall be authorized: 1. to impose fines upon any person in violation of subdivision
    a of this section of one hundred dollars per violation per day for each and every day during which such person violates such subdivision. 2. to order any person in violation of subdivision a of this section immediately to discontinue such activity
    at the premises from which such activity is occurring. 3. to order that such premises from which such activity is occurring be sealed, provided that such premises are primarily used for such activity. c. Orders of the commission issued pursuant to
    this subdivision shall be posted at the premises from which unlicensed activity occurs in violation of this section. d. Orders of the commission issued pursuant to paragraphs two or three of subdivision b of this section shall be stayed with respect
    to any person who, prior to service of the notice provided in subdivision b of this section, had submitted a full and complete application in proper form and accompanied by the requisite fee for a license or the renewal of a license while such application
    is pending. e. Ten days after the posting of an order issued pursuant to paragraphs two or three of subdivision b of this section and upon the written directive of the commission, officers and employees of the commission and officers of the New York
    city police department are authorized to act upon and enforce such orders. f. The commission shall order that any premises which are sealed pursuant to this section shall be unsealed upon: 1. payment of all outstanding fines; and 2. presentation of
    proof that a license has been obtained for such activity or, if such person or premises are for any reason ineligible to obtain a license, proof satisfactory to the commission that such premises will not be used in violation of this section. g. It
    shall be a misdemeanor for any person to remove the seal on any premises sealed in accordance with an order of the commission. h. The owner or other person lawfully entitled to reclaim the contents of the premises sealed pursuant to this section shall
    reclaim such contents. If such owner or such other person does not reclaim such contents within ninety days of the premises having been sealed, such contents shall be subject to forfeiture upon notice and judicial determination in accordance with
    provisions of law. Upon forfeiture the commission shall, upon a public notice of at least five days, sell such forfeited contents at public sale. The net proceeds of such sale, after deduction of the lawful expenses incurred, shall be paid into the
    general fund of the city.</text>
</level>