<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-410.4.1</num>
  <heading>Experience.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-410.4.1 Experience. All applicants for a master fire suppression piping contractor license shall submit satisfactory proof establishing that the applicant: 1. Has had at least seven years total experience within the 10 years prior to application
    in the design and installation of fire suppression piping systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master fire suppression contractor in the United States with the class of license for which application is made, with at least-two
    years of such experience as a registered journeyman fire suppression piping installer in accordance with the provisions of article 411, except that during the three years immediately following the effective date of this code there shall be no requirement
    for such registered journeyman fire suppression piping installer experience; 2. Has received a bachelor's degree in engineering or appropriate engineering technology from an accredited college or university and has had at least five years total experience
    within the seven years prior to application in the design and installation of fire suppression piping systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master fire suppression piping contractor in the United States for the class of
    license for which application is made, at least two of which were in New York city; 3. Is an architect or engineer with at least three years of experience within the five years prior to application in the design and installation of fire suppression
    piping systems in the United States for the class of license for which application is made, where at least one year of such experience was in New York city; or 4. Has had at least seven years total experience within the 10 years prior to application,
    with at least two years of such experience working in the design and installation of fire suppression piping systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master fire suppression piping contractor in the United States with the
    class of license for which application is made. The balance of such required experience may be obtained by performing maintenance, replacement and repair of fire suppression work on existing buildings while in the employ of a city agency under the
    direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master fire suppression piping contractor supervisor employed by the city agency with the class of license for which application is made. Three years after the effective date of this article the two
    years of experience in the design and installation of fire suppression piping systems set forth above may only be satisfied by working as a registered journeyman fire suppression piping installer. 5. An employee of a government agency, private inspection
    agency or other entity, acceptable to the commissioner, whose duties primarily involve the inspection of plumbing work for compliance with this the New York city plumbing code and/or other laws relating to the installation, alteration or repair of
    fire suppression piping systems shall be credited with fifty percent (50%) of the number of years that he or she has been satisfactorily employed in such duties within the ten (10) year period prior to application, which, however, in no event, shall
    exceed two and one-half (2 1/2) years credit of satisfactory experience. The balance of the required seven years must have been obtained by working in the design and installation of fire suppression piping systems under the direct and continuing supervision
    of a licensed fire suppression piping, contractor in the United States except that the requirement of paragraph 1 of this section 28-410.4.1 that an applicant's working experience must have been within the ten (10) year period prior to application
    shall not apply to such balance of the work experience required pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
</level>