<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-123.2</num>
  <heading>Provision of sprinklers in existing buildings.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-123.2 Provision of sprinklers in existing buildings. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the provisions of section 27-954 of this code shall apply to alterations made to buildings, as well as to changes in occupancy or use, as
    set forth below: (a) The provisions of section 27-954 of this code shall apply to an entire existing building that is being altered, when such building is classified in occupancy group J-2 and will have four or more dwelling units upon the completion
    of the alterations, or is classified in occupancy group J-1, and when the costs of making any alterations to any such J-1 or J-2 building within any twelve-month period exceeds fifty percent of the building value. (b) The provisions of section 27-954
    of this code shall apply to an entire existing building when the occupancy classification of the building will change to a residential occupancy group other than occupancy group J-2 with not more than three dwelling units or occupancy group J-3. (c)
    The provisions of section 27-954 of this code shall apply to any space: (1) when alterations thereto involve a change in the occupancy or use thereof to a residential occupancy group other than occupancy group J-2 with not more than three dwelling
    units or occupancy group J-3, or (2) when the costs of making alterations thereto within any twelve-month period exceeds fifty percent of the value of the space. (d) For the purposes of this section, the cost of making alterations and the value of
    any such building or space shall be determined as set forth in section 27-119 of this chapter; provided, however, that for purposes of this section: (1) the cost of making alterations to a residential building shall be determined based on the aggregate
    cost of alterations to the residential portions of such building, and the value of such a building shall be determined based on the aggregate value of the residential portions of the building, exclusive of the value of any non-residential portions
    of the building; and (2) the cost of making alterations to residential spaces in a non-residential building shall be determined based on the collective cost of alterations to such spaces, and the value of such residential spaces shall be determined
    based on the aggregate value of all such spaces in the building, exclusive of the value of any non-residential portions of the building. (e) When a system of automatic sprinklers is installed in any existing building or space pursuant to this section,
    such system shall comply with the requirements of this code and any other laws and rules applicable to the occupancy group in which such building or space is classified or in which such building or space would be classified if such building or space
    were classified under this chapter.</text>
</level>