<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-202</num>
  <heading>Declaration of policy.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-202 Declaration of policy. It is hereby declared to be the public policy of the city to reduce the ambient sound level in the city, so as to preserve, protect and promote the public health, safety and welfare, and the peace and quiet of the inhabitants
    of the city, prevent injury to human, plant and animal life and property, foster the convenience and comfort of its inhabitants, and facilitate the enjoyment of the natural attractions of the city. It is the public policy of the city that every person
    is entitled to ambient sound levels that are not detrimental to life, health and enjoyment of his or her property. It is hereby declared that the making, creation or maintenance of excessive and unreasonable noises within the city affects and is a
    menace to public health, comfort, convenience, safety, welfare and the prosperity of the people of the city. For the purpose of controlling and reducing such noises, it is hereby declared to be the policy of the city to set the unreasonable and prohibited
    noise standards and decibel levels contained herein and to consolidate certain of its noise control legislation into this code. The necessity for legislation by enactment of the provisions of this chapter is hereby declared as a matter of legislative
    determination. This code shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes described in this section. Nothing herein shall be construed to abridge the emergency powers of the board of health or the right of the department of health and
    mental hygiene to engage in any of its necessary or proper activities. It is the intent of the council that the police department as well as other agencies of the city designated by the commissioner of the department of environmental protection shall
    have the authority to enforce the provisions of this code and police officers and designated employees of the department of environmental protection and of such other city agencies shall have the power to issue summonses, appearance tickets and notices
    of violation for violations of this code.</text>
</level>