<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-419</num>
  <heading>Enclosure.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-419 Enclosure. Boilers or furnaces hereafter installed in any building, other than replacement boilers and furnaces and boilers or furnaces used to heat one- or two-family dwellings, shall be enclosed and separated from the rest of the building
    by noncombustible construction having at least a one hour fire-resistance rating, except that: (a) All boilers carrying more than fifteen psi pressure and having a rating in excess of ten horsepower, shall be located in a room or compartment separated
    from the rest of the building by noncombustible construction having at least a two hour fire-resistance rating. (b) Boilers or furnaces located adjacent to, or within, automotive repair shops, public garages (group 1), or any occupancy classified
    in high hazard occupancy group A shall be located in separate buildings or, in rooms enclosed by noncombustible construction having at least a two hour fire-resistance rating. Entrance to such enclosed rooms shall be from the outdoors, or through
    an intervening vestibule constructed of materials having a two hour fire-resistance. rating. The floor area of such vestibules shall be at least fifty square feet, but not more than seventy-five square feet. Ventilation shall be provided by a louver
    permanently open to the outdoor air having a net free area of one hundred forty-four square inches, located near the floor. Vestibule doors shall be one and one-half hour self-closing fire doors, with a six inch high sill provided at the door between
    the vestibule and the boiler room. Both doors shall swing in the direction of the boiler room. (c) Boilers having a rated gross capacity of less than sixty-seven thousand btu per hour for generating steam shall not be required to be enclosed, except
    as provided in subdivision (b) of this section. (d) Electric or fuel-fired space heaters need not be enclosed when they are approved for installation without enclosure and are installed in accordance with the conditions of approval. (e) Boilers and
    furnaces used in conjunction with commercial and industrial processes need not be enclosed, subject to the approval of the commissioner.</text>
</level>