<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-793</num>
  <heading>Boilers.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-793 Boilers. (a) Acceptance tests. Boilers shall not be placed in operation upon completion of construction until they have been inspected and tested and an equipment use permit has been issued by the commissioner. All final inspections and tests
    for boilers shall be subject to the provisions for controlled inspection as provided in subchapter one of this chapter, except that such inspections and tests shall be made by a qualified boiler inspector in the employ of the department or a duly
    authorized insurance company as provided in section two hundred four of the labor law. Equipment having a Btu input of not more than three hundred fifty thousand Btu per hour shall be exempt from this requirement. (b) Periodic boiler inspections.
    (1) Except as provided in paragraph two of this subdivision, all boilers, as defined in section two hundred four of the labor law, excepting those boilers listed in subdivision five of such section of the labor law, shall be inspected at least once
    a year by duly authorized insurance companies or other qualified inspectors in the manner set forth in rules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner. Such inspections shall also include the chimney connectors described in article three of
    subchapter fifteen of this chapter. All boiler inspectors who perform periodic inspections pursuant to this subdivision shall be qualified under section two hundred four of the labor law and rules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner of
    labor. (2) Each owner of a high-pressure boiler, as defined in sections 26-160 and 27-795 of this code, may choose to have the annual boiler inspection conducted by the department or by a duly authorized insurance company. (c) Owners annual statement.
    (1) The owner of each boiler that is subject to periodic inspection shall file an annual written statement with the commissioner, specifying: a. The location of each boiler. b. Whether or not the owner, agent, or lessee has had the boiler inspected
    by a duly authorized insurance company or other qualified inspector in accordance with the requirements of subdivision (b) of this section, setting forth the name and address of the insurance company or other qualified inspector, the date of inspection,
    and the policy number covering the boiler. (2) If the periodic boiler inspection has been performed by a duly authorized insurance company or other qualified inspector pursuant to subdivision (b) of this section, the annual statement shall be accompanied
    by a signed copy of the report of each boiler inspection, on such forms and in such manner as required by the commissioner. (3) The statement shall be filed within thirty days after installation of a boiler. Thereafter, it shall be filed on or before
    the last day of December of the year of each annual inspection. (d) Removal or discontinuance notice. The owner of a boiler that is removed or discontinued from use shall file a written notice of such removal or discontinuance with the commissioner
    within thirty days of the date of removal or discontinuance. (e) Failure to file statements and notices. If an owner of a boiler shall fail to file any statement or notice required under this section, such owner shall be liable for a civil penalty
    pursuant to section 26-125 of this code. (f) Additional inspections. In addition to the inspections required by subdivisions (a) and (b) of this section, the commissioner may make such additional inspections as required to enforce the provisions of
    this code. No fee shall be charged for such additional inspections. (g) Fees. Every owner of a boiler in use and inspected by a duly authorized insurance company shall pay to the department an annual fee for each boiler in the amount prescribed by
    section 26-213 of title twenty-six of the administrative code to cover the city's administrative and supervisory costs involved. The fee shall be payable at the time of the filing of the statement required by this subdivision.</text>
</level>