<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-704</num>
  <heading>Notice of rights and responsibilities.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-704 Notice of rights and responsibilities. a. The agency shall inform applicants, recipients and participants of all rights, entitlements and agency obligations required under this chapter. b. Any notice directing an applicant, recipient or participant
    to report for an assessment, the development of an employability plan, or a work-related assignment, shall contain a description of the rights to pursue education and training activities as set forth in this chapter, and shall contain the following
    statement: "Your Education and Training Rights When you come for your appointment, we will tell you about your rights to participate in education and training programs. The hours you spend in education and training programs may count toward your work
    requirement. A Master List of Programs You have a right to receive the complete "HRA Consolidated Master List of Approved Training Programs." This is a list of education and training programs you can choose to go to. Hours spent in any program on
    that list will count toward your work requirement. Other Choices for Training and Education You can also go to education or training programs that are not on the Consolidated Master List. However, those programs must meet appropriate City or State
    standards. Time To Find the Right Program for You If you need to participate in an education or training program in order to improve your chances of getting a job, we must give you 15 business days before your assessment, upon your request, to find
    an appropriate education or training program. If You Are Already In an Education or Training Program If you are already in school we must allow you to remain in your program as long as your program appears on the "HRA Consolidated Master List of Approved
    Training Programs" or meets the City or State standards mentioned above. Reassessment If you are dissatisfied with the work activity to which you have been assigned for six months or more and you believe that you are eligible to attend education or
    training, you should request a reassessment of your employability. If you are found to be eligible to attend a training or education program, you can switch into an education or training program. Again, your choice must appear on the "HRA Consolidated
    Master List of Approved Training Programs" or meet appropriate City or State standards. If you are already in a work activity, you do not have a 15 business day period to find an education or training program. In this case, you must continue in your
    work activity while you look for an education or training program. Your Right to a Fair Hearing The agency must give you a copy of your employability plan. You have a right to a fair hearing to challenge your assignment."</text>
</level>