<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>25-202</num>
  <heading>Fees.</heading>
  <text>ยง 25-202 Fees. The fees hereinbelow set forth shall be charged for the following applications, appeals, filings and reviews: 1. Zoning variances. Application for any variance under the zoning resolution with respect to: a. (1) Individually owned one
    and two family dwellings: $ 1,100.00. (2) Individually owned three family dwellings: $ 1,700.00. b. Other buildings and structures (fee schedule applicable to square footage involved in application), and junk yards, parking lots, automotive service
    stations and other similar uses (fee schedule applicable to lot area involved in application). (1) 10,000 square feet or less of floor area or lot area: $ 3,950.00. (2) In excess of 10,000 but not more than 20,000 square feet of floor area or lot
    area: $ 5,480.00. (3) In excess of 20,000 but not more than 40,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 7,040.00. (4) In excess of 40,000 but not more than 70,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 8,560.00. (5) In excess of 70,000 but not
    more than 100,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 10,100.00. (6) In excess of 100,000 square feet of floor area: $10,100.00 for the first 100,000 square feet of floor area plus 5.0% of square footage in units of 10,000 square feet above 100,000
    square feet of floor area. (7) In excess of 100,000 square feet of lot area: $ 11,200.00. c. All other applications for any zoning variance under the zoning resolution not subject to paragraph a or b of this subdivision: $ 5,480.00. 2. Zoning special
    permits. Application for any special permit under the zoning resolution with respect to: a. (1) Individually owned one and two family dwellings: $ 1,000.00. (2) Individually owned three family dwellings: $ 1,570.00. b. Other buildings and structures
    (fee schedule applicable to square footage involved in application), and junk yards, parking lots, automotive service stations and other similar uses (fee schedule applicable to lot area involved in application): (1) 10,000 square feet or less of
    floor area or lot area: $ 2,960.00. (2) In excess of 10,000 but not more than 20,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 4,130.00. (3) In excess of 20,000 but not more than 40,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 5,280.00. (4) In excess
    of 40,000 but not more than 70,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 6,430.00. (5) In excess of 70,000 but not more than 100,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $ 7,580.00. (6) In excess of 100,000 square feet of floor area: $7,580.00
    for the first 100,000 square feet of floor area plus 5.0% of square footage in units of 10,000 square feet above 100,000 square feet of floor area. (7) In excess of 100,000 square feet of lot area: $ 8,400.00. c. Application for any special permit
    under the zoning resolution not subject to paragraph a or b of this subdivision: $ 4,130.00. 3. Special order calendar. a. Application to reargue or rehear an application pursuant to the rules of practice and procedure of the board of standards and
    appeals: $1,850.00. b. Application for amendment of a variance or special permit previously granted under the zoning resolution with respect to: (1) Individually owned one and two family dwellings: $440.00. (2) Individually owned three family dwellings:
    $920.00. (3) All other developments: $2,110.00. c. Application for an extension of time: (1) To obtain a certificate of occupancy pursuant to a resolution of the board of standards and appeals: $1,200.00. (2) To complete construction pursuant to section
    72-23 or 73-70 of the zoning resolution: $1,200.00. d. Application for extension of term of a variance or special permit previously granted under the zoning resolution with respect to individually owned one, two or three family dwellings, other buildings
    and structures (fee schedule applicable to square footage involved in application), and junkyards, parking lots, automotive service stations and other similar uses (fee schedule applicable to lot area involved in application): (1) Individually owned
    one, two or three family dwellings: $550.00. (2) 10,000 square feet or less of floor area or lot area: $2,370.00. (3) In excess of 10,000 but not more than 20,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $3,290.00. (4) In excess of 20,000 but not more
    than 40,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $4,220.00. (5) In excess of 40,000 but not more than 70,000 square feet of floor area or lot area: $5,140.00. (6) In excess of 70,000 but not more than 100,000 square feet of floor area or lot area:
    $6,060.00. (7) In excess of 100,000 square feet of floor area: $6,060.00 for the first 100,000 square feet of floor area plus 5.0% of square footage in units of 10,000 square feet above 100,000 square feet of floor area. (8) In excess of 100,000 square
    feet of lot area: $6,720.00. (9) All other applications: $ 3,290.00. e. Application to waive the rules of practice and procedure of the board of standards and appeals when: (1) Application to extend time to complete construction is filed one year
    or less after the permitted filing period: $660.00. (2) Application to extend time to complete construction is filed more than one year after the permitted filing period: $920.00. (3) Application to extend the term of a previously issued variance,
    special permit or appeal is filed one year or less be after the permitted filing period: $1,180.00. (4) Application to extend the term of a previously issued variance, special permit or appeal, is filed between one and two years after the permitted
    filing period: $1,850.00. (5) Application to extend the term of a previously issued variance, special permit or appeal, is filed more than two years after the permitted filing period: $2,630.00. (6) Application to extend the term of a previously issued
    variance, special permit or appeal, is filed more than ten years after the permitted filing period: $5,000. f. Application for minor amendment that is in substantial compliance with previous grant: $ 930.00. 4. Appeals. a. Application to waive section
    thirty-five or thirty-six of the general city law with respect to: (1) One, two and three family residences, per building permit: $790.00. (2) All other residences, per building permit: $1,540.00. (3) All other buildings and properties, per building
    permit: $1,980.00. b. Appeal from or application for review of any order, requirement or determination of the commissioner of buildings or of any borough superintendent of the department of buildings or of the fire commissioner or any rule or regulation
    or amendment or repeal thereof made by the fire commissioner or the commissioner of small business services with respect to: (1) One, two and three family residences, per building permit: $1,260.00. (2) All other residences, per building permit: $2,460.00.
    (3) All other buildings and properties, per building permit: $3,160.00. c. Application to vest building permit under the common law doctrine of vested rights with respect to: (1) One, two and three family residences, per building permit: $940.00.
    (2) All other residences, per building permit: $2,460.00. (3) All other buildings and properties, per building permit: $3,160.00. d. Application for amendment of prior approval of appeals from or application for review of any order, requirement or
    determination of the commissioner of buildings or of any borough superintendent of the department of buildings or of the fire commissioner or any rule or regulation or amendment or repeal thereof made by the fire commissioner or the commissioner of
    small business services with respect to: (1) One, two and three family residences: $920.00. (2) All other developments: $2,110.00 5. Application for extension of period to complete construction pursuant to section 11-33 of the zoning resolution: a.
    One, two and three family residences, per building permit: $940.00. b. All other residences, per building permit: $ 3,690.00. c. All other buildings and properties, per building permit: $ 4,740.00. 6. Exemptions. The provisions of this section shall
    not apply if a municipal department or agency of the city is the applicant or appellant before the board of standards and appeals. 7. Other. Request to obtain off-site file of previous applications to the board of standards and appeals: $50.00.</text>
</level>