<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-678</num>
  <heading>Allowable soil bearing pressures.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-678 Allowable soil bearing pressures. The allowable bearing pressures on satisfactory bearing materials shall be those established in table 11-2. The allowable bearing pressures on nominally unsatisfactory bearing materials shall be those established
    in accordance with section 27-679 of this article. Allowable bearing pressure shall be considered to be the allowable pressure at a point in the soil mass in excess of the stabilized overburden pressure existing at the same point prior to construction
    operations. The stabilized overburden pressure existing at a point shall be defined as that portion of the weight of the overlying soil material that is supported by granular interaction rather than pore pressure. In general, the magnitude of the
    stabilized overburden pressure may be approximated as follows: (a) The overlying soil material shall have been in place for an adequate length of time to produce a stable condition of pore pressure in, or below the foundation level. Where the bearing
    stratum consists of soils of classes 5-65 through 8-65, the bearing stratum shall be considered to be fully consolidated except with regard to the weight of that portion of the overlying soil material that consists of added fill material. (b) Where
    all or a portion of the overlying soil consists of fill material, the weight of the fill material shall not be included in the stabilized overburden pressure unless the magnitude of stabilized pressure is verified by an architect or engineer on the
    basis of laboratory or field tests on undisturbed material. (c) Where the bearing stratum consists of soils of classes 9-65 through 11-65, the stabilized overburden pressure shall be considered as zero unless the magnitude of the stabilized pressure
    is established by an architect or engineer on the basis of laboratory or field tests on undisturbed material. (d) The stabilized overburden pressure shall not include the weight of any soil removed by excavation and not replaced. For footings, the
    total stabilized overburden pressure shall not exceed the weight of a one square foot column of soil (considering submerged weight where the soil column is partly submerged) measured from the bottom of the footing to the lowest level of the final
    grade above the footing. For a box foundation, where the strength of the slab is adequate to stabilize the underlying soil, the stabilized overburden pressure shall not exceed the weight of a one square foot column of soil measured from the bottom
    of the box to the lowest level of the adjacent grade. (e) Where the bearing stratum consists of soils of classes 9-65 through 11-65, the allowable bearing pressure shall be adjusted for the effects of rebound due to excavation as determined from consolidation
    test data. (f) Where the bearing stratum consists of rock of classes 1-65 through 3-65, the stabilized overburden pressure shall be neglected. Table 11-2 Allowable Soil Bearing Pressures ========================================================================
    Basic Allowable Bearing Values Class of Description (Tons per sq. ft.)--See Notes Material See Notes (1) (10), (11) and (12) ------------------------------------------------------------------------ 1-65 Hard Sound Rock 60 See Notes (2) and (8). 2-65
    Medium Hard Rock 40 See Notes (2) and (8). 3-65 Intermediate Rock 20 See Notes (2) and (8). 4-65 Soft Rock 8 5-65 Hardpan -- See Notes (3) and (8). 6-65 Gravel and Gravel Soils (Soil Groups, GW, GP, GM &amp; GC and soils of Soil Groups SW, SP, and
    SM containing more than 10% of material retained on a No. 4 sieve) -- See Notes (4) and (8) and (9). 7-65 Sands (other than Fine Sands) (Soil Groups SW, SP &amp; SM but containing not more than 10% of material retained on a No. 4 sieve) -- See Notes
    (5), (8) and (9). 8-65 Fine sand -- See Notes (6), (8) and (9). 9-65 Clays and Clay Soils (Soil Groups SC, CL &amp; CH) Hard 5 See Note (7). Medium 2 See Note (7). Soft See Sec. 27-679. 10-65 Silts and Silt Soils (Soil Groups ML &amp; MH) Dense 3
    Medium 1.5 Loose See Sec. 27-679. 11-65 Nominally Unsatisfactory Bear- ing Materials See Sec. 27-679. ======================================================================== Notes: (1) Classification. The soil classifications indicated in this table
    are those described in section 27-675 of this article. Where there is doubt as to the applicable classification of a soil stratum, the allowable bearing pressure applicable to the lower class of material to which the given stratum might conform shall
    apply unless the conformance to the higher class of material can be proven by laboratory or field test procedures. (2) Allowable bearing pressure on rock. The tabulated values of basic allowable bearing pressures apply only for massive rocks or, for
    sedimentary or foliated rocks, where the strata are level or nearly so, and, then only if the area has ample lateral support. Tilted strata and their relation to nearby slopes or excavations shall receive special consideration. (3) Allowable bearing
    pressure on hardpan. For hardpan consisting of well cemented material composed of a predominantly granular matrix and free of lenses of fine grained material and inclusions of soft rock, the basic allowable bearing pressure shall be twelve tons per
    square foot. For hardpan consisting of poorly cemented material or containing lenses of fine grained material, inclusions of soft rock, or a fine grained matrix, the basic allowable bearing pressure shall be eight tons per square foot. (4) Allowable
    bearing pressure on gravel and gravel soils. Values of basic allowable bearing pressure shall be as follows: (a) For soils of Soil Groups GW, GP, GM, and GC: Compact, well graded material--ten tons per square foot. Loose, poorly graded material--six
    tons per square foot. Intermediate conditions--Estimate by interpolation between indicated extremes. (b) For soils of Soil Groups SW, SP, and SM, containing more than ten percent of material retained on a No. 4 sieve: Compact, well graded material--eight
    tons per square foot. Loose, poorly graded material--four tons per square foot. Intermediate conditions--Estimate by interpolation between indicated extremes. (5) Allowable bearing pressure on sands. The basic allowable bearing pressure shall be determined
    from the resistance to penetration of the standard sampling spoon. The basic allowable bearing pressure in tons per square foot shall equal 0.10 times N but not greater than six tons per square foot, nor less than three tons per square foot. The appropriate
    value for the penetration resistance at various areas of the site shall be made by averaging the measured resistance within a depth of soil below the proposed footing level equal to the width of the footing. Where the average values so obtained do
    not vary by more than twenty-five percent of the minimum of the average values over the site of the proposed building, the lowest average value shall be used for the design of the entire building. Where the variation exceeds twenty-five percent, the
    allowable bearing pressure shall be predicated on the lowest average value unless appropriate measures are taken to avoid detrimental amounts of differential settlements of the footings. Where the design bearing pressure on soils of class 7-65 exceeds
    three tons per square foot, the embedment of the loaded area below the adjacent grade shall not be less than four feet and the width of the loaded area not less than three feet, unless analysis shall demonstrate the proposed construction to have a
    minimum factor of safety of 2.0 against shear failure of the soil. (6) Allowable bearing pressure on fine sand. The basic allowable bearing pressure shall be determined from the resistance to penetration of the standard sampling spoon. The basic allowable
    bearing pressure in tons per square foot shall equal 0.10 times N but not greater than four tons per square foot nor less than two tons per square foot, except that, for loose materials (resistance to penetration of the standard sampling spoon ten
    blows per foot or less), where the foundation is subjected to vibratory loads from machinery or similar cause, the indicated basic values shall not apply. The allowable bearing pressure shall be established by analysis applying accepted principles
    of soil mechanics and a report of such analysis satisfactory to the commissioner shall be submitted as a part of the application for the acceptance of the plans. (7) Allowable bearing pressure on clays and clay soils. The bearing capacity of medium
    and hard clays and clay soils shall be established on the basis of the strength of such soils as determined by field or laboratory tests and shall provide a factor of safety against failure of the soil of not less than 2.0 computed on the basis of
    a recognized procedure of soils analysis, shall consider probable settlements of the building, and shall not exceed the tabulated maximum values. (8) Increases in allowable bearing pressure due to embedment of the foundation. (a) The basic allowable
    bearing values for rock of classes 1-65, 2-65 and 3-65 shall apply where the loaded area is on the surface of sound rock. Where the loaded area is below the adjacent rock surface and is fully confined by the adjacent rock mass and provided that the
    rock mass has not been shattered by blasting or otherwise is or has been rendered unsound, these values may be increased ten percent of the base value for each foot of embedment below the surface of the adjacent rock surface in excess of one foot,
    but shall not exceed twice the basic values. (b) The basic allowable bearing values for soils of classes 5-65 through 8-65 determined in accordance with notes three, four and five above, shall apply where the loaded area is embedded four feet or less
    in the bearing stratum. Where the loaded area is embedded more than four feet below the adjacent surface of the bearing stratum, and is fully confined by the weight of the adjacent soil, these values may be increased five percent of the base value
    for each foot of additional embedment, but shall not exceed twice the basic values. Increases in allowable bearing pressure due to embedment shall not apply to soils of classes 4-65, 9-65, 10-65, or 11-65. (9) Increase in allowable bearing pressure
    for limited depth of bearing stratum: The allowable bearing values for soils of classes 6-65, 7-65 and 8-65 determined in accordance with this table and the notes thereto (including note eight), may be increased up to one-third where the density of
    the bearing stratum below the bottom of the footings or the tips of the piles increases with depth provided that: (a) The bearing stratum is not underlain by materials of a lower class. (b) The allowable bearing value of the soil material underlying
    the bottom of the footings or the tips of the piles increases at least fifty percent within a depth below the footing or the tips of the piles which is not greater than the width of the footing or the width of the polygon circumscribing the pile group.
    (c) It shall be demonstrated by a recognized means of analysis that the probable settlement of the foundation due to compression, and/or consolidation do not exceed acceptable limits for the proposed building. (10) Combination of loads. The provisions
    of section 27-594 of article two of subchapter ten of this chapter shall apply. (11) Correction for foundations bearing on materials of varying bearing capacities. Where it is shown by borings or otherwise that materials of varying bearing value will
    be used for support of a building: (1) Where the weakest material does not rank below class 5-65, no modifications shall be required. (2) Where the weakest materials rank as classes 6-65 through 8-65, if the difference in basic allowable bearing values
    for the several materials does not exceed thirty percent of the allowable value for the poorest material which is to support the foundation, the foundations may be proportioned in direct conformance with the allowable bearing pressures. Where the
    difference in basic allowable bearing values exceeds thirty percent, appropriate measures shall be taken to limit the differential settlements of the different portions of the structure to tolerable values. (3) For materials of classes 9-65 and 10-65,
    in all cases, appropriate measures shall be taken to equalize the settlements of the different portions of the structure. (12) Inundated footings. The provisions of this section relating to materials of classes 1-65 through 7-65, shall be deemed equally
    applicable both to the dry and to the inundated condition of the soil provided: (a) That the subgrade is undisturbed by the construction operations, (b) The bearing area is in a confined condition. For such cases, no reduction in allowable bearing
    value will be required where the soil supporting the foundation is subject to a rising level of inundation. However, the effects on settlement of a falling level of inundation occurring after construction of the foundation shall be considered in the
    design.</text>
</level>