<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-145</num>
  <heading>Emission of particulate matter from refuse burning equipment and fuel burning equipment; weight-rate standard.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-145 Emission of particulate matter from refuse burning equipment and fuel burning equipment; weight-rate standard. (a) No person shall cause or permit the emission of particulate matter from refuse burning equipment and fuel burning equipment if
    the emission from such equipment is in violation of the provisions of section 24-141 or 24-142 of this code or if the particulate matter emitted as measured in the flue exceeds the following limits: (1) In refuse burning equipment, the permissible
    particulate rate shall be as provided in figure four of section 24-153 of this code. If two or more refuse burning units are connected to a single flue, the total capacity rating of all refuse burning units connected to the flue shall be the capacity
    rating for the purpose of computing the amount of particulate matter which may be emitted. If a single refuse burning unit is manifold to two or more flues the capacity rating of the single refuse burning unit shall be the capacity rating for the
    purpose of computing the amount of particulate matter which may be emitted; (2) In fuel burning equipment in which the preponderance of the particulate matter emitted is caused by the burning of fuel, 0.40 pounds for each million Btu per hour input
    if the equipment has a capacity rating of ten million Btu per hour or less. If the capacity rating of the fuel burning equipment is more than ten million Btu per hour, the amount of permissible emissions of particulate matter shall be as provided
    in figure three of section 24-153 of this code, as measured on a dry basis. (b) If two or more fuel burning units are connected to a single flue, the total capacity rating of all fuel burning units connected to the flue shall be the capacity rating
    for the purpose of computing the amount of particulate matter which may be emitted. If a single fuel burning unit is manifold to two or more flues the capacity rating of the single fuel burning unit shall be the capacity rating for the purpose of
    computing the amount of particulate matter which may be emitted.</text>
</level>