<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-116.2.3</num>
  <heading>Special inspections and other inspections required during the progress of work.</heading>
  <text>ยง 28-116.2.3 Special inspections and other inspections required during the progress of work. After the issuance of a work permit, special inspections and other inspections required by this code to be made during the progress of the work shall be made
    at such times or at such stages of the work and in such manner as shall be provided by this code or as otherwise required by the commissioner. The permit application shall set forth an inspection program for the job. Such inspections may be made by
    approved agencies or by the department as provided in this code or in the rules of the department. Special inspections shall be performed only by individuals who are special inspectors. The permit holder shall notify the relevant special inspectors
    in writing at least 72 hours prior to the commencement of any work requiring special inspection. The commissioner may accept inspection and test reports from approved agencies and special inspectors and the work may, unless otherwise specifically
    provided by code provisions or directed by the commissioner, proceed without any verifying inspection or test by the department. The names and business addresses of special inspectors and approved agencies shall be set forth in the work permit application.
    All inspection reports shall be in writing and signed by the person or entity performing the inspection. A record of all inspections shall be kept by the person performing the inspection. The commissioner may require inspection reports to be filed
    with the department. Records of inspections made by approved agencies and special inspectors shall be maintained by such persons for a period of six years after sign-off of the job or for such other period of time as the commissioner may require and
    shall be made available to the department upon request.</text>
</level>