<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-260</num>
  <heading>Rates of pedicabs.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-260. Rates of pedicabs. a. Rates for pedicab rides shall be based on time calculated per minute per ride. Each pedicab driver shall make such calculation using the timer affixed to the pedicab pursuant to paragraph 12 of subdivision a of section
    20-254 of this subchapter. Each pedicab driver shall activate such timer when all passengers are seated and the pedicab ride commences, and shall stop the timer when the pedicab has reached its destination and the pedicab is at a full stop. 1. It
    shall be unlawful for a pedicab driver to charge any added fee, including fees for additional passengers. 2. Each minute shall be charged at the same rate. 3. Rates shall be displayed on the exterior of the pedicab and the rear of the bike seat on
    the pedicab pursuant to paragraphs 14 and 15 of subdivision a of section 20-254 of this subchapter at all times. b. It shall be unlawful for a pedicab driver to charge a passenger a higher rate than the rate displayed on the pedicab pursuant to paragraphs
    14 and 15 of subdivision a of section 20-254 of this subchapter. c. Pedicab Information Card. 1. The department shall create a pedicab information card in a size and style to be determined by the commissioner that states in substance: (i) all pedicabs
    shall display a sign disclosing the price to be charged per minute per ride on the exterior of the pedicab and the rear of the bike seat of the pedicab; (ii) drivers are not permitted to charge tax; (iii) gratuity is not required; (iv) it shall be
    unlawful for a pedicab driver to charge any added fee, including fees for additional passengers; (v) passengers may call 311 if they have a complaint regarding a pedicab driver or business; and (vi) such additional information as required by the commissioner.
    Each such document shall include an area where each pedicab driver shall insert: (i) his or her name and pedicab driver's license number, which shall be clearly identified as a New York city department of consumer affairs license number; (ii) the
    pedicab business name, address, telephone number and pedicab business license number, which shall be clearly identified as a New York city department of consumer affairs license number; (iii) the rate per ride as indicated on the exterior of the pedicab
    and the rear of the bike seat of the pedicab pursuant to paragraphs 14 and 15 of subdivision a of section 20-254 of this subchapter; (iv) the date; (v) the total number of minutes and/or fraction of a minute of the pedicab ride; and (vi) the total
    charge of the pedicab ride. 2. Such pedicab information card shall be distributed to every pedicab driver licensed pursuant to section 20-257 of this subchapter by the department in a manner to be determined by the commissioner. 3. Before a passenger
    enters a pedicab, the driver shall provide such passenger with the information card required by paragraph one of this subdivision with the following information inserted by the driver: (i) the driver's name and pedicab driver's license number; (ii)
    the pedicab business name, address, telephone number and pedicab business license number; and (iii) the rate per ride as indicated on the exterior of the pedicab and the rear of the bike seat of the pedicab pursuant to paragraphs 14 and 15 of subdivision
    a of section 20-254 of this subchapter. At the conclusion of the pedicab ride, the driver shall enter the following information on the information card: (i) the date; (ii) the total number of minutes and/or fraction of a minute of the pedicab ride;
    and (iii) the total charge of the pedicab ride. The driver shall then return the information card to the passenger.</text>
</level>