<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-804</num>
  <heading>Education and outreach.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-804 Education and outreach. a. No later than July 1, 2009, the office shall develop and implement programs for public education and outreach regarding global warming and the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions by residents, businesses, public
    and private elementary and secondary schools, and other entities within the city of New York. Such program shall include, but not be limited to, awareness campaigns tailored to specific sectors of the public, through which the office shall develop
    and disseminate information regarding global warming, including its potential impacts on the city of New York, and best practices to reduce energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions. b. The New York city renewable energy portal. 1. The office
    shall develop and administer an interactive website called the New York city renewable energy portal. A link to the renewable energy portal shall be prominently displayed on the website of the department of buildings and any other city agency website
    that pertains to sustainable growth or environmental policy. 2. The purpose of the renewable energy portal shall be to effectively inform the public about the feasibility and economic viability of installing renewable energy systems in the city of
    New York. Content on the website shall be written in plain language whenever possible and shall include, but not be limited to, information on solar photovoltaic panels, solar water heaters, geothermal heat pumps, and leadership in energy and environmental
    design (LEED) certification. Links featured on the website shall be verified on a quarterly basis. 3. The renewable energy portal shall have or link to, to the extent they are available, programs that allow the user to calculate the estimated costs
    and benefits of renewable energy systems, lists of financial incentives available at the federal, state, and local levels, and tools and guidelines to evaluate the feasibility of installing renewable energy technologies. 4. The renewable energy portal
    shall assist users in determining which city, state, and federal agencies, if any, must approve a prospective installation of renewable energy systems. The renewable energy portal shall link to the website of any city, state, or federal agency that
    must be contacted in connection with the installation of renewable energy systems, and may also link to any forms, if they are available online, that such agency may require of prospective installers of renewable energy systems. 5. The renewable energy
    portal shall list the qualifications required for any contractor to perform installations of renewable energy systems within the city of New York. 6. Nothing within this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the office to create additional
    resources within the renewable energy portal.</text>
</level>