<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-672</num>
  <heading>Placards to be posted.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-672 Placards to be posted. a. Except as provided in subdivision five of section one hundred ninety-two of the agriculture and markets law, it shall be unlawful for any person, in connection with the sale or offer for sale at retail of any petroleum
    products for use in motor vehicles or motor boats, other than gasoline or diesel motor fuel, to post or maintain at such place of sale or offer to sale, any sign, placard or other display that states, relates or refers to the price at which such petroleum
    products are sold or offered for sale, except as follows: 1. The price stated, mentioned or referred to on such sign, placard or other display, shall be by the unit of the measure at which such petroleum products are customarily sold at retail. 2.
    The name, trade name, brand, mark or symbol, and grade or quality classification, if any, and method of processing of such petroleum products shall be clearly stated on such signs, placard or other display, and, if such petroleum products are sold
    without identification by name, trade name, brand, mark or symbol, such sign, placard or other display shall refer clearly to such petroleum products as unbranded. b. In addition to any sign or placard required pursuant to subdivision five of section
    one hundred ninety-two of the agriculture and markets law, there shall be a sign, poster or placard clearly visible to drivers of approaching motor vehicles on the premises of every location at which gasoline and/or diesel motor fuel are sold or offered
    for sale. Such sign shall be in a size and style to be determined by the commissioner. Such sign, in addition to any other sign, poster or placard that advertises the selling price of gasoline and directly or indirectly refers to a premises where
    the advertised gasoline and/or diesel motor fuel are sold or offered for sale, shall state the name, trade name, brand, mark or symbol and grade or quality classification of such gasoline or diesel motor fuel, together with the total selling price
    per gallon. Total selling price shall be the sum of the basic price per gallon plus all applicable taxes. Such sign, poster or placard shall conform to the rules and regulations of all governmental agencies with jurisdiction as to structure and location.
    1. A retail dealer shall only sell at the total selling price. Any such price when posted may not be raised for a period of not less than twenty-four hours. 2. Where the total selling price for purchases made with cash is less than the total selling
    price for purchases made with credit card, debit card or other form of non-cash payment, such sign, poster or placard shall state the total selling price for each type of accepted payment. c. All numbers referring to price shall be the same height,
    width and thickness. Identification of the gasoline or diesel motor fuel offered for sale, and any non-numerical language distinguishing the total cash selling price from the total credit card, debit card or other form of non-cash payment selling
    price shall be in letters and numbers not less than one-half of the height, width and thickness of the numbers referring to price. Letters and numbers shall be black on a white background. d. Price per gallon indicator. Except as otherwise provided
    in article sixteen of the agriculture and markets law or in any rule or regulations promulgated thereunder, every gasoline or diesel motor fuel dispensing device shall be equipped with a price per gallon indicator and shall have such indicator correspond
    with the total price per gallon on the sign, poster or placard required to be posted pursuant to subdivision five of section one hundred ninety-two of such law or subdivision b of this section. e. Total price indicator. Every gasoline or diesel motor
    fuel dispensing device shall be equipped with a total delivery indicator, and such indicator shall record the correct total price computed on the basis of posted price per gallon and number of gallons delivered. f. Notwithstanding the foregoing, subdivisions
    a, b and c of this section shall not apply to the posting of information and labeling of dispensing devices with respect to the lead content of gasoline for motor vehicles, which shall be governed by the provisions of subdivision d and e of section
    20-673.1 of this subchapter and any rules or regulations promulgated thereunder, and subdivisions a, b and c of this section shall not apply to the posting of information and labeling of dispensing devices with respect to the octane rating of gasoline
    for motor vehicles, which shall be governed by the provisions of subdivision d of section 20-673.2 of this subchapter and any rules or regulations promulgated thereunder.</text>
</level>