<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-848.03</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-848.03 Definitions. As used in this article, the following terms shall have the following meaning: Accessories, factory-built. Such devices as fireplace heater inserts, heat exchangers circulating air or water or other devices which may alter the
    combustion or heating characteristics of the fireplace. Appliance. A device which utilizes fuel or other forms of energy to produce light, heat, power, refrigeration or air conditioning. This definition shall also include wood burning appliances and
    vented decorative appliances. Fireplace, factory-built. A fireplace composed of factory-built components assembled in accordance with the terms of the listing and acceptance to form the completed fireplace and provided with a chimney complying with
    subchapter fifteen of this chapter (see figure 14-1). Fireplace, masonry. A hearth and fire chamber made of solid masonry units such as bricks, stones, or reinforced concrete and provided with a chimney complying with subchapter fifteen of this chapter.
    Fireplace heat exchangers. Metal heat circulators designed for installation wholly within a masonry fireplace built in accordance with this code. Fireplace heat exchangers extract heat from the firebox of masonry fireplaces and return it to the area
    to be heated (see figure 14-2). Fireplace inserts. Solid-fuel burning appliances located partially within a complying masonry fireplace. Stove and room heaters may be used as inserts for installation in masonry fireplaces (see figure 14-3). Fireplace
    stoves. Freestanding assemblies having firechambers intended to be operated open to the room or if equipped with doors to be operated with doors either open or closed and provided with a chimney complying with subchapter fifteen of this chapter (see
    figure 14-4). Room heater. A solid fuel burning freestanding firechamber assembly designed to be operated with the firechamber closed except for fueling and provided with a chimney complying with subchapter fifteen of this chapter (see figure 14-5).
    Hearth extension. The noncombustible surfacing applied to the floor area beneath, and extending beyond the front, back and sides of a heating appliance. Listed and listings. Terms referring to equipment which is shown in a list published by an accepted
    nationally recognized testing laboratory qualified and equipped for experimental testing and maintaining an adequate periodic inspection of current production and whose listing shows that the equipment complies with nationally recognized safety standards.
    Manufacturer's installation instructions. Printed instructions included with equipment as part of the conditions of the listing. Solid fuel. A material such as natural wood which will ignite and burn when subjected to fire. FACTORY-BUILT FIREPLACE
    -- (See figure 14-1) FIREPLACE HEAT EXCHANGER -- (See figure 14-2) AIRTIGHT FIREPLACE INSERT -- (See figure 14-3) FREESTANDING FIREPLACE STOVE -- (See figure 14-4) AIRTIGHT ROOM HEATER -- (See figure 14-5)</text>
</level>