<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>25-109</num>
  <heading>Streets not to be opened through grounds of certain institutions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 25-109 Streets not to be opened through grounds of certain institutions. a. It shall be unlawful to open any streets through the grounds belonging to the corporation of Fordham University in its actual occupation of the area generally bounded by Bronx
    Park on the north and east, Fordham Road on the south, and the tracks of the Harlem Division of the New York Central and Hudson River Railroad Company on the west. b. It shall also be unlawful to open any streets through or upon any part of the land
    and premises owned by New York University, extending from Sedgwick avenue to Aqueduct avenue, and lying immediately south of and adjacent to One hundred eighty-first street, sometimes called University avenue, so long as the same shall be owned or
    occupied for educational purposes by such university. c. It shall be unlawful to open any streets through the grounds of Columbia University, from One hundred sixteenth street to One hundred twentieth street, between Amsterdam avenue and Broadway,
    so long as such grounds are owned or occupied for educational purposes. d. It shall be unlawful to open any streets through or upon any part of the land and premises owned by Manhattan College, within the territory bounded by West 244th street and
    its easterly prolongation, Post road and Spuyten Duyvil parkway, so long as the same shall be owned or occupied for educational purposes. e. It shall be unlawful to open any streets through or upon any part of the land and premises owned by the college
    of Mount Saint Vincent, without the territory bounded approximately by the northerly city line, Riverdale avenue, West 261st street, Netherland avenue, a line about thirteen hundred feet southerly of the city line and the tracks of the New York Central
    and Hudson River Railroad, so long as the same shall be owned or occupied for educational purposes. f. It shall be unlawful to open any streets through or upon any part of the land or premises owned by the college of Mount Saint Vincent, except West
    261st street, between Riverdale avenue and the New York Central and Hudson River Railroad right-of-way and Palisade avenue south of West 261st street as they are now indicated upon the city map, or as they may in the future be changed in width or
    alignment, within the territory bounded approximately by the northerly city line, Riverdale avenue, West 261st street, Palisade avenue, a line about 1,400 feet southerly of the city line and the tracks of the New York Central and Hudson River Railroad,
    so long as they shall be owned or occupied for educational purposes.</text>
</level>