<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-112.2</num>
  <heading>Schedule of permit fees.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-112.2 Schedule of permit fees. Permits for new buildings, structures, mechanical, and plumbing systems or alterations requiring a permit shall be accompanied by a fee for each permit in accordance with the fee schedule of Table 28-112.2. Fifty percent
    of the total fee for the work permit, but not less than one hundred dollars, or the total fee for the work permit where such fee is less than one hundred dollars, shall be paid and shall accompany the first application for the approval of construction
    documents; and the whole or remainder of the total fee shall be paid before the work permit may be issued. The commissioner may require reasonable substantiation of any statement or other form that may be required by the department. Table 28-112.2
    _________________________________________________________________________ Permit Type Initial Fee Renewal Comments Fee _________________________________________________________________________ New Buildings _________________________________________________________________________
    New building work $0.12 for each $100 permit: square foot, or One-, two- or three- fraction thereof, family dwelling of the total floor area of the new building, but not less than $100 for each structure [] Subsequent appli- $100. Each $100. cations
    related to Each initial new build- ing work permit application, inclu- ding but not lim- ited to elevators, filed prior to the first temporary certificate of oc- cupancy (TCO), or the final certifi- cate of occupancy if no TCO is issued [] New building
    work $100. $100. permit: Garage for not more than three cars when accessory to and filed with plans for one-, two- or three- family dwelling to which it is accessory on the same lot _________________________________________________________________________
    New building work $0.26 for each $100 permit: square foot, or annually All other new buildings fraction thereof, of the total floor area of the new building, but not less than $100 for each structure annually. [] Subsequent appli- $100 cations related
    to $100 each annually. annually. initial new build- ing work permit application, inclu- ding but not lim- ited to elevators, filed prior to the first temporary certificate of occupancy (TCO), or the final certifi- cate of occupancy if no TCO is issued
    _________________________________________________________________________ Alterations _________________________________________________________________________ Alteration work Minimum Filing Fee - $170 $100 permit: Minimum Filing Fee - $130 annually
    [] One-, two- or Minimum Filing Fee - $130 three-family Minimum filing fee dwelling. for the first five thousand [] Alteration Type 1 dollars or fraction thereof, [] Alteration Type 2 of the cost of aleration, [] Alteration Type 3 excluding the cost
    for the [] Permit to install installation or alteration and/or alter of any plumbing or plumbing plumbing, plumbing system or fire suppression system and/or fire piping system; not less than suppression piping $130 annually for system in existing
    subsequent years; plus $5.15 building: One-, for each one thousand dollars, two- or three- or fraction thereof, of cost of family dwelling. alterations in excess of five thousand dollars. _________________________________________________________________________
    Alteration work Minimum Filing Fee - $280 $100 permit: Minimum Filing Fee - $225 annually [] Alterations Minimum Filing Fee - $195 in all other Minimum filing fee buildings and for the first three thousand structures, dollars, or fraction thereof,
    including but not of the cost of alteration limited to aerial not including the cost of the towers and masts, installation or alteration tank structures, of any plumbing or plumbing fire escapes, system or fire suppression etc., which are piping system;
    not less than unoccupied and $195 annually for not easily valued subsequent years; plus $20 by area; for each one thousand [] Alteration dollars, or fraction thereof, Type 1 of the next two thousand [] Alteration dollars of such cost; plus Type 2
    $10.30 for each one thousand [] Alteration dollars, or fraction thereof, Type 3 of the alteration cost in [] Applications re- excess of five thousand dollars. lated to new buil- ding work permit application, filed after the first temporary certifi-
    cate of occupancy (TCO), or the final certificate of occupancy if no TCO is issued. [] Installation or alteration of elevators, escalators, amusement devices and other devices regulated under this code, except those filed under a new building application.
    [] Permit to install and/or alter plumbing, plumbing system and/or fire suppression piping system in existing building: All buildings other than one-, two- or three-family dwelling. _________________________________________________________________________
    Permit to install Filing fee calculated $100 or alter service as for respective building equipment except alteration plumbing and fire suppression piping service equipment. _________________________________________________________________________
    Permit to install, $130 $100 alter or replace $65 $100 oil-burning equipment: [] Where the storage tank exceeds two hundred seventy- five gallon capacity; or where the storage tank is less than two hundred seventy-five gallons and is to be buried,
    or is to be installed in a multiple dwelling or a place of assembly or in a building along the line of a subway, or is to deliver fuel oil to a burner installed above the lowest floor of a building with a primary Business Group B. occupancy. [] In
    all other conditions. _________________________________________________________________________ Other _________________________________________________________________________ Permit for foundation, $10 for each two $100 earthwork or open space thousand
    square without roof, whether feet of area or enclosed or unenclosed, fraction thereof, on sites such as parking but not less than lots, gasoline or oil- $130 selling stations, stor- age yards, sales or ex- hibition or show spaces used for generally
    sim- ilar purposes. _________________________________________________________________________ Permit for golf driving $7.50 for each $100 range. twenty thousand square feet of area or fraction thereof, but not less than $130 _________________________________________________________________________
    Accessory building to $130 $100 golf driving range, not to exceed one hundred forty-four square feet. _________________________________________________________________________ Permit for demolition Multiply street $100. and removal. frontage in feet
    or fraction thereof x number of stories of the building x $2.60, but not less than $260. For corner lot, use the longer street frontage. _________________________________________________________________________ Asbestos permits: [] Permit for the
    Specific fee to be performance of an established by the asbestos project commissioner of for which the environmental filing with the protection. department of an asbestos inspection report, or proof of approval by the commissioner of environmental
    protection of an asbestos removal plan is required. [] Application for Terms "asbestos plan approval or project," permit for work "asbestos inspect- for which an ion report" and asbestos "asbestos removal investigator is plan" shall have required
    to submit the meanings an asbestos ascribed in inspection report Section 24-146.1 certifying that the of the work to be performed administrative will not constitute code. an asbestos project. _________________________________________________________________________
    Filing of post- The greater of approval amendments to $100 or the fees existing applications. for the additional scope or cost of work as calculated pursuant to this Table 28-112.2. _________________________________________________________________________
    Scaffold filing fee $130 _________________________________________________________________________ Scaffold permit $30. _________________________________________________________________________ Signs _________________________________________________________________________
    Permit to erect, Filing fee Each face of install or alter sign: calculated as for any sign, Ground sign. respective building when fronting alteration, plus on different $5 for each one streets, shall hundred square feet be treated as of surface area,
    or a separate fraction thereof, sign. but not less than $35 _________________________________________________________________________ Permit to erect, Filing fee $100 Each face of install or alter calculated as for any sign, when sign: Roof sign respective
    building fronting on having a tight, alteration, plus different streets closed or solid $15 for each one shall be tre- surface. hundred square feet ated as a of surface area, or separate sign. fraction thereof, but not less than $70 _________________________________________________________________________
    Permit to erect, Filing fee $100 Each face of install or alter calculated as for any, sign when sign: Roof sign respective building fronting on without a tight, alteration; plus different closed or solid $15 for each one streets, shall surface, extending
    hundred square feet be treated as to a height of not of surface area, or a separate sign. more than thirty- fraction thereof, one feet above but not less than roof level. $100 _________________________________________________________________________
    Permit to erect, Filing fee $100 Each face of install or alter calculated as for any sign, when sign: Roof sign respective building fronting on without a tight, alteration; plus different closed or solid $25 for each one streets, shall surface, extending
    hundred square feet be treated as to a height over of area, or a separate thirty-one feet fraction thereof, sign. above roof level. but not less than $135. _________________________________________________________________________ Permit to erect,
    Filing fee $100 Illuminated install or alter calculated as for sign is subj- sign: Illuminated respective building ect to annual sign projecting alteration. use fee: $45. beyond street line having thirty square feet or less on one side _________________________________________________________________________
    Permit to erect, Filing fee $100 Illuminated install or alter calculated as for sign is subj- sign: Illuminated respective building ect to annual sign projecting alteration. use fee: $70. beyond street line having more than thirty square feet but
    no more than fifty square feet on one side. _________________________________________________________________________ Permit to erect, Filing fee $100 Illuminated install or alter calculated as for sign is subj- sign: Illuminated respective building
    ect to annual sign projecting alteration. use fee: $0.75 beyond street line for each squ- and having more are foot or than fifty square part thereof feet on one side annually, but not less than $100. _________________________________________________________________________
    Maintenance permit As provided by for outdoor signs. rule. _________________________________________________________________________ Temporary Structures _________________________________________________________________________ Permit for tempor-
    $160 for each $100 ary shed, fence, permit railing, foot- bridge, catch platform, building sidewalk shanty, over-the-sidewalk chute. _________________________________________________________________________ Sidewalk shed. $160 for the first $100.
    twenty-five feet or fraction thereof in the length of shed; plus $10 for each additional twenty-five feet or fraction thereof. _________________________________________________________________________ Permit for temporary $130 for the first $100.
    structure other than one thousand square those listed above, feet or fraction including, but not thereof; plus $0.10 limited to tents, for each square foot grandstands, stages. or fraction thereof in excess of one thousand square feet. _________________________________________________________________________
    Reinstatement of Applications/Permits _________________________________________________________________________ Application/permit reinstatement fees: [] Prior to first Full fee at the rate permit. in effect on the date of reinstatement. [] Following
    first Full fee at the rate permit issuance in effect on the date commencing work. of reinstatement. [] Following first Based upon the full permit, with fee at the rate in work partially effect on the date complete. of reinstatement, the percentage
    of the fee equal to the percentage of work remaining as determined by the department inspector, plus the renewal fee. _________________________________________________________________________
  </text>
</level>