<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-324</num>
  <heading>Protection of structural members.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-324 Protection of structural members. Columns, girders, trusses, beams, lintels, etc. that are required to be fire protected, and that support only one floor or a roof, and/or a non-bearing wall not more than one story high, shall be individually
    encased on all sides with materials having the required fire-resistance rating; or shall be protected by a ceiling as specified in section 27-327 of this article having the required fire-resistance rating; or shall be protected by a combination of
    both a ceiling and individual encasement which, together, provide the required fire-resistance rating. Columns, girders, trusses, beams, lintels, etc. that are required to be fire protected, and that support more than one floor or support a bearing
    wall or wall more than one story high, shall be individually encased on all sides for their entire length or height with materials having the required fire-resistance rating. Trusses that support only two stories or one story and a roof may be fire
    protected by an envelope that encompasses the entire truss with materials of the required fire-resistance rating. (a) Embedments and enclosures. Pipes, wires, conduits, ducts, or other service facilities shall not be embedded in the required fire
    protection of a structural member that is required to be individually encased; except that pipes, wires, and conduits may be installed in the space between the required fire protection and the structural member protected, provided that where such
    facilities pierce the required fire protection, the area of the penetrations does not exceed two percent of the area of the fire protection on any one face, the penetrations are closed off with close-fitting metal escutcheons or plates and the concealed
    space shall be firestopped at each story in accordance with the provisions of section 27-345 of article five of this subchapter. (b) Impact protection. Where the fire protective covering of a structural member is subject to impact damage from moving
    vehicles, the handling of merchandise, or other activity, the fire protective covering shall be protected by corner guards or by a substantial jacket of metal or other noncombustible material, to a height adequate to provide full protection. Where
    applicable, such protection shall be designed in accordance with the requirements of section 27-558 of article three of subchapter nine of this chapter. (c) Structural members in cavity walls. Where structural members occur within exterior cavity
    walls, portions of such structural members facing the exterior need not be individually fire protected if the outer width of the cavity wall provides the required fire-resistance rating and is located not more than two and one-half inches from such
    structural members, and if all surfaces of the structural members are fire protected from the interior of the building by materials having the required fire-resistance rating. (d) Prestressing steel. Minimum covering of prestressing steel shall comply
    with the requirements of reference standard RS 5-15. (e) Exterior Exposed Structural Members. Structural members exposed to the outdoors on buildings that do not exceed two stories or thirty feet in height, which are required by table 3-4 to have
    a fire-resistance rating not exceeding one hour, need not be protected on any face of the member that has an exterior separation of thirty feet or more, provided the outdoor area within the thirty feet separation distance is not used for storage of
    materials, or for motor vehicle parking. (f) Inspection of fire protection. The installation of all required sprayed-on fire protection of structural members except those encased in concrete shall be subject to the controlled inspection requirements
    of section 27-132 of article seven of subchapter one of this code. (g) Inspection of existing sprayed-on fire protection during alterations in office spaces and in occupancy group E spaces. In office spaces and spaces classified in occupancy group
    E, where an alteration exposes any required sprayed-on fire protection of structural members, or where, pursuant to an alteration persons are required to enter or access areas in which such sprayed-on fire protection is capable of being observed,
    the existing required spray-on fire protection shall be subject to the controlled inspection requirements of section 27-132 of this code. Such controlled inspection shall require a determination (i) that the existing sprayed-on fire protection as
    originally applied or installed complies with the applicable requirements of this code, including those for installation methods, materials, thickness and coverage; and (ii) that, since its original application, the integrity of the existing sprayed-on
    fire protection has not been compromised, damaged or displaced by the current alteration or by any prior alteration or other event.</text>
</level>