<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-777</num>
  <heading>Construction.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-777 Construction. The construction, installation, and alteration of systems for providing mechanical ventilation, air conditioning, air cooling, air heating, and refrigeration, shall be in accordance with the following: (a) Air conditioning and
    ventilating systems for all occupancies shall be constructed in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 13-1. In addition, equipment used for air conditioning systems shall be constructed, installed and altered in accordance with the
    provisions of reference standards RS 13-7 through 13-15. Where any conflicts arise between the electrical provisions of the foregoing reference standards and the New York city electrical code, the provisions of the latter shall govern. (b) Air conditioning
    systems for one and two family dwellings, for one story buildings four thousand square feet or less in gross floor area provided ducts do not penetrate fire divisions, and for buildings classified in mercantile occupancy group C, twenty-five hundred
    square feet or less in gross floor area shall be constructed and installed in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 13-4. Also see article eleven of subchapter fourteen of this chapter. (c) Exhaust systems for cooking spaces requiring
    mechanical ventilation in accordance with the provisions of subchapter twelve of this chapter, except kitchens located within dwelling units, shall be installed as provided in reference standard RS 13-2. (d) Restaurant cooking equipment shall be provided
    with a means of ventilating such equipment constructed in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 13-3, provided however that restaurant cooking equipment installed for periodic cooking use other than commerical only, in community
    rooms of multiple dwellings, firehouses and other low hazard occupancies as determined by the commissioner may be provided with a means of ventilation constructed in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 13-1. (e) Air blower and
    exhaust systems, where required for the removal or conveying of dust, vapor, or other impurities, shall be installed in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 13-5. (f) Refrigeration systems shall be constructed, installed, and altered
    in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 13-6. (g) The utilization of city water in air conditioning and refrigeration systems shall be subject to the requirements of reference standard RS-16.</text>
</level>