<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-684</num>
  <heading>Footings.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-684 Footings. Inspections of subgrade of footings, piers and walls shall comply with the requirements of section 27-723 of article thirteen of this subchapter. (a) Wood footings. Wood footings may be used only for wood frame structures. Wood footings
    shall be given a preservative treatment in accordance with reference standard RS 11-4. (b) Pole buildings. Buildings not more than one story high may be supported on poles embedded in the ground. Wood poles shall conform to the requirements of reference
    standard RS 11-5 and shall be given a preservative treatment in accordance with reference standard RS 11-4. Steel poles embedded in the soil shall be protected as required by the provisions of paragraph one of subdivision (c) of section 27-685 of
    this article. (c) Grillages. Grillage beams shall be provided with proper spacers, stiffners, and diaphragms, or the space between the beams shall be filled with concrete or grout. In addition, all steel grillages shall be fully protected against
    corrosion by encasement, coating with metal protection of a type satisfactory to the commissioner or by other approved device. (d) Design. (1) CONCRETE FOOTINGS. Concrete footings shall be proportioned in accordance with the provisions of reference
    standard RS 10-3. Reinforcement shall extend to within four inches of the edges of the footing. (2) MASONRY FOOTINGS. Masonry used for the construction of footings shall be of solid units. a. Reinforced masonry footings shall meet the requirements
    of reference standard RS 10-2 and shall be proportioned similarly to the proportioning of reinforced concrete footings. b. Unreinforced masonry footings shall be of such dimension that a sloping plane extending downward from the top of the footing
    where it intersects the pier of wall, to the bottom of the footing, and measured at the angle with the horizontal that is indicated below, will be contained entirely within the footing: Soil bearing capacity of three tons per square foot or less--
    sixty degrees Soil bearing capacity between three tons per square foot and six tons per square foot--seventy degrees Soil bearing capacity greater than six tons per square foot shall be investigated. The compressive stress in the footing, based on
    the assumption that the vertical load is uniformly distributed over horizontal sections bounded by said planes, shall not exceed the values given in reference standard RS 10-1.</text>
</level>