<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-408.6</num>
  <heading>Master plumber business.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-408.6 Master plumber business. No individual, corporation, partnership or other business association shall conduct a plumbing contracting business in the city of New York, or employ the name "plumber" or "plumbing" in its business name unless such
    business is a master plumber business as follows: 1. No less than 51 percent of the control and voting capital stock of such entity is owned by one or more individuals who are licensed master plumbers, except as otherwise provided; 2. All plumbing
    or gas piping work performed by such entity is performed by or under the direct and continuing supervision of such licensed master plumber; 3. The person in charge of such work is such licensed master plumber; and 4. The persons actually performing
    such work are in the direct employ of such master plumber business as authorized by the code. Exception: A company, corporation, partnership or other business association or its predecessor that was engaged in plumbing work prior to January 25, 1990
    may continue to do so in any one or more of such business forms without complying with the foregoing, if (i) application was made to the department prior to July 25, 1990, and (ii) necessary evidence was furnished on or prior to January 25, 1991,
    that such company, corporation, partnership or other business association or its predecessor had employed an average of ten or more journeymen plumbers doing plumbing work for at least five days a week for a period of 10 years or more out of the twenty
    years preceding July 25, 1990, provided, that such plumbing business continues to have all plumbing work conducted under the management and direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master plumber in the direct employ of such plumbing business
    and that such licensed master plumber is not otherwise interested in, associated with or employed by any other plumbing business operating in this city except as a joint venture in which such master plumber's employer is one of the joint venturers.</text>
</level>