<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2056.11</num>
  <heading>Work Practices.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2056.11 Work Practices. a. The department shall promulgate rules, with the approval of the department of health and mental hygiene, establishing work practices to which an owner shall be subject in each of the following circumstances: (1) where
    an owner is performing work in order to comply with a notice of violation or order to correct issued by the department pursuant to this article, which shall be no less stringent than the safety standards required by the commissioner of health and
    mental hygiene whenever such commissioner shall order the abatement of lead-based paint hazards pursuant to section 173.13 of the health code or a successor rule. Such rules shall provide for temporary relocation provided by the owner of the occupants
    of a dwelling or dwelling unit to appropriate housing when work cannot be performed safely. Such rules shall provide that all such work be performed only by firms which have received certification to perform lead abatement under the regulations issued
    by the United States environmental protection agency at subpart L of part 745 of title 40 of the code of federal regulations, or any successor regulations. (2) where an owner, other than in response to an order to correct or notice of violation issued
    by the department or the department of health and mental hygiene, is performing work that will disturb lead-based paint or paint of unknown lead content in a dwelling unit where a child of applicable age resides or in the common area of the multiple
    dwelling in which such dwelling unit is located, where such multiple dwelling was erected prior to January first, nineteen hundred sixty, or where the owner has actual knowledge of the presence of lead-based paint and such multiple dwelling was erected
    on or after January first, nineteen hundred sixty and before January first, nineteen hundred seventy-eight. (i) Except as provided in subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, such rules shall incorporate work practices that are no less protective of public
    health than those set forth in subdivisions d and e of section 173.14 of the health code and those parts of subdivision b of such section applicable thereto or a successor rule, and shall include a requirement that lead-contaminated dust clearance
    testing be performed at the completion of such work. Such rules shall require that such work be performed by a person who has, at a minimum, successfully completed a course on lead-safe work practices given by or on behalf of the department or, by
    the United States environmental protection agency or an entity authorized by it to give such course, or by the United States department of housing and urban development or an entity authorized by it to give such course. Such rules shall require temporary
    relocation provided by the owner of the occupants of a dwelling or dwelling unit to appropriate housing when work cannot be performed safely. (ii) Where such work will disturb more than one hundred square feet of lead-based paint or paint of unknown
    lead content in a room in a multiple dwelling, or will involve the removal of two or more windows with lead-based paint or paint of unknown lead content, such rules shall incorporate work practices that are no less protective of public health than
    those set forth in subdivisions d and e of section 173.14 of the health code and those parts of subdivision b of such section applicable thereto, or a successor rule, and shall include a requirement that lead-contaminated dust clearance testing be
    performed at the completion of such work. Such rules shall also require temporary relocation provided by the owner of the occupants of a dwelling or dwelling unit to appropriate housing when work cannot be performed safely. Such rules shall require,
    in addition, that all such work be performed only by firms which have received certification to perform lead abatement under the regulations issued by the United States environmental protection agency at subpart L of part 745 of title 40 of the code
    of federal regulations for the abatement of lead hazards, or any successor regulations. Such rules shall also provide that not less than ten days prior to the commencement of such work the owner of the premises, or the firm, shall file with the department
    of health and mental hygiene a notice of commencement so that the department of health and mental hygiene may, at its discretion, perform sample audits of such notices to determine that the firms performing the work are properly certified. Such notice
    shall be signed by the owner or by a representative of the firm, and shall be in a form satisfactory to or prescribed by the department of health and mental hygiene, and shall set forth at a minimum the following information: (a) The address of the
    multiple dwelling and the specific location of the work within the multiple dwelling. (b) The name, address and telephone number of the owner of the multiple dwelling in which the work is to be performed. (c) The name, address and telephone number
    of the firm which will be responsible for performing the work. (d) The date and time of commencement of the work, working or shift hours, and the expected date of completion; and (e) Identification of the surfaces and structures, and surface area,
    subject to the work. The rules shall also provide that any changes in the information contained in the notice shall be filed with the department of health and mental hygiene prior to commencement of work, or if work has already commenced, within twenty-four
    hours of any change. The rules shall provide that a copy of the notice of commencement shall be posted at the work site. (iii) The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply where such work disturbs surfaces of less than (a) two square feet of peeling
    lead-based paint per room or (b) ten percent of the total surface area of peeling paint on a type of component with a small surface area, such as a window sill or door frame. (3) where an owner is performing work on turnover pursuant to 27-2056.8
    of this article. Such rules shall include, but not be limited to, requiring lead-contaminated dust clearance tests at the completion of such work. b. No person shall perform a lead-contaminated dust clearance test pursuant to this section unless such
    person is a third-party, who is independent of the owner and any individual or firm that performs the work, and has successfully completed a course approved or administered by the department of health and mental hygiene or by the United States environmental
    protection agency or the United States department of housing and urban development and obtained a certificate or other document issued by or acceptable to the department of health and mental hygiene. c. The department, with the approval of the department
    of health and mental hygiene, shall promulgate rules requiring that all lead-contaminated dust clearance tests submitted to a laboratory for analysis include a sworn certification that such test was performed in compliance with all applicable rules
    and regulations and shall include any additional information that the department shall determine is necessary for the administration and enforcement of this section. d. Where an owner is performing work pursuant to paragraph (1) of subdivision a of
    this section, all lead-contaminated dust clearance test results shall be filed with the department, and a copy shall be provided by the owner to the occupant of the dwelling unit. Where an owner is performing work pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3)
    of subdivision a of this section, a copy of all lead-contaminated dust clearance test results shall be provided to the occupant of the dwelling unit. Copies of lead-contaminated dust clearance test results provided to the occupant of the dwelling
    unit pursuant to this subparagraph shall be in a form satisfactory to or prescribed by the department of health and mental hygiene that provides a sufficiently clear explanation of the meaning of such results.</text>
</level>