<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-328</num>
  <heading>Fire retardant treated wood.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-328 Fire retardant treated wood. (a) Material. Fire-retardant treated wood shall be pressure treated with fire retardant chemicals in accordance with reference standards RS 5-3 and RS 5-4. Where used as a structural element or as furring, the material
    shall have a flame spread rating not greater than twenty-five when tested in accordance with reference standard RS 5-5 when exposed for a period of at least thirty minutes, with no evidence of significant progressive combustion. Where used as interior
    finish or trim, the material shall have a flame spread rating that meets the requirements of section 27-348 of this subchapter for the location in which it is used. Subsequent to treatment, material two inches thick or less shall be air dried or kiln
    dried to an average moisture content of not more than nineteen percent. (b) Label. All fire-retardant treated wood shall bear the identification of a testing laboratory or producer certifying to the performance thereof, in accordance with the acceptance
    requirements of section 27-131 of article seven of subchapter one of this chapter. (c) Application. Fire-retardant treated wood may not be used where exposed to the weather or in interior spaces where the relative humidity is normally eighty percent
    or more. There shall be no fabrication of the material after treatment, such as cutting, shaping, or grooving for splines or ring connectors so as to expose untreated surfaces, except that the material may be cut to length, shaped, or grooved if the
    exposed surfaces or edges are tightly butted against other material that is noncombustible or that is fire retardant treated, so that no untreated wood is left exposed to danger of ignition. Holes may be bored or cut for plumbing or heating pipes
    and for electric outlets only if the openings are coverd with tightly-fitted noncombustible escutcheons or cover plates. The allowable working stresses of the material shall be ninety percent of the allowable stresses for untreated lumber of like
    classification. (d) Where permitted in construction group I. Fire-retardant treated wood may be used in buildings of construction group I in the following cases: (1) As permitted by table 3-4. (2) For interior non-bearing partitions that are not required
    to have a fire-resistance rating. (3) For interior furring and blocking of exterior walls, furring and blocking of interior walls and partitions, and framing of suspended ceilings provided the furring, blocking, and framing do not affect the integrity,
    or reduce the fire-resistance rating, of the construction element. (4) For interior finish and trim. (e) Area increase. Fire-retardant treated wood may be used in construction group II buildings in lieu of untreated wood for wall studs, bearing partition
    studs, columns, beams, girders, joists, rafters, trusses, sole and cap plates, subflooring and roof decks, and when so used, the area limitations of tables 4-1 and 4-2, for buildings of construction group II, may be increased by thirty-three and one-third
    percent.
  </text>
</level>