<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-803</num>
  <heading>Reduction of greenhouse gas emissions that contribute to global warming.</heading>
  <text>ยง24-803 Reduction of greenhouse gas emissions that contribute to global warming. a. (1) Reduction of emissions citywide. There shall be, at minimum, a thirty percent reduction in citywide emissions by calendar year 2030, relative to such emissions for
    the base year for citywide emissions. (2) The emissions reduction required by paragraph one of this subdivision shall be achieved through the applicable policies, programs and actions included in PlaNYC, and any additional policies, programs and actions
    to reduce greenhouse gas emissions that contribute to global warming. If the office determines that such emissions reduction is not feasible despite the best efforts of city government, such office shall report such findings and make recommendations
    with respect to policies, programs and actions that may be undertaken to achieve such reductions. b. Reduction of emissions from city government operations. (1) There shall be, at minimum, a thirty percent reduction in city government emissions by
    calendar year 2017, relative to such emissions for the base year for city government emissions. (2) The emissions reduction required by paragraph one of this subdivision shall be achieved through the applicable policies, programs and actions included
    in PlaNYC, and any additional policies, programs and actions to reduce greenhouse gas emissions that contribute to global warming. If the office determines that such emissions reduction is not feasible despite the best efforts of city government,
    such office shall report such findings and make recommendations with respect to policies, programs and actions that may be undertaken to achieve such reductions. c. Carbon dioxide equivalent emission inventories. (1) No later than September 17, 2008,
    and no later than every September 17 thereafter, the office shall complete and post on its website an inventory and analysis of citywide emissions measured in carbon dioxide equivalent for the previous calendar year, and shall calculate the percentage
    change in citywide emissions measured in carbon dioxide equivalent for such calendar year, relative to such emissions for the base year for citywide emissions. (2) No later than September 17, 2008, and no later than every September 17 thereafter,
    the office shall complete and post on its website an inventory and analysis of city government emissions measured in carbon dioxide equivalent for the fiscal year ending in the previous calendar year, and shall calculate the percentage change in city
    government emissions measured in carbon dioxide equivalent for such calendar year, relative to such emissions for the base year for city government emissions. d. Voluntary global warming emissions reduction program. The effort to reduce citywide emissions
    set forth in subdivision a of this section shall include, but not be limited to, voluntary programs developed and implemented no later than March 1, 2009, that encourage private entities operating within the city of New York to commit to reducing
    their own greenhouse gas emissions measured in carbon dioxide equivalent to help facilitate the citywide emissions reduction effort.</text>
</level>