<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-910</num>
  <heading>Air conditioning prohibitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง20-910 Air conditioning prohibitions. a. For the purposes of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings: 1. "Chain of stores" shall mean five or more stores located within the city of New York that are engaged in the same general
    field of business and conduct business under the same business name or operate under common ownership or management or pursuant to a franchise agreement with the same franchisor. 2. "Commercial building or structure" shall mean an building or structure
    classified in accordance with section BC 302 of the New York city building code in occupancy group B or M, except that such term shall not include a small store. 3. "Door" shall mean any door used to close off any exterior entrance to a commercial
    building or structure and that when open allows for the co-mingling of indoor and outdoor air, but shall not include doors that (i) adjoin indoor seating areas where food or beverages are served and link such areas to outdoor space or outdoor seating
    areas, or (ii) allow for direct table service of food or beverages to outdoor seating areas during times when servers are actively engaged in serving such areas. 4. "Person" shall mean (i) with respect to the portion of a commercial building or structure
    that is a retail or wholesale establishment that sells goods or provides services to consumers, the owner or lessee of such establishment; and (ii) with respect to any other portion of a commercial building or structure, the record owner or lessee
    of such building or structure. 5. "Small store" shall mean a retail or wholesale establishment that sells goods or provides services to consumers and occupies under four thousand square feet of retail or wholesale space, excluding storage space, and
    is not one of a chain of stores. b. Except as provided in subdivision c of this section, it shall be unlawful to keep open any exterior door of a commercial building or structure while an air conditioner or central cooling system is operating that
    cools the area adjacent to such door, except as needed to permit the ingress and egress of people and the delivery and shipping of goods. c. The provisions of this section shall not apply when an emergency situation exists that requires an exterior
    door to be kept open. d. The department shall have the authority to enforce the provisions of subdivision b of this section. A proceeding to recover any civil penalty prescribed by subdivision e of this section shall be commenced by the service of
    a notice of violation, which shall be returnable to the environmental control board. The environmental control board shall have the power to impose any civil penalty prescribed by subdivision e of this section. e. Any person who violates this section
    shall receive a written warning for the first violation, and shall be liable for a civil penalty in the amount of two hundred dollars for each open door for a second violation within an eighteen month period and four hundred dollars for each open
    door for any third and subsequent violation within an eighteen month period.</text>
</level>