<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-380</num>
  <heading>Fire escapes.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-380 Fire escapes. Fire escapes constructed on existing buildings when altered or as a second means of egress for group homes as permitted by section 27-368 of this article shall comply with the following: (a) Capacity. The capacity of fire escapes
    shall be as listed in table 6-1 for stairs. (b) Stairs. The minimum width of fire escape stairs shall be twenty-two inches. Treads shall have a minimum width of eight inches, exclusive of a required one inch nosing. The maximum height of risers shall
    be eight inches. No flight of stairs shall exceed twelve feet in height between landings. (c) Landings. Landings shall be provided at each story served by fire escapes. The minimum width of landings shall be three feet, and the minimum length shall
    be four feet six inches. Floor openings in landings shall be at least twenty-two inches by twenty-eight inches. (d) Handrails and guards. Handrails having a minimum height of thirty-two inches above the tread nosing shall be provided on both sides
    of stairs, and guards having a minimum height of thirty-six inches shall be provided on all open sides of landings, openings in guards shall be of such dimensions as to prevent the passage of a five inch dia. ball. (e) Construction. Fire escapes shall
    be constructed of noncombustible materials adequately protected against deterioration by corrosion or other effects of exposure to the weather, and shall be designed to comply with the requirements of subchapter nine of this chapter. (f) Access. Access
    to fire escapes shall be by doors or windows having a minimum clear opening of twenty-four inches in width and thirty inches in height. Such doors or windows shall have a fire protection rating of three-quarters of an hour except in buildings classified
    in occupancy group J-2. (g) Discharge. The top landing of fire escapes shall be provided with a stair or gooseneck ladder leading to the roof, except that this requirement shall not apply to buildings having a roof pitch of more than twenty degrees.
    The lowest landing of fire escapes shall be not more than sixteen feet above grade and shall be provided with a stair to grade which may be counterbalanced.</text>
</level>