<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-509</num>
  <heading>Construction of sewers.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-509 Construction of sewers. a. The commissioner of environmental protection shall prescribe the manner of opening sewers or drains and the form, size and material of which the connections therewith shall be composed. b. It shall be unlawful to
    make a connection with any sewer or drain without the written permit of the commissioner of environmental protection, except that, in conjunction with the issuance of a permit for the construction or alteration of a structure within the curbline,
    the commissioner of buildings may issue a permit for connection with a sewer or drain. Such connection shall be in the manner prescribed by the commissioner of environmental protection. The commissioner issuing the permit shall require an applicant
    for such permit to demonstrate to his or her satisfaction that the proposed discharges to the sewer will be in compliance with section 24-523 of this chapter and the regulations promulgated pursuant to such section. For such purpose the commissioner
    issuing the permit may require the submission of plans, specifications and such other information as he or she may reasonably require. c. When public sewers are made available, the individual on site private sewage disposal system or any other means
    of sewage disposal or discharge shall be abandoned in a manner prescribed by the commissioner of buildings. The building house sewer shall be connected to the available public sewer within six months of the date of notification that the sewer has
    been accepted to receive flow. As used in this subdivision the term "individual on site private sewage disposal system" shall mean a system of interconnected structures, units, pipes and devices, including a septic tank and an absorption area, which
    does not connect to the city sewer system, and which is used to collect, convey, treat and dispose water-flushed or water-carried domestic or commercial sewage on one tax lot. d. Any person who violates subdivision c of this section, or any order
    issued by or rule promulgated by the commissioner pursuant thereto, shall be liable for a civil penalty in an amount not greater than five thousand dollars for each violation, which may be recovered in a proceeding before the environmental control
    board. A proceeding to recover any civil penalty authorized pursuant to this section shall be commenced by the service of a notice of violation returnable before the environmental control board, which shall have the power to impose the civil penalties
    prescribed herein.</text>
</level>