<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-171.1</num>
  <heading>Multi-passenger wheeled device and motorized pedicab prohibited.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-171.1. Multi-passenger wheeled device and motorized pedicab prohibited. a. Definitions. For purposes of this section: 1. "Motorized pedicab" shall mean a wheeled device that is designed and constructed to transport or carry passengers, that is
    propelled in whole or in part by other than human power, and that is operated to transport passengers for hire. 2. "Multi-passenger wheeled device" shall mean a wheeled device with three or more wheels that is designed and constructed to permit seating
    by more than two people, that is propelled by human power, and that is designed to permit propulsion by more than two individuals simultaneously. 3. "Owner" shall mean any person who possesses with good legal title, or possesses under a lease, reserve
    title contract, conditional sales agreement or vendor's agreement or similar agreement one or more motorized pedicabs or multi-passenger wheeled devices in the city of New York. 4. "Tandem bicycle" shall mean a wheeled device that is constructed so
    that its wheels are aligned in a straight line, one behind the other, permitting operation by two or more people. b. It shall be unlawful to operate, or cause to be operated, any motorized pedicab or multi-passenger wheeled device, other than a tandem
    bicycle, on any street, sidewalk, highway, bridge, tunnel or park within New York City. c. Any person who violates subdivision b of this section may be issued a notice of violation and shall be subject to a civil penalty that shall not be: (1) less
    than two hundred nor more than five hundred dollars for the first violation; (2) less than five hundred nor more than one thousand dollars for the second violation committed within a one year period; (3) less than one thousand nor more than four thousand
    dollars for the third violation committed within a one year period. Such penalty may be recovered in a proceeding before the environmental control board. d. A person who violates subdivision b of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable
    by a fine of not more than two hundred fifty dollars or imprisonment of up to sixteen days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. e. Where a police or peace officer or an authorized employee of a department designated by the commissioner serves a
    summons or notice of violation for violation of this section on a person operating a multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab, such multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab may be seized. Any device seized pursuant to this subdivision
    shall be delivered into the custody of the police department. The environmental control board shall hold a hearing to adjudicate the violation of subdivision b of this section on an expedited schedule and shall render its determination accordingly.
    f. The owner of a multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab seized pursuant to subdivision e of this section shall be eligible to obtain release of such device prior to the hearing provided for in such subdivision, if such owner has not
    been found liable for a violation of subdivision b of this section within a five year period prior to the violation resulting in seizure. The multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab shall be released to such owner upon the posting of an
    all cash bond in a form satisfactory to the commissioner in an amount satisfactory to cover the maximum civil penalties which may be imposed for a violation of subdivision b of this section and all reasonable costs for removal and storage of such
    device. g. Where the environmental control board finds that there was no violation of subdivision b of this section, the owner shall be entitled forthwith to possession of the multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab without charge or to
    the extent that any amount has been previously paid for release of the device, such amount shall be refunded. h. Where the board, after adjudication of the violation of subdivision b of this section, finds a violation of such subdivision, then (i)
    if the multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab is not subject to forfeiture pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision j, the police department shall release such device to its owner upon payment of all applicable civil penalties and all
    reasonable costs of removal and storage; or (ii) if the multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab is subject to forfeiture pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision j of this section, the police department may release such device to its owner
    upon payment of all civil penalties and all reasonable costs of removal and storage, or may commence a forfeiture action within ten days after the written demand by such owner for such device. i. The department shall establish by rule the time within
    which multi-passenger wheeled devices or motorized pedicabs that are not redeemed may be deemed abandoned and the procedures for disposal. j. 1. In addition to any other penalty or sanction provided for in this section, a multi-passenger wheeled device
    or motorized pedicab seized pursuant to subdivision e of this section, and all rights, title and interest therein shall be subject to forfeiture to the city upon notice and judicial determination thereof if the owner of such multi-passenger wheeled
    device or motorized pedicab has been found liable at least two times within a five-year period for violation of subdivision b of this section. 2. A forfeiture action pursuant to this subdivision shall be commenced by the filing of a summons with a
    notice or a summons and complaint in accordance with the civil practice law and rules. Such summons with notice or a summons and complaint shall be served in accordance with the civil practice law and rules on the owner of such multi-passenger wheeled
    device or motorized pedicab. A multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab which is the subject of such action shall remain in the custody of the police department or other appropriate agency pending the final determination of the forfeiture
    action. 3. Any person who receives notice of the institution of a forfeiture action who claims an interest in the multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab subject to forfeiture may assert a claim in such action for the recovery of such
    device or satisfaction of such owner's interest in such device. 4. Forfeiture pursuant to this subdivision shall be made subject to the interest of a person who claims an interest in such device pursuant to subdivision three of this subdivision, where
    such person establishes that: (i) such multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab was operated in violation of this section without the knowledge of such person, or if such person had knowledge of such operation, that such person did not
    consent to such operation by doing all that could reasonably have been done to prevent such operation, or (ii) that the operation of such multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab in violation of this section was conducted by any person
    other than such person claiming an interest in the device, while such device was unlawfully in the possession of a person who acquired possession thereof in violation of the criminal laws of the United States or any state. 5. The police department,
    after judicial determination of forfeiture, shall, by public notice of at least five days, sell such forfeited multi-passenger wheeled device or motorized pedicab at public sale. The net proceeds of any such sale shall be paid into the general fund
    of the city. 6. In any forfeiture action commenced pursuant to this subdivision, where the court awards a sum of money to one or more persons in satisfaction of such person's interest in the forfeited device, the total amount awarded to satisfy such
    interest or interests shall not exceed the amount of the net proceeds of the sale of the forfeited device after deduction of the lawful expenses incurred by the city, including reasonable costs of removal and storage of the device between the time
    of the seizure and the date of sale. k. The penalties provided by subdivisions c, d, e and j of this section shall be in addition to any other penalty imposed by any other provision of law or rule promulgated thereunder.</text>
</level>