<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-526</num>
  <heading>Conveyance of storm water from developments and lots and certain adjacent paved areas to off-site disposal points.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-526 Conveyance of storm water from developments and lots and certain adjacent paved areas to off-site disposal points. (a) Definitions. As used in this section: (1) "Building combined sewer" means a building sewer intended to convey all types of
    wastewater, subject to certain restrictions; (2) "Building sewer" means a sewer consisting of the part of the horizontal piping of a drainage system that extends from the end of a building house drain, as defined in section P100.00 of reference standard
    RS-16 of this code, to a street sewer or to another point of disposal. Building combined sewers and building storm sewers are types of building sewers; (3) "Building storm sewer" means the part of the horizontal piping of a storm water drainage system
    that extends from a building house storm drain, as defined in section P100.00 of reference standard RS-16 of this code, to a street storm sewer, a street combined sewer or another point of disposal; (4) "Catch basin" means a storm sewer inlet connected
    to a storm sewer or a combined sewer; (5) "Development" means a tract of land which has been subdivided into two or more lots, whether or not such tract has been developed as by the installation of any utilities or the construction of any streets
    or buildings or other structures; (6) "Lot" means a portion or parcel of land considered as a unit; a zoning lot; (7) "Owner" means a person in whom legal or equitable title to property or premises is vested, a mortgagee or vendee in possession of
    premises, as assignee of rents, a receiver of premises, or a person listed as owner or agent for an owner on the records as to real property ownership maintained by the bureau of city collections of the department of finance unless such person establishes
    that such records are erroneous or, if claiming that he or she is an agent of the owner, furnishes the identity of the owner; (8) "Person" means a natural person, company, partnership, corporation, association, governmental body or other legal entity,
    including any individual or entity acting in a representative capacity; (9) "Private" means not public; (10) "Public" means owned by the city and intended for use by the public, subject to restrictions which the city or agencies thereof may impose;
    (11) "Storm water" means rainwater or surface water; (12) "Street combined sewer" means a street sewer which is intended to receive the discharge of all types of wastewater, subject to certain restrictions, from one or more building sewers and catch
    basins and to convey such wastewater to an intercepting sewer, a private sewage disposal system or some other point of disposal; (13) "Street sewer" means a sewer located in the bed of a street or elsewhere which is intended to receive the discharge
    of all or certain types of wastewater from one or more building sewers and, in some cases, from catch basins, and to convey such wastewater to points of disposal. Street combined sewers and street storm sewers are types of street sewers; (14) "Street
    storm sewer" means a street sewer which is intended to receive the discharge of storm water from one or more building storm sewers and catch basins and to convey such storm water to a point of disposal; and (15) "Tidal creek" means any creek where
    the level of water rises and falls with tidal action, or would do so if not impeded by artificial structures including but not limited to tide gates. (b) Required conveyance of storm water for off-site disposal when public sewers into which discharge
    is feasible are located within five hundred feet of property. If the commissioner determines that a public street storm sewer or a public street combined sewer is located within five hundred feet, measured along a street, alley or right-of-way, from
    any point on the boundary of a development or of a lot which is not within a development into which it would be feasible, as described in subdivision (g) of this section, to discharge storm water from such development or lot: (1) An owner of a lot
    within such a development or of such a lot not within a development, who is constructing or causing to be constructed on such a lot a single one-family or two-family detached or semi-detached building, may dispose of the storm water falling or coming
    to rest within such lot which is required, by paragraph two of subdivision (b) of section P110.2 of reference standard RS-16 of this code, to be conveyed to a boundary of such lot abutting a street for off-site disposal, by causing such storm water
    to be discharged through an under-the-sidewalk drain or across a sidewalk onto a paved street improved in accordance with the requirements of the department of transportation and containing curbs; provided that catch basins adequate to receive such
    storm water are located, or are installed in accordance with the requirements of this code and of the department, within five hundred feet from the farthest point of storm water discharge onto such street; provided further that the commissioner determines
    that such means of storm water disposal is feasible, as described in subdivision (g) of this section, and also provided that the commissioner of buildings agrees with such determination. (2) An owner of a lot within such a development or of such a
    lot not within a development who is constructing or causing to be constructed a building on such lot shall dispose of the storm water falling or coming to rest on such lot which is required, by paragraph three of subdivision (b) of section P110.2
    of reference standard RS-16 of this code, to be conveyed to a boundary of such lot abutting a street for off-site disposal, except as provided in paragraph one of this subdivision, by conveying such storm water, together with all storm water falling
    or coming to rest on all streets and other paved areas outside of such lot constructed or altered in connection with the construction of such building for the primary purpose of improving vehicular or pedestrian access thereto, by sewers, constructed
    in accordance with requirements in subdivision (e) of this section and elsewhere in this code and of the department, to such public sewer; provided that no sewage shall be discharged into any such public street storm sewer. If installation of a controlled
    flow storm water system, in accordance with the requirements of section P110.6 of this reference standard, is necessary to make it feasible to discharge such storm water into such public sewer, the owner of the lot shall install such a system. (c)
    Required conveyance of storm water for off-site disposal, prior to January first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, when no public sewers into which discharge is feasible are located within five hundred feet of property. The requirements set forth in
    this subdivision shall apply to the construction of all new buildings for which new building permits have been filed prior to January first, nineteen hundred ninety-four. If the commissioner determines that no public street storm sewer or public street
    combined sewer is located within five hundred feet, measured along a street, alley or right-of-way, from any point on the boundary of a development or of a lot not contained in a development into which it would be feasible to discharge storm water
    from such development or such lot: (1) An owner of a lot within such a development or of such a lot not within a development who is constructing or causing to be constructed on such lot a one-family, two-family or three-family building, where more
    than thirty percent of the area being developed, exclusive of streets, shall have no structures and shall be unpaved, but which area may have not more than twenty percent of the floor area of all the structures in the development devoted to nonresidential
    uses, may dispose of all or some of the storm water falling or coming to rest on such lot which, pursuant to paragraph three of subdivision (c) of section P110.2 of reference standard RS-16 of this code, is conveyed to a boundary of the lot abutting
    a street, by discharging such storm water through an under-the-sidewalk drain or across a sidewalk onto a paved street improved in accordance with the requirements of the department of transportation and containing curbs, provided that: (A) such person
    provides for the installation of all street storm sewers or street combined sewers and catch basins, constructed in accordance with the requirements in subdivision (e) of this section and elsewhere in this code and of the department, such that a catch
    basin adequate to receive such storm water, together with all storm water falling or coming to rest on all streets and other paved areas outside of such lot constructed or altered in connection with the construction of such building for the primary
    purpose of improving vehicular or pedestrian access thereto, shall be located within five hundred feet from the farthest point of storm water discharge onto such street, and such that the street storm sewers or street combined sewers extend from such
    catch basin to a point of disposal described in paragraph three of this subdivision; the requirements of this subparagraph shall not apply if private catch basins and sewers meeting all the requirements of this subparagraph are already present; and
    (B) the commissioner determines that such means of storm sewer disposal is feasible, as described in subdivision (g) of this section, and the commissioner of buildings agrees with such determination. (2) An owner of a development which shall only
    contain buildings described in paragraph four of subdivision (c) of section P110.2 of reference standard RS-16 of this code who conveys storm water falling or coming to rest within such development to a boundary of such development, pursuant to such
    paragraph, or an owner of a lot, whether or not within a development, who is constructing or causing to be constructed on such lot a new building and who is required to convey storm water falling or coming to rest within such lot to a boundary of
    such lot abutting a street, pursuant to paragraph five of subdivision (c) of section P110.2 of reference standard RS-16 of this code, shall convey such storm water, together with storm water falling or coming to rest on all streets and other paved
    areas outside of such development or lot which are constructed or altered in connection with the construction of such buildings or building for the primary purpose of improving vehicular or pedestrian access thereto, from such boundary by sewers,
    constructed in accordance with the requirements in subdivision (e) of this section and elsewhere in this code and of the department, to a point of disposal described in paragraph three of this subdivision. (3) Points of disposal for storm water disposed
    of pursuant to this subdivision are: (A) the New York Harbor, or a point on a tidal creek acceptable to the commissioner as an adequate storm water outlet; provided that only building storm sewers and, if necessary, street storm sewers are constructed
    and that no sewage is discharged at such a point of disposal; and provided that such outlets shall only be used in compliance with applicable provisions of law; (B) a public street storm sewer or public street combined sewer, regardless of its distance
    from the property, to which the commissioner determines that conveyance of storm water is feasible, as described in subdivision (g) of this section, provided that no sewage shall be discharged into a street storm sewer; or (C) an existing private
    street storm sewer or private street combined sewer to which the commissioner determines that conveyance of storm water is feasible, as described in subdivision (g) of this section; provided that such street sewer connects with a public street sewer
    or, if it is a private storm sewer, discharges directly into the New York harbor, or into a point on a tidal creek acceptable to the commissioner as an adequate storm water outlet, in accordance with applicable provisions of law; and provided further
    that no sewage shall be discharged into a street storm sewer. (d) Required conveyance of storm water for off-site disposal, on or after January first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, when no public sewers into which discharge is feasible are located
    within five hundred feet of property. The requirements set forth in this subdivision shall apply to the construction of all new buildings for which new building permits have been filed on or after January first, nineteen hundred ninety-four. If the
    commissioner determines that no public street storm sewer or public street combined sewer is located within five hundred feet, measured along a street, alley or right-of-way, from any point on the boundary of a development or of a lot not contained
    in a development into which it would be feasible to discharge storm water from such development or such lot, an owner of a lot within such a development or of such a lot not within a development who is constructing or causing to be constructed a building
    on such lot shall dispose of storm water falling or coming to rest within such lot, together with storm water falling or coming to rest on all streets and other paved areas outside of such lot which are constructed or altered in connection with the
    construction of such building for the primary purpose of improving vehicular or pedestrian access thereto, by means acceptable to the commissioner and the commissioner of buildings, including but not limited to those set forth in section P110.13 of
    this reference standard; provided, however, that such persons shall not be required to construct street storm sewers or street combined sewers for distances greater than seven hundred fifty feet. (e) Maximum required capacity for street storm sewers
    or street combined sewers required by this section. The commissioner may require an owner of a lot or a development who is required by this section to construct street storm sewers or street combined sewers to construct such sewers with a capacity
    not to exceed twenty-five percent above and beyond the capacity which the commissioner determines is needed for the disposal of storm water falling or coming to rest on such property together with storm water falling or coming to rest on all streets
    and other paved areas outside of such property which are constructed or altered in connection with the construction of a building or buildings on such property for the primary purpose of improving vehicular or pedestrian access thereto. The department
    reserves the right to construct catch basins connected to such sewers at the cost and expense of the city, to alleviate flooding or ponding conditions, provided that the commissioner determines that the capacity of such sewers shall not be exceeded.
    (f) Repair of defects in catch basins and sewers required. Any owner of property who causes any catch basin or any sewer which shall lie outside of such property to be constructed pursuant to subdivision (b), (c) or (d) of this section shall cause
    all defects in such catch basin or sewer and all faults in its installation to be repaired for a period of two years after it has been installed, immediately after the department orders such person to do so. (g) Feasibility of discharging storm water
    into a street storm sewer or a street combined sewer. The commissioner shall determine that the discharge of storm water into a street storm sewer or a street combined sewer pursuant to this section is feasible if he or she finds that: (1) the sewer
    is of adequate capacity to receive all such storm water or would be adequate to receive it if the owner of property installed controlled flow storm water systems, in accordance with the requirements of section P110.6 of reference standard RS-16 of
    this code, to restrict the maximum anticipated storm water flow to a level set by the commissioner; (2) the sewer is in adequate physical condition to receive such storm water; (3) no physical obstacle which would make conveyance of such storm water
    to the sewer impracticable exists between the sewer and the boundaries of the development or lot from which such storm water shall be discharged; (4) conveyance of such storm water to the sewer is not impracticable because of the elevation of the
    sewer in relation to the development or lot from which such storm water shall be discharged; (5) the sewer is located in the same drainage area as all or most of the development or lot from which such storm water shall be discharged; and (6) no other
    factor reasonably related to the conveyance of such storm water from such development or lot to the sewer would make the discharge of such storm water into the sewer impracticable or undesirable as a proper means of storm water disposal. (h) Time
    by which construction of the part of the storm water drainage system required by this section shall be completed. The part of the storm water drainage system for property required by this section shall be completed prior to the issuance of a certificate
    of occupancy by the department of buildings for, and actual occupancy of, the building in connection with which such storm water drainage system is being constructed. (i) Performance bond, license and insurance required. If an owner of property is
    required to construct or repair defects in catch basins or sewers which shall lie outside of such property, in connection with the construction of a new building pursuant to this section, he or she shall provide the department with: (1) a performance
    bond or other security satisfactory to the department and approved as to form by the law department of the city for the full cost, as estimated by the department, of performing all such construction and repair work; (2) any license or other written
    instrument which the commissioner or the law department of the city may reasonably request which gives the department, its agents and contractors and the surety for a performance bond described in paragraph one of this subdivision the legal right
    to enter private property to perform such construction and repair work, pursuant to the terms of the performance bond or in accordance with the conditions of acceptance of other security described in paragraph one of this subdivision, and the legal
    right to connect to, to extend or to discharge storm water into any private sewer authorized as a point of disposal pursuant to paragraph three of subdivision (c) of this section, in the event that the owner of property fails to do so as required
    by this section; and (3) insurance of a kind and in an amount which the commissioner and the law department of the city deem satisfactory to insure the city fully for all risks of loss, damage to property or injury to or death of persons to whomever
    occurring arising out of or in connection with the performance of such sewer construction and repair work. (j) Contractual obligations of the city not abrogated. The provisions of this section shall not be construed to abrogate or contravene any contractual
    obligation of the city to construct storm water drainage systems or parts thereof. The requirements of subdivisions (b), (c), (d), (f) and (i) of this section shall be inapplicable to an owner of property insofar as they relate to any construction
    work required to be performed by the city pursuant to such a contractual obligation. (k) Determination by the board of standards and appeals. Any determination made by the board of standards and appeals with reference to the disposal of storm water,
    pursuant to the provisions of section 27-160 and section P110.2 of reference standard RS-16 of this code, shall be binding upon the department for the purposes of the enforcement and administration of this section.</text>
</level>