<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-410.8</num>
  <heading>Master fire suppression piping contractor business required.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-410.8 Master fire suppression piping contractor business required. No individual, corporation, partnership or other business association shall conduct a fire suppression piping contracting business in the city of New York, or employ the name "fire
    suppression piping" in its business name, unless the business is a master fire suppression business as follows: 1. No less than 51 percent of the control and voting capital stock of such entity is owned by one or more individuals who are licensed
    master fire suppression piping contractors, except as otherwise provided; and 2. All fire suppression piping work performed by such entity is performed by or under the direct and continuing supervision of such licensed master fire suppression piping
    contractor; 3. The person in charge of such work is such licensed master fire suppression piping contractor; and 4. The persons actually performing such work are in the direct employ of such master fire suppression piping contractor business as authorized
    by the code. Exception: A company, corporation, partnership or other business association or its predecessor that was engaged in fire suppression piping contractor work prior to January 25, 1990 may continue to do so in any one or more of such business
    forms without complying with the foregoing, if (i) application was made to the department prior to July 25, 1990, and (ii) necessary evidence was furnished on or prior to January 25, 1991, that such company, corporation, partnership or other business
    association or its predecessor had employed an average of 10 or more journeymen doing fire suppression piping contractor work for at least five days a week for a period of ten years or more out of the 20 years preceding July 25, 1990, provided, that
    such business continues to have all fire suppression piping contractor work conducted under the management and direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master fire suppression contractor in the direct employ of such business and that such licensed
    master fire suppression contractor is not otherwise interested in, associated with or employed by any other licensed master fire suppression contracting business operating in this city except as a joint venture in which such licensed master fire suppression
    contractor's employer is one of the joint venturers.</text>
</level>