<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-754</num>
  <heading>Minimum quantity of outside air for mechanical ventilation.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-754 Minimum quantity of outside air for mechanical ventilation. The minimum quantity of outside air required for mechanical ventilation in any occupiable room, where not otherwise prescribed, shall be determined according to table 12-2. Table 12-2
    Required Minimum Outdoor Air Supply and Exhaust (cfm per sq. ft.) ======================================================================== Ventilated Rooms Ventilated Rooms with Natural without Natural Index for Ventilation Ventilation Air Conditioned
    Ventilation Openings Openings Rooms ------------------------------------------------------------------------ Supply Exhaust Supply Exhaust Supply Exhaust ------------------------------------------------------------------------ 0- 300... 2.5 2.0 2.5
    2.0 1.5 1.5 301- 520... 2.0 1.5 2.0 1.5 1.2 1.2 521- 850... 1.5 1.25 1.5 1.25 0.9 0.9 851-1250... .. 1.0 1.0 1.0 0.6 0.6 1251-1650... .. 0.67 0.67 0.67 0.5 0.5 over 1650... .. .. 0.33 0.33 0.4 0.4 ========================================================================
    (a) Window requirements. To be credited as ventilating openings under the provisions of this subchapter, windows or other openings shall meet the requirements of section 27-749 of article six of this subchapter, and where mechanical supply ventilation
    is not provided, shall have a free openable area of at least one square foot per one hundred square feet of floor area. (b) Air conditioning. (1) In air conditioned rooms, the windows and other openings shall not be credited as such in computing the
    index for ventilation. Air conditioned rooms shall be considered as interior rooms. (2) Air that has been exhausted from an air conditioned space may be reconditioned by air conditioning apparatus and recirculated as equivalent outdoor air, provided
    that the total of supply air is not less than required for air conditioned rooms by table 12-2 and that the amount of actual outdoor air is at least thirty-three and one-third per cent of the required total. The actual outdoor air supply shall not,
    under any circumstances, be reduced to less than five cfm per occupant, except that these minimum requirements may be reduced by fifty per cent as provided in section 27-755 of this article. (c) Required exhaust. Required exhaust may be accomplished
    by raising the pressure within the space with consequent leakage through doors and windows, or by drawing the vitiated air from air conditioned spaces into the return air duct of air conditioning apparatus or into an exhaust duct discharging directly
    to the outdoor air. (d) Make-up air. A sufficient quantity of air to make the exhaust system effective shall be provided to the space being exhausted by one or by any combination of the following methods: (1) By supplying air to the space by means
    of a blower system. (2) By infiltration through louvres, registers, or other permanent openings in walls, doors, or partitions, adjoining spaces where air is supplied by one of these methods. (3) By infiltration through cracks around window sash and
    doors. (4) By other methods acceptable to the commissioner. (e) Prohibited use of recirculated air. Air drawn from any of the following spaces may not be recirculated; mortuary rooms; bathrooms or toilet rooms; or any space where an objectionable
    quantity of flammable vapors, dust, odors, or noxious gases is present. Air drawn from rooms that must be isolated to prevent the spread of infection shall not be recirculated, except that air drawn from hospital operating rooms may be recirculated,
    if in compliance with the following requirements: (1) There shall be a minimum of twenty-five total air changes per hour, of which five air changes per hour shall be outdoor air. (2) All fans serving exhaust systems shall be located at the discharge
    end of the system. (3) Outdoor air intakes shall be located at least twenty-five feet from exhaust outlets of ventilation systems and other exhaust discharges, combustion equipment stacks, medical surgical vacuum systems, and plumbing vent stacks,
    from areas which may collect vehicular exhaust such as off-street loading bays, and from areas which may collect other noxious fumes. The bottom of outdoor air intakes serving central systems if installed above a roof, shall be located at least three
    feet above roof level. (4) Positive air pressure shall be maintained at all times in relation to adjacent areas. (5) All ventilation or air conditioning systems serving such rooms shall be equipped with a filter bed of twenty-five per cent efficiency
    upstream of the air conditioning equipment and a filter bed of ninety per cent efficiency downstream of the supply fan, any recirculating spray water systems and water reservoir type humidifiers. All filter efficiencies shall be average atmospheric
    dust spot efficiencies tested in accordance with ASHRAE standard 52-68. (6) A manometer shall be installed across each filter bed. (7) Duct linings shall not be used in ventilation and air conditioning systems serving such rooms unless terminal filters
    of at least ninety per cent efficiency are installed downstream of linings. (8) Air supplied shall be delivered at or near the ceilings and all exhaust air shall be removed near floor level, with at least two exhaust outlets not less than three inches
    above the floor. (f) Outdoor air intakes. For high-rise office buildings erected pursuant to new building applications filed on or after the effective date of this section, outdoor air intakes serving spaces above the second story and serving spaces
    greater than ten thousand square feet of floor area shall be located at least twenty feet above ground level, at least twenty feet from exhaust outlets of ventilation systems and other exhaust discharges, and at least twenty feet from areas that may
    collect vehicular exhaust such as off-street loading bays.</text>
</level>