<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-532</num>
  <heading>Application; fingerprinting; fee; term.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-532 Application; fingerprinting; fee; term. a. An application for any license required under this subchapter or for any renewal thereof shall be made to the commissioner in such form and manner as the commissioner shall prescribe by rule. An applicant
    for any such license shall be fingerprinted by the department for the purpose of securing criminal history records from the state division of criminal justice services and shall pay a processing fee as required by the state division of criminal justice
    services. Where the applicant is a sole proprietorship, fingerprints shall be taken of the owner thereof; where the applicant is a partnership, fingerprints shall be taken of the general partners thereof; where the applicant is a corporation, association,
    firm or other business, fingerprints shall be taken of the officers, principals, directors, and stockholders of more than ten percent of the outstanding stock. Any person required to be fingerprinted hereunder shall furnish to the department three
    current passport size photographs of such persons. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the commissioner need not require applicants for licenses required under this subchapter to be fingerprinted if criminal history records concerning such applicants are
    not available from the state division of criminal justice services. b. There shall be a biennial fee for a license pursuant to this subchapter which shall be three hundred and forty dollars. c. All licenses issued pursuant to this subchapter shall
    expire on December thirty-first, in odd-numbered years, unless sooner suspended or revoked. d. The commissioner may refuse to issue any license required under this subchapter if such applicant or any employee or agent of such applicant has engaged
    in conduct which would constitute a basis for license suspension or revocation under this title.</text>
</level>