<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-101.4.2</num>
  <heading>Applications for construction document approval submitted prior to and within twelve months after the effective date of this code.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-101.4.2 Applications for construction document approval submitted prior to and within twelve months after the effective date of this code. Any work for which an application for construction document approval was submitted to the department prior
    to the effective date of this code and not thereafter abandoned, or for which an application for construction document approval is submitted to the department within a period of twelve months after such date may, at the option of the owner, be performed
    in its entirety in accordance with the provisions of this code, or in accordance with the 1968 building code, provided that such work is commenced within twelve months after the date of issuance of a permit therefore and is diligently carried on to
    completion. The commissioner may, for good cause, extend the time period for commencement of the work beyond 12 months. Where the owner elects to perform the work in compliance with the 1968 building code, the following conditions shall apply: 1.
    Except as otherwise limited by the commissioner, administration and enforcement of the 1968 building code shall be in accordance with this code, including but not limited to approval of construction documents, issuance of permits and certificates
    of occupancy, tests and inspections, penalties and enforcement. Controlled inspections and semi-controlled inspections as referenced in the 1968 building code shall be deemed to be special inspections and shall comply with the provisions of this code
    relating to special inspections. Materials regulated in their use by the 1968 building code shall be subject to applicable provisions of this code. 2. Safety of public and property during construction operations including demolition shall be governed
    by chapter 33 of the New York city building code.</text>
</level>