<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>18-118</num>
  <heading>Renting of stadium in Flushing Meadow park; exemption from down payment requirements.</heading>
  <text>ยง 18-118 Renting of stadium in Flushing Meadow park; exemption from down payment requirements. a. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, general, special or local, the city, acting by the commissioner, with the approval of the board of estimate,
    is hereby authorized and empowered from time to time to enter into contracts, leases or rental agreements with, or grant licenses, permits, concessions or other authorizations to, any person or persons, upon such terms and conditions, for such consideration,
    and for such term of duration as may be agreed upon by the city and such person or persons, whereby such person or persons are granted the right, for any purpose or purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section, to use, occupy or carry on
    activities in, the whole or any part of a stadium, with appurtenant grounds, parking areas and other facilities, to be constructed by the city on certain tracts of land described in subdivision c of this section, being a part of Flushing Meadow park
    and situated in the borough of Queens, city and state of New York, title to which tracts is now in the city. Prior to or after the expiration or termination of the terms of duration of any contracts, leases, rental agreements, licenses, permits, concessions
    or other authorizations entered into or granted pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision and subdivision b of this section, the city, in accordance with the requirements and conditions of this subdivision and subdivision b of this section, may
    from time to time enter into amended, new, additional or further contracts, leases or rental agreements with, and grant new, additional or further licenses, permits, concessions or other authorizations to, the same or any other person or persons for
    any purpose or purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section. b. Any contract, lease, rental agreement, license, permit, concession or other authorization referred to in subdivision a of this section may grant to the person or persons contracting
    with the city thereunder, the right to use, occupy or carry on activities in, the whole or any part of such stadium, grounds, parking areas and other facilities, (1) for any purpose or purposes which is of such a nature as to furnish to, or foster
    or promote among, or provide for the benefit of, the people of the city, recreation, entertainment, amusement, education, enlightenment, cultural development or betterment, and improvement of trade and commerce, including professional, amateur and
    scholastic sports and athletic events, theatrical, musical or other entertainment presentations, and meetings, assemblages, conventions and exhibitions for any purpose, including meetings, assemblages, conventions and exhibitions held for business
    or trade purposes, and other events of civic, community and general public interest, and/or (2) for any business or commercial purpose which aids in the financing of the construction and operation of such stadium, grounds, parking areas and facilities,
    and any additions, alterations or improvements thereto, or to the equipment thereof, and which does not interfere with the accomplishment of the purposes referred to in paragraph one of this subdivision. It is hereby declared that all of the purposes
    referred to in this subdivision are for the benefit of the people of the city and for the improvement of their health, welfare, recreation and prosperity, for the promotion of competitive sports for youth and the prevention of juvenile delinquency,
    and for the improvement of trade and commerce, and are hereby declared to be public purposes. c. The tracts of land referred to in subdivision a of this section are more particularly described as follows: 1. The area of land bounded on the north by
    the south side of Northern boulevard, on the east by the west side of One hundred twenty-sixth street, on the south by the north side of Roosevelt avenue, and on the west by the east side of Grand Central parkway. 2. The area of land bounded on the
    north by the south side of Roosevelt avenue, on the east by the west side of One hundred twenty-sixth street, on the south by lands of the city of New York occupied by the New York city transit authority, and on the west by the east side of Grand
    Central parkway, excepting from such area of land, the portion thereof fronting on Roosevelt avenue occupied by such authority as a substation. d. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section or the provisions of any other law, general,
    special or local, the commissioner, acting in behalf of the city, is hereby authorized and empowered, without the approval of the board of estimate, to enter into contracts, leases or rental agreements with or grant licenses, permits, concessions
    or other authorizations to any person or persons, upon such terms and conditions and for such consideration as may be agreed upon by the commissioner and such person or persons, for terms of duration, which, in the case of each such contract, lease,
    rental agreement, license, permit or other authorization, including renewals, shall not be in excess of one year, whereby such person or persons are granted the right to use, occupy or carry on activities in, the whole or any part of such stadium,
    grounds, parking areas and other facilities, for any purpose or purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section. Upon the expiration of the terms of duration of any of such contracts, leases, rental agreements, licenses, permits, concessions
    or other authorizations entered into or granted pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision, or within thirty days prior to such expiration or termination, the commissioner, in accordance with the requirements and conditions of this subdivision,
    acting in behalf of the city, and without the approval of the board of estimate, may from time to time enter into new, additional or further contracts, leases or rental agreements with, and may grant new, additional or further licenses, permits, concessions
    or other authorizations to, the same or any other person or persons for any purpose or purposes referred to in subdivision b of this section. e. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 107.00 of the local finance law, for the purpose of financing
    and paying the cost of the construction of such stadium, grounds, parking areas and facilities, and the construction of any additions, alterations or improvements thereto or to the equipment thereof, including a roof for such stadium and increased
    seating capacity therein, the city is hereby authorized and empowered, without providing from current funds any part of such cost or otherwise complying with the provisions of section 107.00 of such law, but upon compliance by the city with all other
    applicable provisions of the local finance law, to issue bonds and bond anticipation notes and to make expenditures from the proceeds of such bonds and bond anticipation notes or from any fund into which such proceeds are paid.</text>
</level>