<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-203</num>
  <heading>General definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-203 General definitions. When used in the New York city noise control code the following terms shall have the following meanings: (1) "A" level means the sound level as measured with a sound level meter using the "A" weighting network. The unit
    of measurement is the dB(A). This frequency weighting network for the measurement of sound levels shall comply with standards established by the American National Standards Institute specifications for sound level meters S1.4-1971, as amended or S1.4-1983,
    as amended. (2) Activity means any act or combination of acts which actually results in the production of sound. (3) Air compressor means a device which draws in air or gas, compresses it, and delivers it at a higher pressure. (4) Air horn means a
    device intended to produce a sound signal by means of compressed air or gas or exhaust gas. (5) Airport means an area of land or water that is used or intended to be used for the landing and take off of aircraft, and includes its buildings and facilities,
    if any. (6) Ambient sound means the sound level at a given location that exists as a result of the combined contribution in that location of all sound sources, excluding the contribution of a source or sources under investigation for violation of
    this code and excluding the contribution of extraneous sound sources. For purposes of the enforcement of this code, the ambient sound level of a given location may be determined based upon measurements taken at a comparable site (which includes but
    is not limited to comparable physical locations and time of day) in the nearby area. (7) Apparatus means any mechanism which prevents, controls, detects, measures or records the production of sound. (8) Audible status indicator means any sound reproduction
    device on a motor vehicle that emits or causes to be emitted any continuous or near continuous sound (exceeding 5 seconds if tonal in nature or any duration if verbal in nature) for the purpose of warning that an audible burglar alarm has been installed
    on such motor vehicle and is operational or for creating the appearance that such an alarm has been installed on such motor vehicle and is operational. (9) Authorized emergency vehicle means an authorized emergency vehicle as defined by section 101
    of the vehicle and traffic law. (10) Board means the environmental control board of the city of New York. (11) Building means a building as defined in section 27-232 of the administrative code. (12) Building aperture means any designed opening in
    a building to which a person may reasonably have access including but not limited to any door, gate, window, skylight or hatch. (13) Burglar alarm means any sound signal device designed and intended to produce a sound signal upon unauthorized entrance
    by a person into a building or motor vehicle. (14) "C" level means the sound level as measured with a sound level meter using the "C" weighting network. The unit of measurement is the dB(C). This frequency weighting network for the measurement of
    sound levels shall comply with standards established by the American National Standards Institute specifications for sound level meters S1.4-1971, as amended or S1.4-1983, as amended. (15) Certificate means an operating or temporary operating certificate.
    (16) Charter means the charter of the city of New York including all of its amendments. (17) Circulation device means any device which circulates a gas or fluid, including but not limited to any air conditioner, pump, cooling tower, fan or blower.
    (18) Claxon means any manually, mechanically, or electrically powered device, other than an emergency signal device, including but not limited to a motor vehicle horn, which is intended to, and when operated actually does, emit a sound signal. (19)
    This code means the New York city noise control code. (20) Commissioner means commissioner of environmental protection or his or her authorized representative. (21) Construction or construction work means any or all activity necessary or incidental
    to the erection, demolition, assembling, altering, installing or equipping of buildings, public or private highways, roads, premises, parks, utility lines including such lines in already-constructed tunnels, or other property, including land clearing,
    grading, excavating and filling. (22) Construction device means any device designed and intended for use in construction including, but not limited to any air compressor, pile driver, sledgehammer, bulldozer, pneumatic hammer, steam shovel, derrick,
    crane, steam or electric hoist, construction vehicle or pneumatic or electric tool. (23) Construction material means any material, regardless of composition, designed and customarily used in construction including but not limited to any rails, pillars,
    columns, beams, bricks, flooring, wall, ceiling or roofing material, gravel, sand, cement or asphalt. (24) Container means any receptacle, regardless of contents, manufactured from wood, metal, plastic, paper or any other material including but not
    limited to any barrel, basket, box, crate, tub, bottle, can or refuse container. (25) Decibel means the practical unit of measurement for sound pressure level; the number of decibels of a measured sound is equal to 20 times the logarithm to the base
    10 of the ratio of the sound pressure to the pressure of a reference sound (20 micropascals); abbreviated "dB". (26) Device means any mechanism which is intended to or which actually produces sound when operated or handled. (27) Department means the
    department of environmental protection. (28) Dwelling means any building lawfully occupied in whole or in part as the temporary or permanent residence of one or more natural persons. (29) Dynamic insertion loss means the difference between two sound
    pressure levels which are measured at the same point in space before and after a muffler is inserted between the measurement point and the sound source under operating conditions. (30) Emergency means a public calamity or an exposure of any person
    or property to imminent danger. (31) Emergency signal device means any gong, siren whistle, or siren or any air horn or any similar device the use of which on authorized emergency vehicles is permitted by subdivision twenty-six of section three hundred
    seventy-five of the vehicle and traffic law. (32) Exhaust source means a system which removes and transports air or gas from a device. (33) Extraneous sound is sound that is intense, intermittent, not representative of the relatively steady sound
    levels at a given location and not attributable to a source or sources under investigation for violation of this code. Such sound includes but is not limited to sirens of passing emergency vehicles, unusually loud motor vehicle braking (screeching)
    or exhaust noise, people shouting, animal vocalization, passing aircraft, horn honking, car door slamming and passing trains. Notwithstanding the foregoing provision, sounds that are individually persistent or controlling of the sound level at a given
    location shall not be considered to be extraneous sounds if they constitute more than 50 percent of the duration of an ambient or total sound level measurement such as for example the sound of a passing aircraft at a specific location if airplanes
    regularly pass over such location and the proximity of such passing aircraft to the location, its sound level, and the duration of such sound level, control the sound level at the given location at the time the sound source under investigation is
    being measured. For the purposes of the enforcement of this code, extraneous sounds are excluded when measuring the ambient sound level at a given location and when measuring the sound level of a source or sources under investigation for violation
    of this code except where such sounds are themselves under investigation for violation of this code. (34) Impulsive sound is sound that is of short duration, where each peak of sound lasts 2 seconds or less. The sound is characterized by abrupt onset
    and rapid decay. As used in this code, the term impulsive sound shall not include music. (35) Internal combustion engine means a device for the production of energy by means of the combustion under pressure of fossil fuel. (36) Lawn care device means
    any device powered mechanically, by electricity, by gasoline, by diesel fuel or by any other fuel, which is intended to be used or is actually used for the mowing of grass, the cutting or chipping of trees, tree roots or tree branches, or the clearing
    of leaves or other vegetation from lawns, sidewalks, public streets or public highways and shall include, but not be limited to, such devices as lawn mowers and lawn mower attachments, lawn edgers, leaf blowers, leaf vacuums, mulchers and chippers.
    (37) Lmax means the maximum measured sound level at any instant in time. (38) Motor vehicle means any device which is propelled by an engine in or upon which a person or material may be transported on the ground and which is intended to be operated
    upon a public highway. (39) Muffler means an apparatus generally consisting of but not limited to a series of chambers or baffles for the purpose of transmitting gases while reducing sound levels. (40) Owner means and includes the owner of the freehold
    of the premises or lesser estate therein, or mortgagee thereof, a lessee or agent of any of the above persons, a lessee of a device or his or her agent, a tenant, operator, or any other person who has regular control of a device or an apparatus. (41)
    Paving breaker means any powered construction device intended to cut or trench pavement, subbase macadam, gravel, concrete or hard ground. (42) Person means any individual, partnership, company, corporation, association, firm, organization, governmental
    agency, administration or department, or any other group of individuals, or any officer or employee thereof. (43) Personal audio device means a portable sound reproduction device as normally and customarily used for personal purposes including but
    not limited to a personal radio, phonograph, television receiver, tape recorder or compact disc player. For the purposes of this definition such term shall include a sound reproduction device installed in or operated from a motor vehicle whether or
    not portable. (44) Plainly audible sound means any sound for which any of the content of that sound, such as, but not limited to comprehensible musical rhythms, is communicated to a person using his or her unaided hearing faculties. For the purposes
    of the enforcement of this code, the detection of any component of music, including but not limited to the rhythmic bass by a person using his or her unaided hearing faculties is sufficient to verify plainly audible sound. It is not necessary for
    such person to determine the title, specific words or artist of such music. In the case of motor vehicles the detection of the sound of a muffler or of an exhaust by a person using his or her unaided hearing faculties is sufficient to verify plainly
    audible sound. Plainly audible sound does not require measurement with a sound level meter. (45) Power tool means any device powered mechanically, by electricity, by gasoline, by diesel fuel or by any other fuel, which is intended to be used or is
    actually used for, but shall not be limited to, the performance of such functions as cutting, nailing, stapling, sawing, vacuuming or drilling. (46) Public right-of-way means a public highway, road, street, avenue, alley, driveway, path, sidewalk,
    roadway or any other public place or public way. (47) Railroad means a railroad, other than a rapid transit railroad or street railroad, operated for public use in the conveyance of persons or property for compensation, with all bridges, ferries,
    tunnels, equipment, switches, spurs, tracks, stations and terminal facilities used, operated or owned by or in connection therewith. (48) Rapid transit railroad means a rapid transit railroad used for local service in the transportation of passengers
    as a common carrier for hire together with the appurtenances, facilities and equipment thereof. (49) Receiving property means real property, including but not limited to buildings, grounds, offices and dwelling units, from which sound levels from
    sound sources outside such property may be measured. For the purposes of this definition, individual offices or dwelling units within a building may constitute a receiving property. (50) Refuse collection vehicle means a motor vehicle designed or
    used to remove, collect, or transport refuse, solid waste or recyclables. (51) Sound means an oscillation in pressure, stress, particle displacement, particle velocity, etc., in a medium with internal forces (e.g., elastic, viscous), or the superposition
    of such propagated oscillation which evokes an auditory sensation. (52) Sound level meter means any instrument including a microphone, an amplifier, an output meter, and frequency weighting networks for the measurement of noise and sound levels in
    a specified manner and which complies with standards established by the American National Standards Institute specifications for sound level meters S1.4-1971, as amended or S1.4-1983, as amended. (53) Sound pressure level (decibels) means an expression
    of the acoustic pressure calculated as twenty times the logarithm to the base ten of the ratio of the root mean square of the pressure of the sound to the reference pressure, 20 micropascals. (54) Sound reproduction device means a device intended
    primarily for the production or reproduction of sound, including but not limited to any musical instrument, radio receiver, television receiver, tape recorder, phonograph or electronic sound amplifying system. (55) Sound signal means any sound produced
    by a sound signal device designed to transmit information. (56) Sound signal device means a device designed to produce a sound signal when operated, including but not limited to any claxon, air horn, whistle, bell, gong, siren, but not an emergency
    signal device. (57) Sound source means any activity or device that emits sound. (58) This code means the New York city noise control code. (59) Total sound level means that measured sound level that represents the combined sound level of the source
    or sources under investigation and the ambient sound level. Total sound level measurements shall exclude extraneous sound sources. (60) Tunnel means an underground passage which is intended for use as a railway, aqueduct, road, sewer or major utility
    artery. (61) Tunneling means any activity necessary or incidental to the construction of any tunnel, including the sinking of shafts to tunnel or to an intermediate level and the surface activities required to sink the shafts and construct the tunnel.
    (62) Unreasonable noise means any excessive or unusually loud sound that disturbs the peace, comfort or repose of a reasonable person of normal sensitivities, injures or endangers the health or safety of a reasonable person of normal sensitivities,
    or which causes injury to plant or animal life, or damage to property or business. (63) Refuse collection facility means any structure, building or other premises at which solid waste is received for the purpose of subsequent transfer to another location
    regardless of whether such solid waste is subject to any processing or reduction in volume at such structure, building or premises.</text>
</level>