<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-408.3.1</num>
  <heading>Experience.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-408.3.1 Experience. All applicants for a master plumber license shall submit satisfactory proof establishing that the applicant: 1. Has had at least seven years total experience within the 10 years prior to application in the design and installation
    of plumbing systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master plumber in the United States, with at least two years of such experience as a registered journeyman plumber in accordance with the provisions of article 409, except
    that during the three years immediately following the effective date of this code there shall be no requirement for such registered journeyman plumber experience; 2. Has received a bachelor's degree in engineering or appropriate engineering technology
    from an accredited college or university and has had at least five years total experience within the seven years prior to application in the design and installation of plumbing systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master
    plumber in the United States, where at least two years of such experience were in New York city; 3. Is an architect or engineer with at least three years of experience within the five years prior to application in the design and installation of plumbing
    systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master plumber in the United States, where at least one year of such experience was in New York city; or 4. Has had at least seven years total experience within the 10 years prior to
    application, with at least two years of such experience working in the design and installation of plumbing systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master plumber in the United States. The balance of such required experience
    may be obtained by performing maintenance, replacement and repair plumbing work on existing buildings while in the employ of a city agency under the direct and continuing supervision of a licensed master plumber supervisor employed by the city agency.
    Three years after the effective date of this code the two years experience in the design and installation of plumbing systems set forth above may only be satisfied by working as a registered journeyman plumber. 5. An employee of a government agency,
    private inspection agency or other entity, acceptable to the commissioner, whose duties primarily involve the inspection of plumbing work for compliance with the New York city plumbing code and/or other laws relating to the installation, alteration
    or repair of plumbing systems shall be credited with fifty percent (50%) of the number of years that he or she has been satisfactorily employed in such duties within the ten (10) year period prior to application, which, however, in no event, shall
    exceed two and one-half (2 1/2) years credit of satisfactory experience. The balance of the required seven years must have been obtained by working in the design and installation of plumbing systems under the direct and continuing supervision of a
    licensed master plumber in the United States except that the requirement of paragraph 1 of this section 28-408.3.1 that an applicant's working experience must have been within the ten (10) year period prior to application shall not apply to such balance
    of the work experience required pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
</level>