<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-829</num>
  <heading>Location of tanks.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-829 Location of tanks. (a) Inside of buildings, above ground, on the lowest floor. (1) TANK CAPACITY OF FIVE HUNDRED FIFTY GALLONS OR LESS. Storage tanks having a capacity of five hundred fifty gallons or less may be installed above ground on the
    lowest floor of a building, provided that such tanks are mounted on adequate noncombustible supports, with the tank anchored thereto. No more than five hundred fifty gallons of total storage capacity may be connected to one burner or may be installed
    without the protection provided in paragraph two or three of this subdivision. (2) TANK CAPACITY MORE THAN FIVE HUNDRED FIFTY GALLONS BUT LESS THAN ELEVEN HUNDRED GALLONS. Storage tanks having a capacity of more than five hundred fifty gallons but
    less than eleven hundred gallons may be installed above ground on the lowest floor of a building, provided that all portions of such tanks above the floor are completely enclosed with noncombustible construction having at least a two hour fire resistance
    rating. Weep holes one inch in diameter shall be provided at least every three feet along the bottom of the enclosure unless at least fifteen inches of clearance, together with access door, is provided between the tank and the enclosure. (3) TANK
    CAPACITY ELEVEN HUNDRED GALLONS OR MORE. Storage tanks having a capacity of eleven hundred gallons or more may be installed above ground on the lowest floor of a building, provided that all portions of such tanks above the floor are completely enclosed
    with noncombustible construction having at least a three hour resistance rating. At least fifteen inches clearance shall be provided over the tanks and on all sides between the tanks and the enclosure. A noncombustible access door, constructed so
    as to preserve the integrity of the fire resistive enclosure, shall be installed in the enclosure above the point where the capacity of the enclosure below the door sill would be equal to the capacity of the largest tank installed. When the longest
    inside dimension of the enclosure exceeds thirty-five feet, access doors shall be installed at intervals not exceeding twelve feet. Columns, pipes, or similar obstructions may project into the required fifteen inches of space within the enclosure,
    provided that access door or doors are so arranged that all portions of the enclosure are accessible for servicing. (4) MAXIMUM TANK SIZE. The capacity of individual storage tanks in no case shall exceed twenty thousand gallons. (b) Inside of building
    above the lowest floor. (1) Fuel oil storage tanks having a capacity of two hundred seventy-five gallons or less may be installed inside of buildings above the lowest story when provided with a four inch thick concrete or masonry curb, or with a metal
    pan of gauge equal to the gauge of the tank, completely surrounding the tank and of sufficient height to contain two times the capacity of the tank. The number of such oil storage tanks shall be limited to one per story. (2) Storage tanks having a
    capacity of two hundred seventy-five gallons or less, installed above the lowest floor inside a building shall be filled by means of a transfer pump supplied from a primary storage tank located and installed as otherwise required by this subchapter.
    A separate transfer pump and piping circuit shall be provided for each storage tank installed above the lowest floor. No intermediate pumping stations shall be provided between the storage tank and the transfer pump. Appropriate devices shall be provided
    for the automatic and manual starting and stopping of the transfer pumps so as to prevent the overflow of oil from these storage tanks. (3) A float switch shall be provided with the curb or pan around the storage tank and shall be arranged so as to
    sound an alarm and stop the transfer pump in case of failure of the tank or the control in the tank. The operation of the float switch shall be tested at least once each week. An alarm bell shall be located in the same room with the tank and a visual
    and audible alarm shall be located in a maintenance office. The enclosing and sealing of switches and wiring shall conform to the requirements of the electrical code of the city of New York for devices located in an atmosphere of flammable vapors.
    (c) Inside of buildings, below ground. (1) Storage tanks having a capacity greater than two hundred seventy-five gallons may be buried inside a building provided that the top of the tank is at least two feet below floor level. In lieu of two feet
    of earth over the tank, the tank may be covered by concrete flooring having the same thickness as the basement floor, but not less than four inch concrete meeting the requirement of subchapter ten of this chapter and reinforced with two inch by two
    inch mesh of at least no. 20 U.S. standard gauge steel wire. Tanks shall be placed in firm soil and shall be surrounded by clean sand or well-tamped earth, free from ashes and other corrosive substances, and free from stones that will not pass through
    a one inch mesh. When necessary to prevent floating, tanks shall be securely anchored. (2) No tank shall be buried within three feet of any foundation wall or footing. (d) Outside of building, below ground. (1) Storage tanks located outside of buildings
    and below ground shall be buried with the top of the tank at least two feet below ground. Tanks shall be placed in firm soil and shall be surrounded by clean sand or well-tamped earth, free from ashes or other corrosive substance, and free from stones
    that will not pass through a one inch mesh. When necessary to prevent floating, tanks shall be securely anchored. (2) No tank shall be buried within three feet of any foundation wall or footing. (e) Outside of buildings, above ground. (1) Storage
    tanks of a capacity greater than two hundred seventy-five gallons located outside of buildings above ground shall be not less than one and one-quarter (1 1/4) tank diameters and in no case less than ten feet. from the line of adjoining property, the
    nearest building or adjacent tank. The minimum clearance between individual tanks located outside of buildings above ground and the line of adjoining property which may be built upon shall be fixed by the following formula: G - 275 M.C. = 10 + 4 (--------)
    5000 where: M.C. = minimum clearance from nearest surface of tank to adjoining property, in feet. G = capacity of tank, in gallons. The maximum allowable capacity of fuel oil storage tanks located outside of buildings above ground shall be one hundred
    thousand gallons. (2) Tanks shall be located so as not to obstruct or interfere with any means of egress. (3) Each storage tank shall be protected by an embankment or dike. Such protection shall have a capacity at least one and one-half times the
    capacity of the tank so surrounded and shall be at least four feet high, but in no case shall the protection be higher than one-quarter the height of the tank when the height of the tank exceeds sixteen feet. Embankments or dikes shall be made of
    earth work with clay core, of masonry, of reinforced concrete or of steel. Earth work embankments shall be firmly and compactly built of good earth free from stones, vegetable matter, etc., and shall have a flat section of at least three feet at the
    top and a slope of at least one and one-half to two on all sides. Concrete, masonry or steel dikes shall be designed so as to conform safely all of the oil in the tank so surrounded. Embankments or dikes shall be continuous and unpierced, and the
    outside toe shall be located at least five feet inside of the property line, and no less than five feet from a driveway or parking area. (f) Tanks located along line of subways. (1) No buried tank shall be placed within twenty feet of the outside
    line of a subway wall. Where an above ground tank within a building is located within the outer lines of the subway, or within twenty feet of the outside line of the subway wall, such tank shall be placed within a welded steel oiltight pan of not
    less than no. 18 manufacturer's standard gauge metal suitably reinforced and of capacity to contain the contents of the tank. (2) For the purpose of the foregoing requirement, a subway shall be deemed to include any subsurface railroad or rapid transit
    roadbed.</text>
</level>