<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3014</num>
  <heading>Master electrician's and special electrician's licenses and fees.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-3014 Master electrician's and special electrician's licenses and fees. a. Before any master electrician's or special electrician's license will be issued or renewed, the applicant shall pay a license or renewal fee as prescribed by the department's
    rules. The commissioner may exempt any agency, as defined in chapter fifty-two of the charter, from paying the aforementioned fees for licensed special electricians who are employees of such agencies. b. Seal. The holder of a master electrician's
    license shall be issued a seal, of a design or form authorized by the commissioner, bearing the holder's full name, license number, and the legend "licensed master electrician." The holder of a special electrician's license shall be issued a seal,
    of a design and form authorized by the commissioner, bearing the holder's full name, license number, and the legend "licensed special electrician." c. No license shall be transferable. The seal is the property of the department and is not transferable
    by the licensee. d. The loss or theft of a license or seal must be reported to the department within five calendar days. Before any license or seal will be reissued, the applicant shall pay a reissuance fee as prescribed by the department's rules.
    e. An application for a change of license from master electrician to special electrician shall involve the issuance of a new license and seal with or without examinations as the commissioner may direct. f. An application for a change of license from
    special to master electrician shall be granted only upon compliance by the special electrician with all applicable provisions of this chapter and the rules of the department. g. Each license and seal shall be issued for one year and the full fee shall
    be payable irrespective of the date of issue. h. Not more than one license and/or seal shall be issued to an individual and no individual shall make or cause to be made a duplicate of such license or seal.</text>
</level>