<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-889</num>
  <heading>Adjoining gas vents.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-889 Adjoining gas vents. (a) Responsibility of owner of taller building. Whenever a building is erected, enlarged, or increased in height so that any portion of such building, except chimneys or vents, extends above the top of a previously constructed
    gas vent within fifty feet, the owner of the new or altered building shall have the responsibility of altering such gas vents that have their outlets within fifty feet measured horizontally, of any part of the newly erected building. Such alterations
    shall be at the expense of the owner of the new or altered building and shall be accomplished by one of the following means or a combination thereof: (1) Carry up such previously constructed vents from gas-fired equipment to the height required in
    section 27-888 of this article. (2) Offset such gas vents to a distance of more than fifty feet from the new or altered building, provided that the new location of the outlet of the offset gas vent shall comply with the requirements of this subchapter.
    (b) Protection of draft. After the alteration of a gas vent as described in subdivision (a) of this section, it shall be the responsibility of the owner of the new or altered building to provide any mechanical devices or equipment necessary to maintain
    the proper draft in the equipment. (c) Written notification. The owner of the new or altered building shall notify the owner of the building affected in writing at least forty-five days before starting the work and request written consent to do such
    work. Such notice shall be accompanied by a written description or a plan showing how the proposed alterations are to be made. (d) Approval. The method of correction shall be subject to the approval of the commissioner. (e) Refusal of consent. If
    consent is not granted by the owner of the previously constructed or altered building to do the alteration work required by paragraph one of subdivision (a) of this section, such owner shall signify his or her refusal in writing to the owner of the
    new or altered building and to the commissioner, and the owner of the new or altered building has submitted plans that conform to the requirements of this section, he or she shall thereupon be released from any responsibility for the operation of
    his or her equipment and for any health hazard or nuisance that may occur as a result of the newly erected or modified building. Such responsibilities shall then be assumed by the owner of the previously constructed building. Likewise, should such
    owner neglect to grant consent within forty-five days from the date of written request or fail to signify his or her refusal, he or she shall then assume all responsibilities as prescribed above. (f) Procedures. It shall be the obligation of the owner
    of the new or altered building to: (1) Schedule this work so as to create a minimum of disturbance to the occupants of the affected building. (2) Provide such essential services as are normally supplied by the equipment while it is out of service.
    (3) Where necessary, support such extended gas vents from his or her building or carry up such vents within his or her building. (4) Provide for the maintenance, repair, and/or replacement of such alterations. (5) Make such alterations of the same
    material as the original gas vent except where the owner of the vent affected shall give his or her consent to do otherwise. All work shall be done in such fashion as to maintain the architectural esthetics of the existing building. (g) Existing violations.
    Any existing violations on the previously constructed equipment shall be corrected by the owner of the equipment before any equipment is added or alterations made at the expense of the owner of the new or altered building. (h) The commissioner may
    grant a variance in accordance with the provisions of section 27-107 of article one of subchapter one of this chapter.
  </text>
</level>