<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-375</num>
  <heading>License plate.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-375 License plate. Upon the payment of the license fee the commissioner shall issue a license to the owner of the sightseeing bus or horse drawn cab together with a license plate to be securely affixed to a conspicuous and indispensable part of
    such sightseeing bus or securely and conspicuously affixed to the rear axle of such horse drawn cab, on which shall be clearly set forth the license number of such sightseeing bus or horse drawn cab. The license plate issued to the licensee may, in
    the discretion of the commissioner, be a plate of a permanent nature with a replaceable date tag attached thereto, indicating the expiration date of the plate during each license year and the issuance of such a plate with such date tag to a person
    possessing such a plate, shall be deemed issuance of a license plate. Such license plate and the replaceable date tag to be issued from year to year to be attached thereto, shall be of such material, form, design and dimension and set forth such distinguishing
    number or other identification marks as the commissioner shall prescribe. The commissioner upon renewal of the license hereunder, may continue the use of the license plate for as many additional license years as he or she in his or her discretion
    may determine, in which event he or she shall issue and deliver to the licensee a replaceable date tag as evidence of renewal of the license, which shall be attached or affixed in such manner as he or she may prescribe by rule. The failure to affix
    or display such date tag in a manner prescribed by the commissioner shall constitute a violation of this section. In the event of the loss, mutilation or destruction of any license plate or date tag issued hereunder, the owner may file such statement
    and proof of facts as the commissioner shall require, with a fee of twenty-five dollars, at the department, and the department shall issue a duplicate or substitute license plate or date tag.</text>
</level>