<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-163.1</num>
  <heading>Purchase of cleaner light-duty and medium-duty vehicles.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-163.1 Purchase of cleaner light-duty and medium-duty vehicles. a. Definitions. When used in this section or in section 24-163.2 of this chapter: (1) "Alternative fuel" means natural gas, liquefied petroleum gas, hydrogen, electricity, and any other
    fuel which is at least eighty-five percent, singly or in combination, methanol, ethanol, any other alcohol or ether. (2) "Alternative fuel motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle that is operated using solely an alternative fuel or is operated using
    solely an alternative fuel in combination with gasoline or diesel fuel, and shall not include bi-fuel motor vehicles. (3) "Average fuel economy" means the sum of the fuel economies of all motor vehicles in a defined group divided by the number of
    motor vehicles in such group. (4) "Bi-fuel motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle that is capable of being operated by both an alternative fuel and gasoline or diesel fuel, but may be operated exclusively by any one of such fuels. (5) "City agency"
    means a city, county, borough, administration, department, division, bureau, board or commission, or a corporation, institution or agency of government, the expenses of which are paid in whole or in part from the city treasury. (6) "Equivalent carbon
    dioxide" means the metric measure used to compare the emissions from various greenhouse gases emitted by motor vehicles based upon their global warming potential according to the California air resources board or the United States environmental protection
    agency. (7) "Fuel economy" means the United States environmental protection agency city mileage published label value for a particular motor vehicle, pursuant to section 32908(b) of title 49 of the United States code. (8) "Gross vehicle weight rating"
    means the value specified by the manufacturer of a motor vehicle model as the maximum design loaded weight of a single vehicle of that model. (9) "Light-duty vehicle" means any motor vehicle having a gross vehicle weight rating of 8,500 pounds or
    less. (10) "Medium-duty vehicle" means any motor vehicle having a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 8,500 pounds but not more than 14,000 pounds. (11) "Motor vehicle" means a vehicle operated or driven upon a public highway which is propelled
    by any power other than muscular power, except electrically-driven mobility assistance devices operated or driven by a person with a disability, provided, however, that this term shall not include vehicles that are specially equipped for emergency
    response by the department, office of emergency management, sheriff's office of the department of finance, police department, fire department or department of correction. (12) "Purchase" means purchase, lease, borrow, obtain by gift or otherwise acquire.
    (13) "Use-based fuel economy" means the total number of miles driven by all light-duty and medium-duty vehicles in the city fleet during the previous fiscal year divided by the total amount of fuel used by such vehicles during the previous fiscal
    year. b. (1) Except as provided for in paragraphs two and three of this subdivision, beginning July 1, 2006, each light-duty vehicle and medium-duty vehicle that the city purchases shall achieve the highest of the following ratings, with subparagraph
    one of this paragraph being the highest vehicle rating, applicable to motor vehicles certified to California LEV II standards and available within the applicable model year for a light-duty vehicle or medium-duty vehicle that meets the requirements
    for the intended use by the city of such vehicle: (i) zero emission vehicle (ZEV) (ii) advanced technology partial zero emission vehicle (ATPZEV) (iii) partial zero emission vehicle (PZEV) (iv) super ultra low emission vehicle (SULEV) (v) ultra low
    emission vehicle (ULEV) (vi) low emission vehicle (LEV) (2) The city shall not be required to purchase a zero emission vehicle or advanced technology partial zero emission vehicle in accordance with paragraph one of this subdivision if the only available
    vehicle or vehicles that achieve such a rating cost greater than fifty percent more than the lowest bid as determined by the applicable procurement process for a vehicle available in the next highest rating category that meets the requirements for
    the intended use by the city of such vehicle. (3) Notwithstanding the requirements of paragraph one of this subdivision, such requirements need not apply to a maximum of five percent of the light-duty vehicles and medium-duty vehicles purchased within
    each fiscal year. (4) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2005, at least eighty percent of the light-duty vehicles the city purchases in such fiscal year shall be alternative fuel motor vehicles. c. (1) The city shall not purchase additional bi-fuel
    motor vehicles. (2) Any bi-fuel motor vehicle that is owned or operated by the city shall be powered on the alternative fuel on which it is capable of operating, except that such vehicle may be operated on gasoline or diesel fuel (i) where, as of
    the date of enactment of this section, such vehicle is no longer mechanically able to operate on such alternative fuel and cannot be repaired, or (ii) solely for the period of time recommended by the vehicle manufacturer. d. (1) Not later than October
    1, 2005, the city shall complete an inventory of the fuel economy of all light-duty vehicles purchased by the city during the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2004, and shall calculate the average fuel economy of all such light-duty vehicles. (2) The
    city shall achieve the following minimum percentage increases in the average fuel economy of all light-duty vehicles purchased by the city during the following fiscal years, relative to the average fuel economy of all such vehicles purchased by the
    city during the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2004, calculated pursuant to paragraph one of this subdivision: (i) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2006, five percent; (ii) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2007, eight percent; (iii) For the
    fiscal year beginning July 1, 2008, ten percent; (iv) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2009, twelve percent; (v) For the fiscal years beginning July 1, 2010 and July 1, 2011, fifteen percent; (vi) For the fiscal years beginning July 1, 2012,
    July 1, 2013 and July 1, 2014, eighteen percent; (vii) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2015, twenty percent; (viii) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2016, twenty percent; (ix) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2017, twenty-five percent;
    (x) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2018, twenty-five percent; (xi) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2019, thirty percent; (xii) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2020, thirty percent; (xiii) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2021,
    thirty-five percent; and (xiv) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2022, and for each fiscal year thereafter, forty percent. e. (1) Not later than January 1, 2007, and not later than January 1 of each year thereafter, the mayor shall submit to the
    comptroller and the speaker of the council a report regarding the city's purchase of light-duty vehicles and medium-duty vehicles during the immediately preceding fiscal year. The information contained in this report shall also be included in the
    preliminary mayor's management report and the mayor's management report for the relevant fiscal year and shall include, but not be limited to, for each city agency: (i) the total number of light-duty vehicles and medium-duty vehicles and all other
    motor vehicles, respectively, purchased by such agency; (ii) the total number of light-duty vehicles and medium-duty vehicles, respectively, purchased by such agency that are certified to California LEV II standards in each of the six rating categories
    listed in subdivision b of this section, disaggregated according to vehicle model; (iii) the reason as to why each vehicle model was purchased, rather than a vehicle model rated in a higher category listed in subdivision b of this section; (iv) if
    an available zero emission vehicle or advanced technology partial zero emission vehicle is not purchased, in accordance with paragraph two of subdivision b of this section, specific information regarding the cost analysis that formed the basis for
    such decision; (v) the percentage of light-duty vehicles and medium-duty vehicles purchased within each fiscal year in accordance with paragraphs one and two of subdivision b of this section; and (vi) for the report required not later than January
    1, 2007, the percentage of light-duty vehicles purchased by the city during the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2005 that were alternative fuel motor vehicles. (2) Not later than January 1, 2007, and not later than January 1 of each year thereafter,
    the mayor shall submit to the comptroller and the speaker of the council a report regarding the fuel economy of light-duty vehicles purchased by the city during the immediately preceding fiscal year. The information contained in this report shall
    also be included in the preliminary mayor's management report and the mayor's management report for the relevant fiscal year and shall include, but not be limited to: (i) the average fuel economy of all light-duty vehicles purchased by the city during
    the preceding fiscal year; and (ii) the percentage increase in the average fuel economy of all such light-duty vehicles, relative to the average fuel economy of all light-duty vehicles purchased by the city during the fiscal year beginning July 1,
    2004, calculated pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision d of this section, that this total amount represents. (3) Not later than January 1, 2016, and not later than January 1 of each year thereafter, the mayor shall submit to the comptroller and
    the speaker of the council a report regarding the use-based fuel economy for the immediately preceding fiscal year. The information contained in such report shall also be included in the preliminary mayor's management report and the mayor's management
    report for the relevant fiscal year. f. (1) Beginning July 1, 2006, for each fiscal year, the city shall measure the amount of fuel consumed by the city's fleet of motor vehicles and the equivalent carbon dioxide emitted by such vehicles, for each
    type of fuel consumed by such vehicles. (2) For the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2006, and for each fiscal year thereafter, the department shall publish on its website by October 1 following the close of each fiscal year and the mayor shall include
    in the preliminary mayor's management report and the mayor's management report for the relevant fiscal year the estimated total amount of fuel consumed by the city's fleet of motor vehicles and the estimated total amount of equivalent carbon dioxide
    emitted by such vehicles, disaggregated according to fuel type. For the purposes of this subdivision, the city's fleet of motor vehicles shall include vehicles specially equipped for emergency response by the department, office of emergency management,
    sheriff's office of the department of finance, police department or fire department. g. This section shall not apply: (1) where federal or state funding precludes the city from imposing the purchasing requirements of this section; (2) to purchases
    that are emergency procurements pursuant to section three hundred fifteen of the charter; or (3) except for subdivision f of this section, to diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles subject to paragraph two of subdivision b of section 24-163.4 of this
    chapter. h. To the extent not prohibited by law, alternative fuel motor vehicles may be purchased by the city in concert with any public or private entity.</text>
</level>