<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-109</num>
  <heading>Registrations generally.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-109 Registrations generally. (a) In addition to the registrations required by subdivision (b) of this section the commissioner may order the written registration of emission sources other than those located in one or two family dwellings and motor
    vehicles. A period of sixty days from publication in the City Record of the commissioner's order shall be allowed for the filing of such registration. In cases of an emergency, the commissioner may designate a shorter period of time. (b) No person
    shall cause or permit the following unless he or she has first registered with the department: (1) the spraying of any insulating material in or upon any building or other structure during its construction, alteration or repair; (2) the demolition
    of any building or other structure, unless the building or structure is being demolished pursuant to chapter one of title seventeen or article eight of subchapter two of chapter one of title twenty-six of the code. (3) The installation, alteration,
    use or operation of any fuel burning equipment which in the aggregate, feeding into a common emission point, has a Btu input or gross output equal to or greater than three hundred fifty thousand Btu per hour but less than one million Btu per hour.
    (4) The installation, alteration, use or operation of any fuel burning equipment which in the aggregate, feeding into a common emission point, has a Btu input or gross output equal to or greater than three hundred fifty thousand Btu per hour but less
    than 2.8 million Btu per hour and which uses a fuel gas, gasoline, or fuel oil grades Nos. 1 or 2 as classified by the American society for testing and materials. (c) Registration shall be made on forms furnished by the department. (1) Forms for registration
    pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section may require information concerning the unit of equipment covered by the registration, the kind and amount of air contaminant emitted by the equipment, medical and other scientific information concerning
    the effects of the air contaminant on persons, animals, and plants, and any additional information required by the commissioner for the purpose of enforcing this code. (2) Forms for registration pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision (b) of this
    section shall require information concerning the kind and amount of insulating material that will be sprayed, the composition of the insulating material, medical and other scientific information concerning the effects of the insulating material on
    persons, animals, and property, the precautions that will be taken to prevent the insulating material from being emitted into the open air, and any additional information required by the commissioner for the purpose of enforcing this code. Registration
    for spraying of insulating material shall be filed at least five days prior to commencement of such spraying work. (3) Forms for registration pursuant to paragraph two of subdivision (b) of this section shall require information concerning the kind
    and amount of particulate matter that it is reasonably anticipated may be released as a result of the demolition, the precautions that will be taken to prevent particulate matter from becoming air-borne, and any additional information required by
    the commissioner for the purpose of enforcing this code. (4) The registrant shall maintain the registration in current status by notifying the commissioner of any change in any item of information furnished in compliance with this section, other than
    a change in ownership, within a reasonable time not to exceed fifteen days. (d) Registration shall be made by the following persons: (1) If the registrant is a partnership or group other than a corporation, the registration shall be made by an individual
    who is a member of the group. (2) If the registrant is a corporation, the registration shall be made by an officer of the corporation. (3) In the case of registration pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section by the owner of the equipment. (4) In
    the case of registration pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision (b) of this section, by the person responsible for the construction, alteration or repair of the building or other structure in or upon which spraying will occur. (5) In the case of
    registration pursuant to paragraph two of subdivision (b) of this section, by the person responsible for the demolition of the building or structure. (e) Registration shall be made in duplicate. Upon approval thereof, a stamped copy of the registration
    shall be returned to the registrant, and shall be displayed in accordance with section 24-113 of this subchapter. * (f) Registration of equipment or apparatus shall be valid for a period of up to three years from the date of approval of the initial
    registration or renewal, unless sooner revoked or cancelled by the commissioner. Where a registration is renewed after its expiration, the registration fee charged in accordance with the provisions of this part shall be increased on a monthly pro-rated
    basis for the period of time between such expiration and renewal, unless it is shown to the satisfaction of the commissioner that registration was not required under the provisions of this chapter. * NB Amended L.L. 49/85 ยง 2, language juxtaposed
    per Ch. 907/85 ยง 14</text>
</level>