<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-121</num>
  <heading>Permits, exemptions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-121 Permits, exemptions. (a) A permit shall not be required for the installation or alteration of the following equipment or apparatus: (1) Air conditioning, ventilating, or exhaust systems not designed to remove air contaminant generated by or
    released from equipment. (2) Air contaminant detector or air contaminant recorder. (3) Dilution ventilating systems for control of welding fumes and gases. (4) Exhaust systems for controlling steam and heat. (5) Fuel burning equipment, other than
    smoke house generators, which in the aggregate has a Btu input or gross output of not more than one million Btu per hour. (6) Fuel burning equipment which in the aggregate has a Btu input or a gross output of less than 2.8 million Btu per hour and
    uses a fuel gas, gasoline or fuel oil grade No. 1 or 2 as classified by the American society for testing and materials. (7) Fumigation vaults having an environmental rating of D in accordance with section 24-153 of this code. (8) Installations for
    the preparation of food for on-site consumption or retail purchase, unless required pursuant to regulations issued by the commissioner. (9) Internal combustion engines used to power motor vehicles or other stationary engines which have a Btu input
    of not more than three hundred fifty thousand Btu per hour. (10) Laboratory equipment used exclusively for chemical or physical analyses of non-radioactive material. (11) Refrigeration equipment used for cold storage. (12) Sewing equipment. (13) Vents
    used exclusively by tanks used in the storage of: (i) Residual and distillate fuel oil; or (ii) (A) sanitary or storm drainage systems; or (B) steam or air safety valves; or (iii) Liquid soap, liquid detergent, tallow or vegetable oil, waxes, or emulsions.
    (14) Type metal crucible or melting pots used in connection with printing presses and having an environmental rating of D in accordance with section 24-153 of this code. (15) Vacuum cleaning systems used exclusively for industrial, commercial or residential
    housekeeping. (16) Vents used exclusively for: (i) Sanitary or storm drainage systems; or (ii) Steam or air safety valves; or (iii) Storage tanks. (17) Ventilating or exhaust systems for paint storage rooms or cabinets. (18) Water cooling towers and
    water cooling ponds not used for evaporative cooling of process water, or not used for evaporative cooling of condensed water for jet or barometric condensers. (b) A permit shall not be required for the installation or alteration of equipment or apparatus
    in one and two-family dwellings. (c) Although a permit is not required for the installation or alteration of the equipment or apparatus listed in subdivisions (a) and (b) of this section, such equipment and apparatus shall otherwise comply with this
    code. (d) A permit shall not be required to begin an alteration of equipment or apparatus if delaying the alteration may endanger life or the supplying of essential services. The department shall be notified in writing of the alteration within twenty-four
    hours or on the first working day, after the alteration is commenced, and an application for a permit shall be filed within fourteen days after the day the alteration is commenced. (e) Nothing in this section shall in any way alter, affect, or change
    any other requirement or law of any other governmental agency or department.
  </text>
</level>