<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-946</num>
  <heading>Fire pumps.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-946 Fire pumps. (a) Additional water supply. Additional water supply shall be provided for standpipes in buildings over three hundred feet high. The primary water supply to the standpipe system shall be supplemented by one or more manually operated
    fire pumps as follows: (1) Standpipe systems in buildings more than three hundred feet high shall have at least one seven hundred fifty gpm pump or two five hundred gpm pumps. Pumps shall be capable of delivering their rated capacity at a pressure
    of fifty psig above the normal static pressure determined from the highest hose outlet (except the roof manifold) in the building plus the frictional resistance through the pipe from the pump to the outlet. (2) Where a group of two or more buildings,
    whether connected or separated, are operated under a single ownership and one or more buildings exceed three hundred feet in height, one fire pump shall be accepted as the supplemental supply for the group. The pump shall be installed in the building
    where the maintenance personnel are located, and a metal sign with one inch lettering shall be installed in each building at all of the hose outlets on the entrance floor indicating the location of the fire pump. (b) Standpipe pump rooms and location.
    (1) Fire pumps shall be installed at the entrance floor level or below, in rooms enclosed by noncombustible construction having a two hour fire-resistance rating and that are adequately heated, ventilated, lighted, and drained. The pump room shall
    have access to the street level by a direct opening to a street or a court, or by a passageway or stairway having a fire-resistance rating of at least two hours. (2) No person shall install other machinery or mechanical equipment in a fire pump room,
    unless the building is of construction class IA, IB, or IC. (3) No person shall place or install any equipment containing a refrigerant classified in groups A1, A2, A3, B1, B2 or B3 in subchapter thirteen of this chapter, or place or install gas piping
    or gas consuming devices or any other equipment within any space housing a fire pump that would create a hazardous condition. (c) Power supply for standpipe fire pumps. The type of fire pump and prime mover used in a standpipe system shall be suitable
    for the required service in a standpipe system provided for fire department use. If the prime mover employs any form of power other than an electric current supplied by a public utility, the use thereof shall be subject to the approval of the commissioner.
    Electrical power to the motor shall be taken from the street side of the house service switch. (d) Combined use of fire pumps for standpipe and automatic sprinkler systems. A fire pump that furnishes the required auxiliary water supply either to a
    standpipe system or to an automatic sprinkler system shall be accepted as furnishing the corresponding water supply to the other system if such pump is in the same premises, provided that in every such case of combined use, suitable relief and shutoff
    valves shall be installed so as to prevent the water pressure on the automatic sprinkler system resulting from any required operation of the pump for the standpipe system from becoming greater than one hundred seventy-five psig.
  </text>
</level>