<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-224</num>
  <heading>License required.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-224 License required. a. Any person owning, leasing, managing or operating a restaurant under permit from the department of health and mental hygiene upon property which abuts upon any street within the city may maintain or operate upon the sidewalk
    of such street in an area immediately adjacent to its premises, a sidewalk cafe, provided that such sidewalk cafe shall be granted a license and a revocable consent by the commissioner. b. The commissioner, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter
    and the applicable provisions of the zoning resolution, shall establish such rules, regulations, terms and conditions as the commissioner deems proper in respect to the granting and issuance of such licenses and revocable consents, priorities or rights
    between applicants for a license covering the same space, and operation (including hours of operation, provided that no such rule, regulation, term or condition shall prevent licensed sidewalk cafes from operating during the hours of 10:00 a.m. through
    12:00 a.m. daily or shall allow licensed sidewalk cafes to operate before 10:00 a.m. on Sundays) and maintenance of any sidewalk cafe, to ensure good order and to prevent undue obstruction of the sidewalk, which shall have the force and effect of
    law. A license to operate a sidewalk cafe shall be issued after the review and approval of a petition for a revocable consent to construct and operate such sidewalk cafe pursuant to the provisions of section 20-225, 20-226 or 20-227 of this subchapter.
    The operator of a sidewalk cafe under license from the commissioner shall cause the boundary of the area licensed as a sidewalk cafe to be marked in a manner prescribed under rules promulgated by the commissioner. c. No license shall be granted for
    an enclosed sidewalk cafe until an alteration permit or any other required permit is issued by the department of buildings. No license shall be granted for a sidewalk cafe located in a historic district, on a landmark site or attached or adjacent
    to a landmark or an improvement containing an interior landmark without the required approval of the landmarks preservation commission. No license shall be granted for an unenclosed cafe which obstructs the means of egress from any portion of a building
    nor for any unenclosed cafe with an awning unless a permit therefor is issued by the department of buildings. d. The fee for such license shall be at the rate of five hundred and ten dollars for a two-year license. Such license fee shall be in addition
    to any fee imposed, pursuant to rules of the commissioner, upon approval of a petition for a revocable consent, or a renewal of such revocable consent, to construct and operate a sidewalk cafe or any other applicable fee. e. A licensee must provide
    waiter or waitress service to patrons in the sidewalk cafe if alcohol is served. If no alcohol is served at the restaurant, a licensee must provide adequate service to maintain tables in the sidewalk cafe and the adjacent sidewalk in a manner that
    ensures good order and cleanliness. f. The license shall be personal to the applicant and may not be sold, leased or transferred and shall be deemed revoked by the sale or transfer of the lease or of title to the building or structure to which the
    sidewalk cafe is related.</text>
</level>