<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-903</num>
  <heading>Reporting on housing development projects.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-903. Reporting on housing development projects. a. For each housing development project, the department shall make available on its website the following information: (1) the project identifier; (2) the program name as identified by the department
    and the list identifiers of all prequalified lists used in connection with such program; (3) the address; block; lot number; stories; square footage of the building at its base; the number of proposed dwelling units including the number of bedrooms,
    disaggregated by income limits and all initial legal and actual rents; and the number of proposed commercial units; (4) the source, type and value of all city financial assistance and other financial assistance provided by the city, disaggregated
    by source and type; (5) the anticipated completion date of such project; (6) for the developer, contractors and subcontractors for such project: (i) the name and address; (ii) the name and title of each principal officer and principal owner of such
    developer, contractor or subcontractor and (iii) when applicable, whether the wage information described by subdivision a of section 26-904 of this chapter has been provided to the department for such developer, contractor or subcontractor; (7) whether
    the developer was prequalified at the time of selection; (8) the method used to select the developer including, but not limited to, direct negotiation, request for proposals, competitive bidding, public bidding, auction, selection by entities other
    than the department, and application; (9) the criteria used to evaluate potential developers and to select the developer; (10) whether the developer or contractor executed any legal documents subjecting any of the project work to section 220 of the
    New York state labor law; (11) whether the developer or contractor executed any legal documents subjecting any of the project work to subchapter IV of chapter thirty-one of part A of subtitle II of title 40 of the United States Code or any applicable
    regulations or rules; (12) To the extent known to the department, based on information reported to the department by the developer that the department reasonably believes to be correct and complete, a description of the final outcome of any judicial
    actions or proceedings, including any final judgment rendered or settlement, with respect to section 220 of the New York state labor law or subchapter IV of chapter thirty-one of part A of subtitle II of title 40 of the United States code or any applicable
    regulations or rules, within the five-year period immediately preceding developer selection by the department, against the developer, the current principal owner or principal officer thereof, or the former principal owner or principal officer thereof
    if such person held such position or status within the five-year period immediately preceding developer selection by the department; (13) the completion date of the project; and (14) the total number of construction conditions and for each such condition,
    the nature of the condition and a description of any remedial actions taken, ordered or requested with respect to such condition. b. For housing development projects where the developer was selected after the effective date of this chapter, the department
    shall update the information required by subdivision a of this section every six months until completion of such project except that the information required by paragraph fourteen shall be updated every six months until five years after completion
    of such project. c. For housing development projects where the developer was selected prior to the effective date of this chapter, the department shall make available the information required by subdivision a of this section no later than January
    1, 2014 and shall update such information every six months thereafter until completion of such project except that: (1) the information required by paragraph six for subcontractors shall be limited to subcontractors that entered into a contract or
    other agreement with or were otherwise engaged by a contractor or the department; and (2) the information required by paragraph fourteen shall be updated every six months until five years after completion of such project.</text>
</level>