<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-121</num>
  <heading>Construction and excavation sites; storage of materials and equipment on street.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-121 Construction and excavation sites; storage of materials and equipment on street. a. Permit. It shall be unlawful for any person to obstruct, or cause to be obstructed, any portion of a street with construction materials or equipment, unless
    authorized by a permit issued by the commissioner. b. Conditions. In addition to any other conditions which may be set forth in such permit or in the rules of the department, the following conditions shall apply: 1. Any permit granted pursuant to
    this section shall be posted in a conspicuous place on or near the material or equipment or kept on the site or in the designated field headquarters of the work with respect to which the permit was issued so as to be readily accessible to inspection.
    2. Sidewalks, gutters, crosswalks and driveways shall at all times be kept clear and unobstructed, and all dirt, debris and rubbish shall be promptly removed therefrom. The commissioner may authorize encumbrance of the sidewalk with equipment or material
    in a manner which will not prevent the safe passage of pedestrians on such sidewalk. 3. The outer surface of such construction material or equipment shall be clearly marked with high intensity fluorescent paint, reflectors, or other marking which
    is capable of producing a warning glow when struck by the headlamps of a vehicle or other source of illumination. 4. All construction material and equipment shall have printed thereon the name, address and telephone number of the owner thereof. 5.
    In a street upon which there is a surface railroad, construction materials or equipment shall not be placed nearer to the track than five feet. 6. The street under such construction material or equipment shall be shielded by wooden planking, skids
    or other protective covering approved by the commissioner. 7. Construction material or equipment shall not obstruct a fire hydrant, bus stop or any other area as set forth in the rules of the department the obstruction of which would impair the safety
    or convenience of the public. c. Removal of unauthorized obstructions. The commissioner may remove any construction material or equipment placed in or upon any street in violation of this section, the rules of the department or the terms or conditions
    of a permit issued pursuant to this section. If the identity and address of the owner is reasonably ascertainable, notice of the removal shall be sent to the owner within a reasonable period of time after the removal. If such material or equipment
    is not claimed within thirty days after its removal, it shall be deemed to be abandoned. If the equipment is a vehicle, its disposition shall be governed by section twelve hundred twenty-four of the vehicle and traffic law. All other unclaimed material
    or equipment may be sold at public auction after having been advertised in the City Record and the proceeds paid into the general fund or such unclaimed material or equipment may be used or converted for use by the department or by another city agency
    or by a not-for-profit corporation engaged in the construction of subsidized housing. Material or equipment removed pursuant to this subdivision shall be released to the owner or other person lawfully entitled to possession upon payment of the costs
    of removal and storage as set forth in the rules of the department and any fines or civil penalties imposed for the violation or, if an action or proceeding for the violation is pending in court or before the environmental control board, upon the
    posting of a bond or other form of security acceptable to the department in an amount which will secure the payment of such costs and any fines or civil penalties which may be imposed for the violation.</text>
</level>