<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-345</num>
  <heading>Firestopping.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-345 Firestopping. Concealed spaces within partitions, walls, floors, roofs, stairs, furring, pipe spaces, column enclosures, etc. that would permit passage of flame, smoke, fumes, or hot gases from one floor to another floor or roof space, or from
    one concealed area to another, shall be firestopped to form an effective draft barrier, or shall be filled with noncombustible material in accordance with the requirements of this section. Firestopping shall not be required where a concealed space
    is sprinklered in accordance with the construction provisions of subchapter seventeen of this chapter, or is constructed as a shaft. (a) Firestopping materials. In buildings of construction group I, firestopping or fill shall be of noncombustible
    material that can be shaped, fitted, and permanently secured in position. In buildings of construction group II, firestopping may be of combustible material consisting of wood not less than two inches nominal thickness with tight joints, two layers
    of one inch nominal thickness assembled so that there are no through joints or of one-half inch exterior type plywood with joints backed, except that noncombustible firestopping shall be used in concealed spaces of fire divisions and where in contact
    with fireplaces, flues, and chimneys. Noncombustible firestopping may be masonry set in mortar, concrete, three-quarter inch thick mortar or plaster on noncombustible lath, plasterboard at least three-eighths of an inch thick, fire-rated wallboard
    at least five-eighths of an inch thick, sheet metal at least No. 14 U.S. std. gage thick, solid web metal structural members, asbestos-cement board at least one-quarter of an inch thick, or equivalent rigid noncombustible material. Mineral, slag,
    or rockwool may be used for firestopping when compacted to a density of at least three and one-half pounds per cubic foot into a confined space of least dimension not more than one-third its second dimension. (1) The performance of through-penetration
    fire stops shall be measured and specified according to reference standard RS 5-19. (2) The commissioner may accept reference standard RS 5-19 test data results from an independent laboratory acceptable to the commissioner pursuant to subdivision
    (c) of section 27-131, when such data is submitted by a registered architect or licensed professional engineer to justify the usage of fire stops or the details of their installation not specified herein. (b) Hollow partitions and furred spaces. All
    hollow partitions and furred out spaces shall be firestopped at each floor level. Firestops shall be the full thickness of the hollow space or furred out space. (c) Stairs. Concealed spaces within stair construction shall be firestopped between stringers
    at the top and bottom of each flight of stairs so as not to communicate with concealed spaces in the floor, roof or intermediate landing construction. (d) Ceiling spaces. Floor or roof assemblies required to have a fire-resistance rating shall have
    any concealed spaces therein firestopped in accordance with section 27-327 of this subchapter. (e) Exterior cornices. Exterior cornices and eaves, constructed of combustible materials or with combustible framing, shall be firestopped at the ends of
    fire divisions and party walls, and at maximum intervals of twenty feet. If not continuous, they shall have closed ends and at least four inches separation between adjoining sections. (f) Trim and finish. Where combustible trim and finish is permitted
    all hollow spaces shall be firestopped at ten foot intervals or shall be solidly filled with noncombustible materials. (g) Duct and pipe spaces. Ducts and pipes enclosed in construction that does not meet the requirements of this code for shaft construction
    shall be firestopped at every floor level. (h) Inspection of firestopping. The installation of all required firestopping shall be subject to the controlled inspection requirements of section 27-132 of article seven of subchapter one of this chapter,
    except that the architect or engineer need not be retained by the owner. Firestopping shall not be concealed from view until inspected.</text>
</level>