<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-139</num>
  <heading>Private operation.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-139 Private operation. a. If the board of estimate shall determine that municipal operation of any terminal facilities is inexpedient, it shall advertise for proposals for the privilege of constructing, equipping and operating the same, or for
    equipping and operating after construction by the city, or for operating after construction and equipment by the city, by a notice to be printed once a week for two successive weeks in not less than two daily newspapers, and may require security from
    bidders for the execution of their bids, if accepted. Such notice shall describe such terminal facilities in such terms as the board of estimate shall deem proper, and shall state the time and place at which proposals will be received and opened.
    All proposals shall undertake to equip such facilities, unless equipment shall have been provided by the city, and to maintain and operate such terminal facilities for a period not exceeding twenty-five years, with the privilege, however, of renewing
    such contract for a further period not exceeding twenty-five years upon terms to be readjusted as provided in such contract. Such proposals may offer to pay to the city for the use of such terminal facilities either (1) a fixed annual sum; or (2)
    a share of gross receipts; or (3) a share of net receipts. The board of estimate, or a duly appointed committee thereof, shall attend at the time and place specified in such public notice, and shall publicly open all proposals which shall have been
    received, but such board shall not be bound to accept any proposals so received, and may reject all such proposals and readvertise for proposals in the manner hereinbefore provided, or may accept any of such proposals as will, in the judgment of such
    board, best promote the public interest, and award a contract accordingly. b. Any contract for private operation of terminal facilities shall contain a provision whereby the city, at any time after ten years, may terminate the same so far as it relates
    to the maintenance and operation of terminal ways, and terminal stations, and the equipment thereof, upon terms to be fixed in such contract, upon giving one year's written notice of its intention so to do. Upon termination by the city, pursuant to
    the privilege so reserved, the city shall purchase the equipment actually used in the operation of such terminal facilities at an amount agreed upon between the owner thereof and the city; or, in the event of failure to agree, at an amount to be fixed
    by appraisal, each party to name an impartial appraiser, and the two so named to select the third. In the event of failure to agree upon a third appraiser, he or she shall be named by the presiding justice of the appellate division of the supreme
    court, first department; provided, however, that the contract for the operation of such terminal facilities may provide for the amortization of all or a part of the operator's investment out of earnings, in which event the portion so amortized shall
    become the property of the city at the termination of the contract without further payment to the operator. c. Any contract for private operation may provide for the construction of warehouses, factories or other buildings on land owned by the city,
    which warehouses, factories or buildings shall, during construction and at all times thereafter, be the property of the city. The contract may provide for the amortization of the cost of such warehouses, factories or buildings out of receipts from
    their operation, or out of receipts from the operation of all the terminal facilities included in such contract during the term thereof, and may provide for the payment by the city of any unamortized portion of the actual cost plus a reasonable contractor's
    profit, not to exceed fifteen per centum at the termination of the contract, or on the exercise of an option to recapture reserved in the contract. The contract may provide for the payment to the city for the privilege of operating such warehouses,
    factories, or other buildings so constructed, either (1) a fixed annual sum; or (2) a share of the gross receipts; or (3) a share in the net profits. d. Such contract may contain any other provision not inconsistent with this section which the board
    of estimate may deem necessary or desirable for the protection of the interests of the city. e. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law, a railroad corporation may, with the consent of the board of estimate, purchase, acquire
    or hold any stocks or any bonds or other evidences of indebtedness of a corporation which, pursuant to this section, enters into a contract with the city for the operation of terminal facilities in the boroughs of Brooklyn and Queens, or either of
    them, and which contract provides for the handling over such terminal road of freight moved by water, or partly by rail and partly by water, and freight moved wholly by rail, without discrimination as between such freight moved by water, or partly
    by rail and partly by water, and freight moved wholly by rail. The consent of such board shall be granted only upon such notice and after such hearing as may be prescribed under rules and regulations which such board is hereby authorized to adopt.</text>
</level>