<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-503</num>
  <heading>Drainage plan.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-503 Drainage plan. a. The commissioner of environmental protection shall devise and prepare a plan for the proper sewerage and drainage of the city, so far as the same has not already been done, for the purpose of thoroughly draining and carrying
    off water and other matter. He or she shall lay out the city into as many sewerage districts as he or she may deem necessary for such purpose, and shall determine and show, on suitable maps or plans: 1. The location, course, size and grade of each
    sewer and drain proposed for each of such districts; 2. The contemplated depth of such sewers and drains below the present surface and below the established grades of streets and avenues; 3. The proposed alterations and improvements in existing sewers;
    4. Such other particulars as may be necessary for the purpose of exhibiting a complete plan of the proposed sewerage therein. b. Such plan shall indicate the location and size of all sewage disposal works or plants, and the necessary appurtenances
    thereto, as determined by the department of environmental protection. c. The commissioner of environmental protection shall submit such map or plan simultaneously to the department of health and mental hygiene, the director of city planning, each
    affected community board and the office of the appropriate borough president. The department of health and mental hygiene shall review such map or plan with respect to the creation or abatement of any health hazard. Such department shall file a statement
    with the commissioner of environmental protection and the director of city planning, in relation to such map or plan, within fifteen days subsequent to such submission either approving or disapproving such map or plan. d. The director of city planning
    shall review and determine the conformance of such map or plan with the city map, as adopted. Upon determination that such map or plan conforms with the city map, such director shall certify such determination to the commissioner of environmental
    protection. Unless the director shall file a statement with such commissioner in relation to such map or plan within thirty days subsequent to the submission of said map or plan, such map or plan shall be deemed to conform with the city map and shall
    constitute the certification thereof. e. Copies of such map or plan as approved in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be filed by the commissioner of environmental protection in each county office of record, the community board for
    the community in which any portion of such map or plan is situated and the office of the borough president in which any portion of such map or plan is situated within the city of New York and in the offices of the department of transportation and
    department of health and mental hygiene of such city.</text>
</level>