<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-905</num>
  <heading>Demographic Data.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-905. Demographic Data. a. Admissions to Detention Facilities. 1. By September 30 of each year, ACS shall post a report on its website regarding the total number of admissions in the previous fiscal year to the following facilities: i. secure detention
    facilities; and ii. non-secure detention facilities. 2. The data provided pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision a of this section shall be disaggregated by the following factors: i. age; ii. gender; iii. race; iv. zip code of residence, except
    that for a number between one and five admissions from one zip code, the number shall be replaced with a symbol; v. for youth remanded to a detention facility by a court, the most serious charged offense on the court petition, complaint or indictment
    at the time ACS assumed custody; and vi. for youth brought to detention by police, whether the top arrest charge was a misdemeanor or a felony at the time ACS assumed custody. b. Demographic Data for Detention Facilities. 1. By September 30 of each
    year, ACS shall post a report on its website regarding the average daily population in the previous fiscal year in the following facilities: i. secure detention facilities; and ii. non-secure detention facilities. 2. By September 30 of each year,
    ACS shall post a report on its website regarding the number of youth admitted to a detention facility during the previous fiscal year who spent time either in non-secure detention only, secure detention only, or both non-secure and secure detention,
    disaggregated by the following factors: i. age; ii. gender; iii. race; iv. zip code of residence, except that for a number between one and five admissions from one zip code, the number shall be replaced with a symbol; v. for youth remanded to a detention
    facility by a court, the most serious charged offense on the court petition, complaint or indictment at the time ACS assumed custody; and vi. for youth brought to detention by police, whether the top arrest charge was a misdemeanor or a felony at
    the time ACS assumed custody. c. Admissions to Placement Facilities. 1. By September 30 of each year, ACS shall post a report on its website regarding the total number of admissions in the previous fiscal year to the following facilities: i. non-secure
    placement facilities; and ii. limited-secure placement facilities. 2. The data provided pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision c of this section shall be disaggregated by the following factors: i. age; ii. gender; iii. race; iv. zip code of residence,
    except that for a number between one and five admissions from one zip code, the number shall be replaced with a symbol; v. youth who were detained at a detention facility immediately prior to being ordered to a placement facility by a court pursuant
    to the family court act; vi. youth who were not detained at a detention facility immediately prior to being ordered to a placement facility by a court pursuant to the family court act; vii. youth who were transferred to an ACS placement facility from
    the custody of the New York state office of children and family services in accordance with subdivision six of section four hundred and four of the New York state social services law; and viii. for youth ordered to a placement facility by a court,
    the most serious offense adjudicated against such youth by the court. d. Demographic Data for Placement Facilities. 1. By September 30 of each year, ACS shall post a report on its website regarding the average daily population in the previous fiscal
    year in the following facilities: i. non-secure placement facilities; and ii. limited-secure placements facilities. 2. By September 30 of each year, ACS shall report on its website the number of youth admitted to a placement facility during the previous
    fiscal year who spent time either in non-secure placement only, limited secure placement only, or both non-secure and limited secure placement, disaggregated by the following factors: i. age; ii. gender; iii. race; iv. zip code of residence, except
    that for a number between one and five admissions from one zip code, the number shall be replaced with a symbol; and v. for youth ordered to a placement facility by a court, the most serious offense adjudicated against such youth by the court. e.
    Data on Transfers. 1. By September 30 of each year, ACS shall post a report on its website regarding the total number of youth who have been transferred during the previous fiscal year from: i. a non-secure detention facility to a secure detention
    facility; ii. a secure detention facility to a non-secure detention facility; iii. a non-secure placement facility to a limited secure placement facility; iv. a non-secure placement facility to a secure placement facility; v. a limited secure placement
    facility to a non-secure placement facility; vi. a limited secure placement facility to a secure placement facility; vii. a secure placement facility to a limited secure placement facility; and viii. a secure placement facility to a non-secure placement
    facility. 2. The data provided pursuant to paragraph one of subdivision e of this section shall be disaggregated by the following factors: i. age; ii. gender; and iii. race. f. Interim Reports. 1. On or before September 30, 2013, ACS shall post a
    report on its website regarding the total population in non-secure placement facilities as of the last day of every month during the previous fiscal year. 2. No more than one year after ACS begins operating limited secure placement facilities, ACS
    shall post a report on its website regarding: i. the total number of admissions to such facilities in the first nine months of their operation, disaggregated by the following factors: (a) age; (b) gender; (c) race; and (d) youth who were transferred
    to an ACS placement facility from the custody of the New York state office of children and family services in accordance with subdivision six of section four hundred and four of the New York state social services law; ii. the total population in such
    facilities as of the last day of every month during the first nine months of their operation; and iii. the number of youth admitted to such facilities during the first nine months of their operation who, during that period, spent time either in non-secure
    placement only, limited secure placement only, or both non-secure and limited secure placement, disaggregated by the following factors: (a) age; (b) gender; (c) race; (d) zip code of residence except that for a number between one and five admissions
    from one zip code, the number shall be replaced with a symbol; and (e) for youth ordered to a placement facility by a court, the most serious offense adjudicated against such youth by the court.</text>
</level>