<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>28-107.2</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง28-107.2 Definitions. The following words and terms shall, for the purposes of this article and elsewhere in the code, have the meanings shown herein. CLASS A MULTIPLE DWELLING, CLASS B MULTIPLE DWELLING. FURNISHED ROOM HOUSE, ROOMING UNIT AND SINGLE
    ROOM OCCUPANCY. Shall have the meanings set forth in section 27-2004 of the New York city housing maintenance code. SINGLE ROOM OCCUPANCY MULTIPLE DWELLING. A single room occupancy multiple dwelling means: 1. A "class A multiple dwelling" used in
    whole or part as a "rooming house" or "furnished room house," or for "single room occupancy" pursuant to section 248 of the New York state multiple dwelling law; 2. A "class A multiple dwelling," containing "rooming units"; or 3. A "class B multiple
    dwelling." Exception: The term single room occupancy multiple dwelling shall not include: 1. College or school dormitories; 2. Clubhouses; 3. Luxury hotels, as such term is defined by the commissioner of housing preservation and development; or 4.
    Residences whose occupancy is restricted to an institutional use such as housing intended for use by the employees of a single company or institution; 5. City-owned multiple dwellings; or 6. Any multiple dwelling containing fewer than nine "class
    B" dwelling units; used for single room occupancy unless the total number of such units is more than fifty percent of the total number of dwelling units in such multiple dwelling; or 7. Any multiple dwelling that: 7.1. Is the subject of a program
    approved by the commissioner of housing preservation and development and related to the rehabilitation of a single room occupancy multiple dwelling or the provision of housing for persons of low or moderate income, other than a program consisting
    solely of real property tax abatement or tax exemption; and 7.2. Has been exempted from the provisions of this article by the commissioner of housing preservation and development.</text>
</level>