<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-357</num>
  <heading>Exit requirements.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-357 Exit requirements. The determination of exit requirements for a building shall be based upon the occupancy group classification of the building, the number of occupants, the floor area, the travel distance to an exit, and the capacity of the
    exits, as provided in table 6-1 and herein. Every floor of a building shall be provided with exit facilities for its occupant load. The occupant loads of floors shall not be cumulative for the purpose of designing vertical exits, except where one
    floor is used by another as a means of egress. Vertical exits provided from any floor above grade may serve simultaneously all floors above grade, and vertical exits provided from any floor below grade may serve simultaneously all floors below grade.
    (a) Mixed occupancy. When a building is classified in more than one occupancy group in accordance with the provisions of section 27-239 of article two of subchapter three of this chapter, the exit requirements for the entire building shall be determined
    on the basis of the occupancy group having the strictest exit requirements, or the exit requirements for each building section shall be determined separately. (b) Incidental occupancies. When a building contains incidental occupancies classified in
    occupancy groups other than that under which the building is classified, the exit requirements for the floor on which such occupancies occur shall be based upon those of the occupancy group under which the building is classified; but the access and
    exit requirements for the incidental occupancy shall be based upon the occupancy group classification of the incidental occupancy. (c) Multiple occupancy or use. Where a building, floor, or space is used for multiple purposes involving different activities
    at different times, that occupancy involving the greatest number of occupants shall be used in determining the exit requirements. (d) Building access. All buildings classified in other than occupancy groups A, mechanical and electrical equipment rooms
    and boiler and furnace rooms of D-2 or J-3 shall have at least one primary entrance accessible to and usable by individuals who use wheelchairs. Such entrance shall provide access to a level that makes elevators available in buildings where elevators
    are provided. Where ramps are used to comply with this requirement, they shall have a slope not greater than one in twelve, and shall otherwise conform to the provisions of section 27-377 and reference standard RS 4-6. The commissioner may waive the
    requirements of this section in the alteration of buildings existing on the effective date of this code in accordance with section 27-292.6 of this code. (For Table 6-1 see chapter 839 of the laws of 1986) FOOTNOTES TO TABLE 6-1 a. For method of measurement
    see subdivision (c) of section 27-360 of this article. b. Reduce listed capacity of ramps by twenty-five percent when slope exceeds 1 in 10. c. Except for public garages. (See article ten of subchapter seven of this chapter.) d. There shall not be
    more than one classroom on each side of a corridor between an exit and the end of the corridor (dead end). e. Applies to corridors serving classrooms. Other corridors shall have a minimum width of forty-four inches. f. Applies to corridors serving
    patients. Other corridors shall have a minimum width of forty-four inches. g. There shall be no patient bedrooms between an exit and the end of the corridor (dead end). h. See subdivision (d) of section 27-369 of article five of this subchapter for
    permissible increase. i. See section 27-369 of article five of this subchapter. j. See section 27-370 of article five of this subchapter. k. See section 27-378 of article five of this subchapter. m. Where a door opening is divided by mullions into
    two or more door openings, each such opening shall be measured separately in computing the number of units of exit width.</text>
</level>