<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-2116</num>
  <heading>Enforcement of civil penalty; powers of housing part of the civil court, collection of judgment.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-2116 Enforcement of civil penalty; powers of housing part of the civil court, collection of judgment. (a) The department may bring an action in the housing part of the New York city civil court for the recovery of civil penalties, together with
    costs and disbursements. Leave of court, obtained by motion to the housing part thereof, shall be required for disclosure or for a bill of particulars, except for a notice under section three thousand one hundred twenty-three of the civil practice
    law and rules, which shall be granted only upon a showing that such disclosure or bill of particulars is necessary to the prosecution or defense of the action. If it is so noted on the summons, any motion for disclosure or a bill of particulars must
    be made in writing and on notice and must be filed with the clerk with proof of service no later than thirty days after joinder of issue. (b) The owner shall be responsible for the correction of all violations, but in an action for civil penalties
    may in defense or mitigation of such owner's liability for civil penalties show: (1) That the violation or violations were corrected within the time specified in the notice of violation and the certificate of compliance was duly filed; or (2) That
    the violation did not exist at the time the notice of violation was served; or in mitigation or remission of his or her liability for civil penalties show: (i) That he or she began to correct the violation promptly upon receipt of the notice of violation,
    but that its full correction could not be completed within the time provided because of technical difficulties, inability to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor, or inability to gain access to the dwelling unit wherein the violation occurs,
    or such other portion of the building as might be necessary to make the repair; or (ii) That he or she was unable to obtain a permit or license necessary to correct the violation, provided that diligent and prompt application was made therefor; or
    (iii) That the violation giving rise to the action was caused by the act or negligence, neglect or abuse of another not in the employ or subject to the direction of the defendant. Where the aforesaid allegations are made by way of mitigation of penalties,
    the owner shall show, by competent proof, pertinent financial data, and efforts made to obtain necessary materials, funds or labor or to gain access, or to obtain a permit or license and such other evidence as the court may require. If the court finds
    that sufficient mitigating circumstances exist, it may remit all or part of any penalties arising from the violation, but may condition such remission upon a correction of the violation within a time period fixed by the court. (c) A defendant in an
    action for civil penalties who asserts that a violation was caused by the act, negligence, neglect or abuse of a third party who has commenced an action against such third party and may request the court to permit consolidation of defendant's action
    for the reasonable cost of such correction against such third party with the pending action for penalties, or if no other action is then pending against such third party, defendant may make application to implead the party alleged to have caused the
    act, negligence, neglect or abuse. Upon a finding that the violation in issue was caused by such third party, a judgment shall be entered against such third party in favor of the defendant for the reasonable cost of such correction. (d) When the department
    obtains a determination in an action under this article against an owner, judgment may be entered against the premises which shall constitute a lien when a transcript of such judgment is filed in the office of the county clerk in the manner prescribed
    for the filing of judgments and may be enforced against the premises, and, if such judgment remains unsatisfied for ninety days, as a levy upon the rents, pursuant to section 27-2148 of article eight of this subchapter.</text>
</level>