<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-772</num>
  <heading>Written Agreement.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 20-772 Written Agreement. No immigration assistance services shall be provided until the customer has executed a written contract with the provider who will provide such services. The contract shall be in a language understood by the customer, either
    alone or with the assistance of an available interpreter, and, if that language is not English, an English language version of the contract must also be provided. A copy of the contract shall be provided to the customer upon the customer's execution
    of the contract. The customer has the right to cancel the contract within three business days after his or her execution of the contract, without fee or penalty. The right to cancel the contract within three days without payment of any fee may be
    waived when services must be provided immediately to avoid a forfeiture of eligibility or other loss of rights or privileges, and the customer furnishes the provider with a separate dated and signed statement, by the customer or his or her representative,
    describing the need for services to be provided within three days and expressly acknowledging and waiving the right to cancel the contract within three days. The contract may be cancelled at any time after execution. If the contract is cancelled after
    three days, or within three days if the right to cancel without fee has been waived, the provider may retain fees for services rendered, and any additional amounts actually expended on behalf of the customer. All other amounts must be returned to
    the customer within fifteen days after cancellation. The written contract shall be in plain language, in at least twelve point type and shall include the following: 1. The name, address and telephone number of the provider. 2. Itemization of all services
    to be provided to the customer, as well as the fees and costs to be charged to the customer. 3. A statement that original documents required to be submitted in connection with an application made to the federal bureau of citizenship and immigration
    services or for other certifications, benefits or services provided by government may not be retained by the provider for any reason, including payment of fees or costs. 4. A statement that the provider shall give the customer a copy of each document
    filed with a governmental entity. 5. A statement that the customer is not required to obtain supporting documents through the provider, but may obtain such documents himself or herself. 6. The statement: "You have three (3) business days to cancel
    this contract. Notice of cancellation must be in writing, signed by you and mailed by registered or certified United States mail to (specify address). If you cancel this contract within three days, you will get back your documents and any fees that
    you paid." 7. A statement that the provider has financial surety in effect for the benefit of any customer in the event that the customer is owed a refund, or is damaged by the actions of the provider, together with the name, address and telephone
    number of the surety. 8. The statement: "The individual providing assistance to you under this contract is not an attorney licensed to practice law or accredited by the board of immigration appeals to provide representation to you before the bureau
    of citizenship and immigration services, the department of labor, the department of state or any immigration authorities and may not give legal advice or accept fees for legal advice." 9. The statement: "The individual providing assistance to you
    under this contract is prohibited from disclosing any information or filing any forms or documents with immigration or other authorities without your knowledge and consent." 10. The statement: "A copy of all forms completed and documents accompanying
    the forms shall be kept by the service provider for three years. A copy of the customer's file shall be provided to the client on demand and without fee." * NB There are 2 ยง 20-772's</text>
</level>