<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-859</num>
  <heading>Chimney heights and locations.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-859 Chimney heights and locations. (a) Low temperature chimneys. Low temperature chimneys shall extend at least three feet above the highest construction, such as a roof ridge, parapet wall, or penthouse, within ten feet of the chimney outlet,
    whether the construction is on the same building as the chimney or on another building. However, such constructions do not include other chimneys, vents, or open structural framing. Any chimney located beyond ten feet from such construction, but not
    more than the distance determined in subdivision (d) of this section, shall be at least as high as the construction. (b) Medium temperature chimneys. Medium temperature chimneys shall extend at least ten feet above the highest construction, such as
    a roof ridge, or parapet wall or penthouse within twenty feet of the chimney outlet, whether the construction is on the same building as the chimney or on another building. However, such constructions do not include other chimneys, and vents. Any
    chimney located beyond twenty-feet from such constructions but not more than the distance determined in subdivision (d) of this section, shall be at least as high as the construction. (c) High temperature chimneys. High temperature chimneys shall
    extend at least twenty feet above the highest construction, such as roof ridge, parapet wall, penthouse, or other obstruction within fifty feet of the chimney outlet, whether the construction is on the same building as the chimney or in another building.
    However, such constructions do not include other chimneys, vents, or open structural framing. Any chimney located beyond fifty feet from such construction but not more than the distance determined in subdivision (d) of this section, shall be at least
    as high as the construction. (d) Formula. The following formula shall be used for determining the distances referred to in subdivisions (a), (b) and (c) of this section: D = F (sq.rt.) A where: D = Distance, in ft., measured from the center of the
    chimney outlet to the nearest edge of the construction. F = Value determined from table 15-1. A = Free area, in sq. in., of chimney flue space. Table 15-1 "F" Factor for Determining Chimney Distances ========================================================================
    --------------"F" Factor-------------- Low Temp. Medium Temp. High Temp. Type of Fuel Chimney Chimney Chimney ------------------------------------------------------------------------ Gas .......................... 2 2 3 No. 2 Fuel Oils ..............
    2.5 2.5 3 No. 3, No. 6 Fuel Oils, Solid Fuels and Incinerators........ 3 3 3 ========================================================================
  </text>
</level>