<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-914</num>
  <heading>Use of sick time.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-914 Use of sick time. a. An employee shall be entitled to use sick time for absence from work due to: 1. such employee's mental or physical illness, injury or health condition or need for medical diagnosis, care or treatment of a mental or physical
    illness, injury or health condition or need for preventive medical care; or 2. care of a family member who needs medical diagnosis, care or treatment of a mental or physical illness, injury or health condition or who needs preventive medical care;
    or 3. closure of such employee's place of business by order of a public official due to a public health emergency or such employee's need to care for a child whose school or childcare provider has been closed by order of a public official due to a
    public health emergency. b. An employer may require reasonable notice of the need to use sick time. Where such need is foreseeable, an employer may require reasonable advance notice of the intention to use such sick time, not to exceed seven days
    prior to the date such sick time is to begin. Where such need is not foreseeable, an employer may require an employee to provide notice of the need for the use of sick time as soon as practicable. c. For an absence of more than three consecutive work
    days, an employer may require reasonable documentation that the use of sick time was authorized by subdivision a of this section. For sick time used pursuant to paragraphs 1 and 2 of subdivision a of this section, documentation signed by a licensed
    health care provider indicating the need for the amount of sick time taken shall be considered reasonable documentation and an employer shall not require that such documentation specify the nature of the employee's or the employee's family member's
    injury, illness or condition, except as required by law. d. Nothing herein shall prevent an employer from requiring an employee to provide written confirmation that an employee used sick time pursuant to this section. e. An employer shall not require
    an employee, as a condition of taking sick time, to search for or find a replacement worker to cover the hours during which such employee is utilizing sick time. f. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit an employer from taking disciplinary
    action, up to and including termination, against a worker who uses sick time provided pursuant to this chapter for purposes other than those described in this section.</text>
</level>