<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-226</num>
  <heading>Reporting requirements.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-226 Reporting requirements. a. No later than one week following the submission of the mayor's management report, the commissioner shall submit to the council a report detailing the department's activities pursuant to this chapter. Except as provided
    in any paragraph of this section, this report shall provide information for the period covered by the mayor's management report. The report required by this section shall at a minimum include: i. the number of criminal acts and violations of this
    subchapter reported to have occurred within the fulton fish market distribution area and each other seafood distribution area. Such acts and violations shall include, without limitation (aa) acts of physical violence and threats of such violence,
    (bb) acts of damage to property and threats of such acts and (cc) thefts or threats of such thefts; ii. the number of referrals to a state or federal prosecutor made by the commissioner and/or market manager with respect to the items contained in
    paragraph one of this section, the number of such referrals for which a prosecution was brought and the results of any such prosecutions; iii. a current listing of the names and business addresses of unloading and loading business licensees and wholesale
    seafood and seafood delivery business registrants; iv. the number of applications for each such license or registration that were denied with a statement of the reasons for denials and the number of pending applications for each; v. the number of
    class A and class B photo identification cards which have been issued, respectively, the number of applications for each such card which have been denied with a statement of the reasons for denials and the number of pending applications for each such
    card; vi. the number of unloading and loading business licenses, wholesale and seafood delivery business registrations and class A and class B photo identification cards that have been suspended or revoked under sections 22-217 or 22-218 of this chapter,
    respectively, a statement of the reasons for such actions and the average duration of such suspensions; vii. the number of principals of wholesalers and seafood delivery businesses and holders of class B photo identification cards, respectively, to
    whom the provisions of section 22-216 of this chapter have been applied and the result under section 22-217 of this chapter; viii. the number of vehicles, property and equipment, respectively, which have been seized under this chapter and the number
    forfeited, with a statement of the reasons for such seizures and forfeitures; ix. the amounts, by category, of all revenues relating to implementation of this chapter to which the city is entitled, the amounts actually collected and the reasons for
    any difference; and x. the amounts, by category, of all expenditures relating to enforcement of the provisions of this chapter. b. Unless otherwise provided, all items required to be reported pursuant to paragraphs i through x of subdivision a of
    this section shall be reported separately for the fulton fish market distribution area and for each other seafood distribution area.</text>
</level>