<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-3019</num>
  <heading>Modification, suspension or revocation, electrical sign-off, permit or other authorization.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-3019 Modification, suspension or revocation, electrical sign-off, permit or other authorization. a. The commissioner may at any time by an order in writing for good cause shown, modify, suspend or revoke any sign-off, permit or other authorization
    issued pursuant to this chapter for failure to comply with the provisions of this code or other applicable laws or rules; or whenever there has been any false statement or any misrepresentation as to a material fact in the application or submittal
    documents upon the basis of which such approval was issued; or whenever a permit has been issued in error and conditions are such that the permit should not have been issued. Such notice shall inform the permit holder of the reasons for the proposed
    action and that the permit holder has the right to present to the commissioner or his or her representative within ten business days of delivery of the notice by hand or fifteen calendar days of the posting of notice by mail, information as to why
    the permit should not be modified, suspended or revoked. A copy of any such order shall be served in the manner provided in this subchapter. No person other than the commissioner or an officer or employee of the department, duly authorized thereto
    by the commissioner, shall alter or amend any sign-off, permit or other authorization issued pursuant to this chapter or the rules of the department. b. Immediate suspension in cases of imminent peril. The commissioner may immediately suspend any
    permit without prior notice to the permit holder when the commissioner has determined that an imminent peril to life or property exists. The commissioner shall immediately notify the permit holder that the permit has been suspended and the reasons
    therefore, that it is proposed to be revoked, and that the permit holder has the right to present to the commissioner or his or her representative within ten business days of delivery of the notice by hand or fifteen calendar days of the posting of
    notice by mail information as to why the permit should not be revoked.</text>
</level>