<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-960</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-960 Penalties. In addition to any other penalty provided by law: a. Except as otherwise provided in subdivision b of this section, any person who violates any provision of this chapter or any of the rules promulgated thereto shall be liable for
    a civil penalty which shall not exceed ten thousand dollars for each such violation. Such civil penalty may be recovered in a civil action or may be returnable to the department of consumer affairs or other administrative tribunal of competent jurisdiction;
    b. Any person who violates subdivision a of section 20-953 of this chapter shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished for each violation by a criminal fine of not more than ten thousand dollars for each day of such violation or by imprisonment not
    exceeding six months, or both; and any such person shall also be subject to a civil penalty of not more than five thousand dollars for each day of such violation to be recovered in a civil action or returnable to the department of consumer affairs
    or other administrative tribunal of competent jurisdiction; and c. (i) In the event that a shipboard gambling business has violated subdivision f of section 20-963 of this chapter, the commission, in addition to any other penalty prescribed in this
    section, shall, after providing notice and the opportunity to be heard, be authorized to order that any gambling device or other gambling equipment used in the violation of such subdivision shall be removed, sealed or otherwise made inoperable. An
    order pursuant to this paragraph shall be posted on the vessel on which such violation occurs. The commission shall take reasonable measures to provide notice to a person(s) holding a security interest(s) in a gambling device or gambling equipment
    with respect to which action is taken pursuant to this section. (ii) Ten days after the posting of an order issued pursuant to paragraph (i) of this subdivision, this order may be enforced by any person so authorized by section 20-962 of this chapter.
    (iii) Any gambling device or gambling equipment removed pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision shall be stored at a dock or in a garage, pound or other place of safety and the owner or other person lawfully entitled to the possession of such
    item may be charged with reasonable costs for removal and storage payable prior to the release of such item. (iv) A gambling device or gambling equipment sealed or otherwise made inoperable or removed pursuant to this subdivision shall be unsealed,
    restored to operability or released upon payment of all outstanding fines and all reasonable costs for removal and storage and upon demonstration satisfactory to the commission that the provisions of subdivision f of section 20-963 will be complied
    with in all respects. (v) It shall be a misdemeanor for any person to remove the seal from or make operable any gambling device or gambling equipment sealed or otherwise made inoperable in accordance with an order of the commission. (vi) A gambling
    device or gambling equipment removed pursuant to this subdivision that is not reclaimed within ninety days of such removal by the owner or other person lawfully entitled to reclaim such item shall be subject to forfeiture upon notice and judicial
    determination in accordance with provisions of law. Upon forfeiture, the commission shall, upon a public notice of at least ten business days, sell such item at public sale. The net proceeds of such sale, after deduction of the lawful expenses incurred,
    shall be paid into the general fund of the city. d. The corporation counsel is authorized to commence a civil action on behalf of the city for injunctive relief to restrain or enjoin any activity in violation of this chapter and for civil penalties.</text>
</level>