<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-140</num>
  <heading>Administrative fees.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 24-140 Administrative fees. (a) A person applying for the registration of the demolition of a building shall pay a fee to be computed by multiplying the street frontage in feet by the number of stories of the building times 25 cents, provided that
    the minimum fee shall not be less than $250.00. Wherever a building shall have frontage on more than one street, the longer frontage shall be used in the above computation. (b) A person applying for the registration of the spraying of insulating material
    shall pay a fee to be computed by multiplying the street frontage in feet by the number of stories of the building times 60 cents, provided that the minimum fee shall not be less than $250.00. Wherever a building shall have frontage on more than one
    street, the longer frontage shall be used in the above computation. (c) A person applying for or renewing the registration of equipment shall pay a fee of $110.00 for each such registration or renewal with respect to equipment which in the aggregate,
    feeding into a common emission point, has a Btu input or gross output equal to or greater than 350,000 Btu per hour but less than 1 million Btu per hour, and $190.00 for each such registration or renewal with respect to equipment which in the aggregate
    has a Btu input or gross output equal to or greater than 1 million Btu per hour but less than 2.8 million Btu per hour feeding into a common emission point. A person applying for or renewing the registration of other equipment shall pay a fee of $190.00
    for each such registration or renewal. (d) A person issued a registration of equipment or apparatus for a period of less than three years shall pay a pro-rated registration fee on the basis of one thirty-sixth of the full fee for each full month of
    the registration period. * NB Amended Ch. L.L. 49/85 ยง 10, language juxtaposed per Ch. 907/85 ยง 14
  </text>
</level>