<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-354</num>
  <heading>Work and materials to be procured by contract; exceptions; certificate of public interest.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-354 Work and materials to be procured by contract; exceptions; certificate of public interest. a. All work hereby authorized to be done and all materials hereby authorized to be furnished involving an expenditure of over one thousand dollars, shall
    be procured by contract made in the manner required by and pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter. The commissioner of environmental protection, however, may without contract cause such surveys to be made and such maps, plans and estimates
    to be prepared, as shall, in his or her opinion, be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, and may appoint and fix the compensation of suitable engineers and other persons to supervise and inspect all work hereby authorized to be
    done. The commissioner of environmental protection may procure any work to be done without contract, not involving an expenditure of over five thousand dollars, if the commissioner certifies that in his or her opinion, it is for the public interest
    that such work be done; and in such certificate the commissioner shall state his or her reasons therefor. b. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of this subchapter or of any general or special law, the commissioner of environmental protection,
    during the existence of a state of war between the United States of America and the governments of Germany, Japan and Italy, or any of them, and for six months immediately following the termination thereof, may procure or contract for, without public
    letting, any equipment or materials necessary for the completion of the Delaware aqueduct and appurtenant structures and for any work to be done in connection with the installation of such equipment or materials if the commissioner certifies that
    in his or her opinion, it is in the public interest that any such equipment or material be procured or contracted for or any such work be done, without public letting, and any such certificate of the commissioner shall state his or her reasons therefor.
    Any such certificate shall be filed in the office of the comptroller of the city of New York.</text>
</level>