<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-377</num>
  <heading>Ramps.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-377 Ramps. Interior or exterior ramps may be used as exits in lieu of interior or exterior stairs provided they comply with the applicable requirements for interior stairs in section 27-375 of this article or exterior stairs in section, 27-376
    of this article respectively, and with the following: (a) Capacity. The capacity of ramps shall be as listed in table 6-1. (b) Maximum grade. Ramps shall not have a slope steeper than 1 in 8, except that in buildings classified in occupancy group
    H the slope shall not exceed 1 in 12, and except as provided in subchapter eight of this chapter for places of assembly. (c) Design. (1) CHANGES IN DIRECTION. Ramps shall be straight, with changes in direction being made at level platforms or landings,
    except that ramps having a slope not greater than one in twelve at any place, may be curved. (2) LENGTH. The sloping portion of ramps shall be at least three feet but not more than thirty feet long between level platforms or landings. (3) PLATFORMS.
    Level platforms or landings, at least as wide as the ramp, shall be provided at the bottom, at intermediate levels where required, and at the top of all ramps. Level platforms shall be provided on each side of door openings into or from ramps having
    a minimum length in the direction of exit travel of three feet, and when a door swings on the platform or landing a minimum length of five feet. (4) DOORS. Door openings into or from ramps shall comply with the requirements for stairs in subdivision
    (g) of section 27-375 of this article. No door shall swing over the sloping portion of a ramp. (5) GUARDS AND RAILINGS. Guards and railings of ramps shall comply with the applicable requirements of subdivision (f) of section 27-375 of this article
    except that only ramps having a slope steeper than one in twelve need comply with the requirements for handrails and intermediate handrails shall not be required. (6) SURFACE. Interior ramps exceeding a slope of one in ten and all exterior ramps shall
    be provided with nonslip surfaces. (7) Ramps for people having physical disabilities shall additionally comply with the requirements of reference standard RS 4-6.</text>
</level>