<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-696</num>
  <heading>General requirements for installation of piles.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-696 General requirements for installation of piles. (a) Protection of adjacent property. Piles shall be installed with adequate provision for the protection of adjacent buildings and property. (b) Protection of the pile during installation. Piling
    shall be handled and installed to the required penetration and resistance by methods that leave their strength unimpaired and that develop and retain the required load-bearing resistance. Any damaged pile shall be satisfactorily repaired or the pile
    shall be rejected. Subject to the approval of the commissioner, damaged piles may be used at a fraction of the design load as determined by the architect or engineer in lieu of repair or rejection. (c) Protection of pile materials after installation.
    Where boring records or site conditions indicate possible deleterious action on pile materials due to soil constituents, changing water levels, or other causes, such materials shall be adequately protected by preservatives or encasements that will
    not be rendered ineffective by driving and that will prevent such deleterious action. The following specific provisions shall apply: (1) Untreated timber piles shall not be used unless the top level of the pile is below the permanent water table.
    The permanent water table level shall not be assumed higher than the invert level of any sewer, drain, or subsurface structure in the adjacent streets, nor higher than the water level at the site resulting from the lowest drawdown of wells or sumps,
    but in no case shall untreated timber piles be used where the cut-off level is less than ten feet below the adjacent legal grade. Where treated piles are required, preservative treatment shall consist of impregnation with creosote or a creosote solution
    or, for piles entirely embedded below grade, a pentachlorophenal solution may be used. Treatment shall be in accordance with all requirements of reference standard RS 11-6. (2) Piles installed in ash or garbage fills, cinder fills, or which are free-standing
    in or near a seawater environment, or which are used for the support of chemical plants, coal piles or under similar conditions of chemical seepage or aggressive action, or which are used for support of electrical generating plants, shall be investigated
    regarding the need for special protective treatment and, where protective treatment is indicated, shall be protected against deterioration by encasement, coating, or other device acceptable to the commissioner. (d) Equipment. Equipment and methods
    for installing piles shall be such that piles are installed in their proper position and alignment, without damage. Equipment shall be maintained in good repair.</text>
</level>