<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-529.4</num>
  <heading>Color schemes and emblems and additional requirements for commuter vans.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-529.4 Color schemes and emblems and additional requirements for commuter vans. a. Commuter vans shall have the name of the vehicle owner, the name of the person holding the authorization pursuant to which such vehicle is operating and evidence
    of such authorization displayed on the outside and inside of the vehicle in such form as shall be prescribed by the commission. b. Commuter vans shall display a sticker on at least the front, back and sides of such vehicles containing a unique emblem
    in such form as shall be prescribed by the commission. The commission shall issue such stickers to the commuter van owner upon the issuance of a commuter van license and such sticker shall: (1) be large enough to be easily seen by law enforcement
    officers and members of the public; (2) include information uniquely identifying the van, which may include make and model, color(s) of such van, license plate number or information about the commuter van license and the term of such license; (3)
    be hard to replicate, with security features such as holograms or other security features as prescribed by the commission; and (4) include any other information or features as prescribed by the commission. c. Commuter vans may be painted any color
    approved by the commission, other than the colors reserved for medallion taxis. d. All commuter vans shall at all times carry inside the vehicle and the operator shall produce upon demand of any officer or employee designated by the commission, any
    police officer or any authorized officers or employees of the department of transportation or the New York city transit authority: 1. the commuter van license; 2. the driver's commuter van driver's license; 3. the authorization to operate a commuter
    van service, or copy thereof reproduced in accordance with the specifications set forth in rules of the commission; 4. the vehicle registration and evidence of current liability insurance; and 5. a passenger manifest, and such records evidencing prearrangement
    as are prescribed by rule of the commission.</text>
</level>