<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-168.1</num>
  <heading>Clean heating oil.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-168.1 Clean heating oil. (a) Definitions. For the purpose of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings: (1) "Biodiesel" shall mean a fuel, designated B100, that is composed exclusively of mono-alkyl esters of long chain
    fatty acids derived from feedstock and that meets the specifications of the American Society of Testing and Materials designation D 6751-09a. (2) "Bioheating fuel" shall mean a fuel comprised of biodiesel blended with petroleum heating oil that meets
    the specifications of the American Society of Testing and Materials designation D 396-09a or other specifications as determined by the commissioner. (3) "District steam system" shall mean a system for the production of steam and for its transmission
    and distribution through underground pipelines to multiple buildings. (4) "Emergency generator" shall mean a machine or device that combusts fuel to create electricity and that is used for the purpose of providing backup power in the event of a general
    interruption in electrical service. (5) "Feedstock" shall mean soybean oil, oil from annual covercrops, algal oil, biogenic waste oils, fats or greases, or non-food grade corn oil, provided that the commissioner may modify the definition of feedstock
    based on the vegetable oils, animal fats or cellulosic biomass listed in table 1 of 40 C.F.R. ยง 80.1426. (6) "Heating oil" shall mean oil refined for the purpose of use as fuel for combustion in a heating system and that meets the specifications of
    the American Society of Testing and Materials designation D 396-09a or other specifications as determined by the commissioner. (7) "Heating system" shall mean a system that generates heat, hot air, hot water or steam by combustion and distributes
    it within a building. (8) "Renewable biomass" shall mean crops and crop residue from existing agricultural land, tree residues, animal waste material and byproducts, slash and pre-commercial thinnings from non-federal forest lands, biomass cleared
    from the vicinity of buildings and other areas to reduce the risk of wildfire, algae, and separated yard waste or food waste. Such term shall not include processed materials such as particle board, treated or painted wood, and melamine resin-coated
    panels. (9) "Renewable fuel" shall mean fuel produced from renewable biomass. (b) (1) After October 1, 2012, no person shall cause or permit the use in any building in the city or deliver to any building in the city for use in such building, heating
    oil that is fuel oil grade no. 2, no. 4 or no. 6 containing less than two percent biodiesel by volume. The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to the use or delivery of heating oil for use in an emergency generator or for use in a boiler
    where heating oil from a dual-use tank supplies both such boiler and an emergency generator. (2) The commissioner may authorize the use of any renewable fuel in heating systems if he or she determines that such fuel meets an applicable American Society
    for Testing and Materials standard or other standard as determined by the commissioner, and the emissions from such fuel contain equal or lesser amounts of particulate matter, sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides than the emissions from fuel oil grade
    no. 2. (c) The commissioner may waive the requirements of paragraph 1 of subdivision b of this section in accordance with the provisions of this subdivision. (1) A waiver may be issued for a particular type of boiler or fuel if the commissioner finds
    that: (i) a sufficient quantity of bioheating fuel containing two percent biodiesel is not available in the city for that boiler type; (ii) the price of available bioheating fuel for that boiler type is at least fifteen percent more than the price
    of a comparable fuel oil grade of one hundred percent petroleum heating oil; (iii) the use of bioheating fuel would void the manufacturer's warranty for that boiler type; or (iv) there is no applicable American Society of Testing and Materials standard
    or other standard as determined by the commissioner to govern the specification of the bioheating fuel for purposes of receiving bids and enforcing contracts. (2) Any waiver issued pursuant to subparagraph (i) or (ii) of paragraph 1 of this subdivision
    shall expire after three months, unless renewed in writing by the commissioner. (3) Any waiver issued pursuant to subparagraph (iii) or (iv) of paragraph 1 of this subdivision shall expire after six months, unless renewed in writing by the commissioner.
    (4) A waiver may be issued for a specific district steam system if the commissioner finds based on documentation submitted by the applicant, including but not limited to a report certified by a professional engineer, that compliance with the requirements
    of paragraph 1 of subdivision b of this section would result in damage to equipment used to generate steam within such district steam system. Any waiver issued pursuant to this paragraph shall expire after one year, unless renewed in writing by the
    commissioner. (d)(1) No later than September 1, 2013, and no later than September 1 of every year thereafter, the commissioner shall submit a report to the mayor and the speaker of the council, which shall include: (i) all waivers, findings and renewals
    of such findings issued pursuant to this section during the immediately preceding calendar year; (ii) a summary of the information received pursuant to subdivision e of this section; (iii) all waivers, findings and renewals of such findings issued
    pursuant to subdivision b of section 24-169 of this code during the immediately preceding calendar year; and (iv) determinations made by the commissioner regarding renewable biomass pursuant to paragraph 2 of subdivision b of this section and any
    recommendations with respect to the use of renewable biomass in the city, considering appropriate standards and experiential use. (2) The report required pursuant to this subdivision may be satisfied by including such information in the management
    report and preliminary management report made public and submitted to the council by the mayor pursuant to section twelve of the New York city charter. (e)(1) The commissioner shall require persons who supply heating oil directly to buildings in the
    city to disclose annually to the commissioner the following information regarding fuel oil supplied: (i) the amount in gallons of each fuel oil grade supplied by such person to buildings by zip code; and (ii) the average percentage of biodiesel blended
    into each fuel oil grade supplied by such person within the city and the types of feedstock used in the creation of such biodiesel. (2) The commissioner shall prescribe the form in which required information shall be reported annually to the department.
    Such form shall be certified by the person supplying the information as to the completeness and accuracy of the information provided. (3) The department shall require that records be maintained to substantiate the information provided pursuant to
    this subdivision and that such records shall be made available for inspection and audit by the department for a period up to three years. (f) The term "fuel oil" as used in any provision of the administrative code of the city of New York or the rules
    of the city of New York shall be deemed to include heating oil that is fuel oil grade no. 2, no. 4 or no. 6 containing biodiesel. (g) The commissioner shall promulgate rules to carry out the provisions of this section. (h) The commissioner shall have
    the authority to sample, test and analyze heating oil supplied to buildings in the city to determine compliance with this section. (i) Use of biodiesel for heating purposes by city buildings. (1) After October first, two thousand fourteen, all no.
    2, no. 4 and no. 6 heating oil purchased for use in any building owned by the city shall be bioheating fuel containing not less than five percent biodiesel (B5) by volume except that the provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to the use of
    emergency generators. (2) The commissioner of citywide administrative services shall institute a pilot program to use greater amounts of biodiesel in city-owned buildings. Such pilot program shall require that beginning October first, two thousand
    fourteen, the heating oil burned in not less than five percent of city-owned buildings shall contain at least ten percent biodiesel (B10) by volume. Such pilot program shall continue until October first, two thousand fifteen and within six months
    of the conclusion of such pilot program, the commissioner of citywide administrative services shall issue a report to the mayor and the speaker of the council detailing the findings of such pilot program, including the utility of and any impediments
    to the use of ten percent biodiesel (B10) by volume in city-owned buildings and any recommendations for the use of ten percent biodiesel (B10) by volume in all city-owned buildings. (3) The commissioner of citywide administrative services in conjunction
    with the office of long-term planning and sustainability shall undertake a one year study on the feasibility of the use of five percent biodiesel (B5) by volume in all buildings throughout the city. Such study shall include recommendations on whether
    and when the city should require the use of five percent biodiesel (B5) by volume in heating oil in all buildings and shall be issued to the mayor and the speaker of the council by April first, two thousand fifteen.</text>
</level>