<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-878</num>
  <heading>Incinerator chimney connectors.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-878 Incinerator chimney connectors. (a) The chimney connector from the combustion chamber of an auxiliary fuel-fired incinerator shall be constructed of metal at least as heavy as no. 16 manufacturers standard gauge when twelve inches or less in
    diameter or greater dimension, and of metal at least as heavy as no. 12 manufacturers standard gauge when they exceed twelve inches in diameter or greater dimension. (b) Chimney connectors from auxiliary fuel-fired incinerators shall be lined with
    firebrick, laid in fire clay mortar, at least two and one-half inches thick when they are between twelve inches and eighteen inches in diameter or greater dimension and at least four and one-half inches thick when they are larger; where no flue gas
    temperature reduction is effected the chimney connectors shall be equipped with a guillotine or horizontal sliding damper or butterfly damper interlocked with the fuel firing controls so that operation of the incinerator occurs when the damper is
    open. If chimney connectors from auxiliary fuel-fired incinerators lead into and combine with chimney connectors from other equipment, the connectors from the other equipment shall also be lined as required for direct flue connections unless the cross-sectional
    area of the connector into which they lead is at least four times their required cross-sectional area. (c) Chimney connectors for an auxiliary fuel-fired incinerator to a boiler stack or chimney for a high temperature heating equipment shall be permitted
    when the cross-sectional area of such stack or chimney is at least four times that of the incinerator chimney connector. (d) The clearance of incinerator chimney connectors from combustible material or construction shall be at least thirty-six inches.
    This clearance may be reduced as outlined in table 15-8 in accordance with the type of protection applied to the combustible material or construction.
  </text>
</level>