<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>23-408</num>
  <heading>Violations; Penalties and Other Enforcement.</heading>
  <text>ยง 23-408 Violations; Penalties and Other Enforcement. a. Any owner who installs, operates or maintains a public pay telephone on, over or under any street or other inalienable property of the city without a permit therefor shall be guilty of a misdemeanor
    and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not more than ten thousand dollars and imprisonment of not more than thirty days, or both such fine and imprisonment. Such owner shall, in addition, be liable for civil penalties pursuant
    to subdivisions c and d of this section. b. An owner who repeatedly fails to provide phone services from a public pay telephone for any sustained period of time or who fails to provide coinless twenty-four hour 911 service from such public pay telephone
    shall be in violation of this chapter and shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than two thousand five hundred dollars for each violation which may be recovered in a civil action or in a proceeding before the environmental control board.
    In the case of a continuing violation, each day's continuance shall be a separate and distinct offense. c. An owner who violates any provision of this chapter, or any term or condition of a permit issued pursuant thereto, or any rule promulgated by
    the commissioner pursuant thereto shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than one thousand dollars for each violation which may be recovered in a civil action or in a proceeding before the environmental control board. In the case of a continuing
    violation, each day's continuance shall be a separate and distinct offense. d. An owner who is liable for a civil penalty for a violation pursuant to subdivision c of this section shall also be liable in a civil action for an additional civil penalty
    in the amount of the expense, if any, incurred by the city in the removal of the public pay telephone and the performance of related repair and restoration work. e. In addition to authorized officers and employees of the department, officers and employees
    of the department of transportation who are designated by the commissioner shall have the power to issue summonses and appearance tickets returnable in the criminal court and notices of violation returnable before the environmental control board for
    violations of the provisions of this chapter. f. An owner of a public pay telephone shall be liable for a violation by his or her employee, agent or independent contractor of the provisions of this chapter, or any term or condition of a permit issued
    pursuant thereto, or any rule promulgated by the commissioner pursuant thereto, made in the course of performing his or her duties. g. An owner who submits an application for a public pay telephone permit containing a certification made by a commercial
    lessee pursuant to subparagraph (iii) of paragraph 2 of subdivision a of section 23-403 of this chapter, knowing that such certification contains a false statement or false information, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor. h. The commissioner may request
    the corporation counsel to institute any action or proceeding that may be appropriate or necessary to restrain, correct or abate a violation of the provisions of this chapter. i. 1. If the commissioner has reasonable cause to believe that an owner,
    or any employee, agent or independent contractor of such owner, has violated the provisions of this chapter, or any term or condition of a permit issued pursuant thereto, or any rule promulgated by the commissioner pursuant thereto, the commissioner
    may (i) notify the owner of the condition identified by the commissioner as a violation and specify the action that must be taken to correct the condition in such manner and within such period of time as shall be set forth in such notice, and (ii)
    shall afford the owner an opportunity to contest the commissioner's notice in a manner to be set forth in rules of the commissioner. Upon final determination by the commissioner and failure of such owner to correct the condition in the manner and
    within the period of time specified by the commissioner, the commissioner shall be authorized, at his or her discretion: aa. to remove or cause the removal of any public pay telephone which is installed, operated or maintained on, over or under any
    street or other unalienable property of the city without a permit therefor. Notwithstanding the foregoing, notice shall be provided pursuant to this subdivision prior to removal only where the name and address of the owner is shown on the public pay
    telephone or can be readily identified by the commissioner by virtue of a trademark prominently displayed on the public pay telephone; bb. to revoke a permit and, upon revocation, to further order the removal of the public pay telephone. In the event
    the permittee fails to remove the public pay telephone and to perform related repair and restoration work within the time period specified by such order, the commissioner may remove or cause the removal of the public pay telephone and have repair
    and restoration work performed at the expense of the permittee, who shall be liable for the amount expended by the city; cc. to render a public pay telephone inoperable except for the purpose of emergency telephone service through the 911 system or
    an operator. Such action may continue until the violation has been corrected to the satisfaction of the commissioner and payment has been made of all civil penalties imposed for the violation and any fees for any administrative expense or expense
    of additional inspections incurred by the city as a result of such violation. The commissioner shall affix to any public pay phone rendered inoperable pursuant to this paragraph a notice advising the public that the phone may be used only for emergency
    telephone service through the 911 system or an operator and setting forth the provisions of subdivision h of this section. Any device utilized by the commissioner for the purpose of rendering a public pay telephone inoperable shall be designed so
    as to permit the unimpaired use of the public pay telephone upon the removal of the device; dd. to suspend review of all applications for the issuance or renewal of permits filed by such owner pursuant to this chapter. Such suspension may continue
    until the violation has been corrected to the satisfaction of the commissioner and payment has been made of all fines or civil penalties imposed for the violation, any costs incurred by the city for removal and related repair or restoration work,
    and any fees for any administrative expense or expense of additional inspections incurred by the city as a result of such violation. 2. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph one of this subdivision, if the commissioner determines that an imminent
    threat to life or property exists, the commissioner may remove or cause the removal of a public pay telephone, and have repair and restoration work performed at the expense of the owner, without affording the owner an opportunity to be heard prior
    to such removal. An owner who is a permittee or whose name and address is shown on the public pay telephone shall be provided notice and an opportunity to be heard five days after such removal in accordance with rules of the commissioner. 3. The procedures
    set forth in this subdivision shall be employed by the commissioner in addition to or in lieu of the other remedies set forth in this section and shall not be construed to limit the power of the commissioner to commence a civil action or proceeding
    before the environmental control board, or to require that the commissioner resort to any procedure set forth in this subdivision as a prerequisite to the commencement of any such action or proceeding. j. It shall be a misdemeanor for any person:
    (i) to remove any device installed by the commissioner pursuant to subparagraph aa of paragraph one of subdivision g of this section or to otherwise make operable a public pay telephone upon which such a device has been installed; or (ii) to remove
    or deface any notice affixed to a public pay telephone pursuant to such paragraph of such subdivision. Such misdemeanor shall be punishable upon conviction by a fine of not more than ten thousand dollars or imprisonment for not more than thirty days
    or both such fine and imprisonment. k. Any public pay telephone removed pursuant to this section which is not claimed by the owner within thirty days of removal shall be deemed to be abandoned. All abandoned public pay telephones may be sold at public
    auction after having been advertised in the City Record and the proceeds paid into the general fund or such abandoned telephones may be used or converted for use by the department or by another city agency. A public pay telephone shall be released
    to the owner upon payment of the costs of removal, repair and restoration work, and of storage, any fees for any administrative expense or expense of additional inspections incurred by the department as a result of the violation, or, if an action
    or proceeding for the violation is pending in a court or before the environmental control board, upon the posting of a bond or other form of security acceptable to the commissioner in an amount which will secure the payment of such costs and any fines
    or civil penalties which may be imposed for the violation.</text>
</level>