<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-543</num>
  <heading>Light projection sources.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-543 Light projection sources. Motion picture projection and other light projection sources shall comply with the following: (a) Film. The projection, use or storage of film having a nitro-cellulose base (commonly known as nitrate film) shall not
    be permitted except under conditions specified in special permits when issued by the fire department. Safety film meeting the specifications and test standards of reference standard RS 8-1 may be projected, used or stored. (b) Projection machines.
    Projection machines shall meet the requirements of the electrical code of the city of New York. The lamp housing of projection machines using carbon-arc or other light sources that emit gaseous discharge shall be equipped with, or connected to a mechanical
    ventilation system of adequate capacity to exhaust the products of combustion through ducts directly to the outdoors. Such duct systems shall comply with the requirements of subchapter thirteen of this chapter. When more than one projection machine
    or other facility employing a carbon-arc or similar light source is used, all may be vented by the same duct system if the capacity is adequate for all facilities so connected. (c) Other light source facilities. All devices, such as spotlights, that
    employ a carbon-arc or other light source that emits gaseous discharge shall be vented directly as required in subdivision (b) of this section, unless the space in which such devices are located is mechanically ventilated and provides at least two
    thousand cubic feet of room volume for each device. (d) Light or projection rooms or booths. When enclosed, rooms or booths used for the projection of motion picture film or the manipulating of lights shall be built of noncombustible materials, and
    shall provide a clear working space of at least two feet around the projection apparatus. Such rooms or booths shall be provided with vents opening to a mechanically ventilated area or the outdoors, adequate in size to supply the make-up air required.
    The rooms or booths shall be provided with at least one noncombustible or metal clad door at least two feet by six feet opening in the direction of exit travel, and no point within the room, booth, or gallery shall be more than fifty feet from a door
    opening into a corridor or space that provides access to an exit at a distance not greater than seventy-five feet.</text>
</level>