<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-801</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-801 Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply: (a) "Affordable" shall mean that rental expenses for dwelling units do not exceed thirty percent of the annual gross household income of the existing tenants,
    and/or where rental expenses do not exceed the rent levels allowable pursuant to the rent restrictions applicable to such dwelling units prior to conversion, provided however that dwelling units which become vacant in assisted rental housing should
    not be rented to households whose income exceeds eighty percent of the New York metropolitan area median income as determined by the United States department of housing and urban development. (b) "Appraised value" shall mean the value as determined
    by a majority vote of an advisory panel of three appraisers who shall perform such appraisal in accordance with the American Arbitration Association's rules for the real estate industry. (c) "Assisted rental housing" shall mean a privately-owned multiple
    dwelling or group of multiple dwelling units managed together under the same ownership in which the majority of dwelling units therein are subject to federal, state or city income eligibility restrictions and in which rents for such dwelling units
    are controlled, regulated or assisted by a federal, state or city agency pursuant to a regulatory agreement or rental assistance agreement designed to make such dwelling units affordable on a project-based basis. Assisted rental housing programs shall
    include: (1) any program created, administered, or supervised by the city or state under article II or article IV of the private housing finance law, but shall not include any multiple dwelling owned or operated by a company organized under article
    II or article IV of the private housing finance law that was occupied prior to January 1, 1974. (2) any program providing project-based assistance under section eight of the United States housing act of 1937, as it may be amended from time to time;
    and (3) housing programs governed by sections 202, 207, 221, 232, 236, or 811 of the national housing act, (12 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), as they may be amended from time to time; (d) "Bona fide purchaser" shall mean a person or entity that has tendered
    a bona fide offer to purchase the assisted rental housing. (e) "Bona fide offer to purchase" shall mean a good faith and without fraud offer, made in writing and approved by the department that is tendered by a bona fide purchaser no later than one
    hundred and twenty days after an appraisal performed pursuant to section 26-804 of this chapter, and that is non-binding on the owner with intent to convert. (f) "Conversion" or "convert" shall mean the transfer of title, leasing, intention to sell
    or lease, mortgage pre-payment, withdrawal from an assisted housing program, decision not to extend or renew participation in the program or any other action taken by the owner that would result in the termination of participation by the owner in
    the assisted rental housing program. (g) "Household" shall mean all lawful occupants of any dwelling unit as defined in section 27-2004 of this code. (h) "Household income" shall mean, for any household, the sum of the amount reported separately in
    the most recent individual or joint tax return for wage or salary income, net self-employed income, interest, dividends, rent received, royalties, social security or railroad retirement benefits or disability benefits and all other income for each
    member of the household reported on a tax return. (i) "Department" shall mean the department of housing preservation and development or successor agency. (j) "Financial assistance" shall mean any benefits received as a result of an assisted rental
    housing program that act to maintain affordable rents in the assisted rental housing. (k) "First opportunity to purchase" shall mean the opportunity by a tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, to purchase in good faith and without
    fraud the assisted rental housing at or below its appraised value before such assisted rental housing becomes subject to conversion. (l) "Notice" shall mean a written communication addressed to a tenant association, or if no tenant association exists,
    to each tenant, or if applicable, to a qualified entity, by means of first class and registered mail, or personal delivery upon a tenant association, or if no tenant association exists, upon each tenant, or if applicable, a qualified entity. Each
    such notice shall be deemed to have been given upon the deposit of such first class and registered mail in the custody of the United States postal service or upon receipt of personal delivery, and by posting of such notice in the common areas of the
    assisted rental housing. (m) "Owner" shall mean any person or entity, or combination of such persons or entities, or any agent of such persons or entities, that has a controlling interest in assisted rental housing that is subject to conversion. (n)
    "Qualified entity" shall mean any individual, partnership, limited liability partnership, limited liability corporation, not-for-profit corporation or business corporation, or other entity authorized to do business in New York state and experienced
    in the management of affordable housing, designated by the tenants residing in at least sixty percent of the occupied dwelling units within the same assisted rental housing to act on its behalf pursuant to section 26-809 of this chapter and approved
    in writing by the department and which obligates itself and any successors in interest to assume the ongoing responsibility of continuing maintenance and operation of the assisted rental housing as affordable for the duration of the housing's useful
    life and in accordance with the purposes of this chapter. (o) "Right of first refusal" shall mean the right of a tenant association, or if applicable, a qualified entity, to submit a good faith and without fraud offer, in writing to the owner to purchase
    the higher of the assisted rental housing's appraised value or the identical price, terms and conditions offered by a bona fide purchaser as approved by the department. (p) "Tenant" shall mean a lawful occupant who resides within a dwelling unit within
    such assisted rental housing pursuant to law or a lease recognized by either the owner of such assisted rental housing, the department or a court of competent jurisdiction. (q) "Tenant association" shall mean an association, whether incorporated or
    not, for which written consent to forming a tenant association has been given by tenants representing at least sixty percent of the occupied dwelling units within the same assisted rental housing, and which association notifies or has notified the
    owner of the assisted rental housing and the department of its existence or establishment and has provided to such owner and the department the names and addresses of at least two of the officers or representatives of such association. Where more
    than one group of tenants in the same assisted rental housing claims to be the tenant association for such assisted rental housing, the department shall determine which group, if any, is the tenant association for the purposes of this chapter in the
    same manner as the department certifies a tenant association for the purposes of article II of the private housing finance law.</text>
</level>