<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-709</num>
  <heading>Hunts Point zone.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-709 Hunts Point zone. a. There is hereby established in the borough of the Bronx an empire zone as follows: BEGINNING at the point of intersection of the center line of East 156th Street and the center line of Prospect Avenue; thence northeasterly
    along the center line of Prospect Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of East 162nd Street, said line being the district boundary line between the R7-1 and R6 zoning districts as it appears on Sheet 6c of the Zoning Map of the New York
    City Planning Commission as amended effective February eighth, nineteen hundred ninety (A-1571), as contained in the Zoning Resolution of the City of New York; thence easterly along the center line of East 162nd Street to a point 100 feet to the northwest
    of Westchester Avenue as measured from its northwesterly street line; thence northeasterly along a line 100 feet to the northwest of Westchester Avenue and running parallel thereto to the point where it meets the westerly U.S. pierhead and bulkhead
    line of the Bronx River; thence southerly along the said U.S. pierhead and bulkhead line to a point where said pierhead and bulkhead lines divide; thence southerly and westerly along the westerly U.S. pierhead line of the Bronx River to a point where
    said U.S. pierhead line would meet the center line of Halleck Street if such center line were extended to the pierhead line; thence northerly along the prolongation of the center line of Halleck Street to the point where it meets the center line of
    Ryawa Avenue; thence westerly along the center line of Ryawa Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of Manida Street; thence southerly along the center line of Manida Street and its prolongation to a point where it meets the northerly
    U.S. pierhead line of the East River; thence northwesterly along said U.S. pierhead line to the point where it meets the center line of the southerly terminus of East 149th Street; thence northerly along the center line of East 149th Street to the
    point where it meets the main line set of tracks of the New York, New Haven &amp; Hartford Rail Road as such set of tracks appear on Sheet 6c as described aforesaid; thence northeasterly along the main line set of tracks of the New York, New Haven
    &amp; Hartford Rail Road to the point where it meets the center line of Leggett Avenue; thence northwesterly along the center line of Leggett Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of East 156th Street; thence easterly along the center
    line of East 156th Street to the point and place of beginning. The following areas shall not be included in the empire zone: (1) Joseph Rodman Drake Park: BEGINNING at the point of intersection of the center line of Longfellow Avenue and the center
    line of Oak Point Avenue; thence easterly along the center line of Oak Point Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of Hunt's Point Avenue; thence southeasterly along the center line of Hunt's Point Avenue to the point where it meets the
    center line of Drake Park Sguare; thence westerly along the center line of Drake Park Square to the point where it meets the center line of Longfellow Avenue; thence northerly along the center line of Longfellow Avenue to the point and place of beginning.
    (2) Bill Rainey Memorial Park: BEGINNING at the point of intersection of the center line of Longwood Avenue and the center line of Dawson Street; thence northeasterly along the center line of Dawson Street to the point where it meets the center line
    of Intervale Avenue; thence southeasterly along the center line of Intervale Avenue to the point where it meets the center line of Beck Street; thence southwesterly along the center line of Beck Street to a point 100 feet to the north of Longwood
    Avenue as measured from its northerly street line; thence northwesterly along a line 100 feet to the north of Longwood Avenue and running parallel thereto to a point on the prolongation of the center line of Kelly Street; thence southerly along the
    prolongation of the center line of Kelly Street to the point where it meets the center line of Longwood Avenue; thence northwesterly along the center line of Longwood Avenue to the point and place of beginning. (3) BEGINNING at the point of intersection
    of the westerly street line of Edgewater Road and the southerly street line of the Bruckner Expressway; thence westerly along the southerly street line of the Bruckner Expressway to the point where it meets the easterly street line of the Sheridan
    Expressway; thence southwesterly along the easterly street line of the Sheridan Expressway to the point where it meets the northerly street line of Hunt's Point Avenue; thence westerly along the northerly street line of Hunt's Point Avenue to the
    point where it meets the westerly street line of the Sheridan Expressway; thence northeasterly along the westerly street line of the Sheridan Express to a point 100 feet to the north of Westchester Avenue as measured from its northerly street line;
    thence easterly along a line 100 feet to the north of Westchester Avenue and running parallel thereto to the point where it meets the easterly street line of the Sheridan Expressway; thence southerly along the easterly street line of the Sheridan
    Expressway to the point where it meets the northerly street line of the Bruckner Expressway; thence easterly along the northerly street line of the Bruckner Expressway to the point where it meets the westerly street line of Edgewater Road; thence
    southerly along the westerly street line of Edgewater Road to the point and place of beginning. (4) BEGINNING at the point of intersection of the southerly street line of Hunt's Point Avenue and the easterly street line of the Sheridan Expressway;
    thence southwesterly along the easterly street line of the Sheridan Expressway to the point where it meets the center line of Leggett Avenue; thence westerly along the center line of Leggett Avenue to the point where it meets the southerly street
    line of Hunt's Point Avenue; thence easterly along the southerly street line of Hunt's Point Avenue to the point and place of beginning. (5) Any lands under water. b. Upon approval by the empire zones designation board, pursuant to subdivision (a-3)
    of section 960 of the general municipal law, of the initial distinct and separate contiguous areas described by block and lot in subdivision c of this section, the boundaries of the zone set forth in subdivision a of this section shall be superseded
    by subdivision c of this section. c. There is hereby established in the borough of the Bronx an empire zone consisting of the following blocks and lots: Area 1: Block: 2604 Lots: 33; 34; 68; 72; 74; 140; 174; 195; 252; 270; 275; 280; 292; 295; 500;
    600. Block: 2606 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 28; 30; 41; 49; 63; 125; 140; 172; 204; 230; 252. Block: 2730 Lots: 28; 98; 101; 150. Block: 2731 Lots: 1; 2; 3; 4; 5; 27; 40; 43; 49; 55; 61; 64; 65; 154. Block: 2733 Lots: 55; 58. Block: 2736 Lots: 11; 21; 42;
    49; 52; 57; 58; 66; 70; 80; 82; 84; 86; 105; 109; 115; 120; 122; 123; 130; 138; 146; 148; 149; 150; 151; 156; 160; 185; 189; 194; 202; 208; 213; 225; 237; 242; 252; 254; 256; 257; 266; 270; 276; 277; 279; 283; 297. Block: 2737 Lots: 1; 14; 16; 20;
    22; 23; 38; 40; 41; 48; 61; 65; 67; 69; 70; 75; 76; 78; 79; 80; 91; 95; 102; 115; 121; 125; 127; 129; 130; 134; 137; 140; 141; 142. Block: 2739 Lots: 1; 15. Block: 2741 Lots: 1; 42; 50; 60; 66; 89; 100. Block: 2755 Lots: 29; 48; 51; 52; 58; 62; 95;
    107; 109; 110; 115; 120; 125; 131; 133. Block: 2756 Lots: 55; 56; 57; 58; 59; 60; 61; 62; 63; 64; 65; 66; 67; 68; 69; 70; 71; 72; 73; 74; 75; 76; 77; 78; 79; 80; 85; 90. Block: 2757 Lots: 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 39; 40; 41; 42; 44; 50; 51; 66; 67; 68;
    69; 80; 85; 89; 92; 93; 112; 121; 122; 123; 124. Block: 2759 Lots: 1; 20; 22; 28; 42; 45; 70; 100; 101; 160; 169; 187; 240; 250; 260; 388; 389; 392. Block: 2761 Lots: 1; 3; 6; 10; 18; 22; 24; 30; 32; 33; 34; 35; 36; 37; 38; 39; 40; 41; 42; 43; 53;
    54; 55; 56; 57; 58; 59; 60; 61; 62; 63; 64; 65; 66; 67; 69; 70; 71; 72; 73; 74; 75; 76; 77; 78; 79; 80; 81; 83; 87; 92; 93; 94; 95; 97; 101; 102; 103; 107; 111; 112; 113; 114; 115; 116; 117; 120; 126; 130; 137; 138; 139; 142; 149; 153; 154; 156; 157;
    158; 159; 160; 161; 162; 163; 164; 166; 169; 173; 177; 179; 183; 189; 192; 193; 202; 208; 219; 224; 227; 231; 233; 236; 244; 248; 249; 252; 413; 415; 465; 472; 473; 474; 475; 476; 578; 579. Block: 2762 Lots: 1; 7; 12; 13; 14; 15; 16; 17; 18; 19; 20;
    23; 25; 35; 37; 40; 42; 44; 45; 47; 49; 51; 54; 56; 57; 59; 60; 61; 62; 63; 64; 65; 72; 78; 80; 82; 84; 85; 86; 89; 91; 92; 93; 94; 95; 97; 103; 106; 107; 108; 109; 110; 111; 112; 113; 114; 117; 118; 119; 120; 121; 123; 129; 130; 131; 132; 137; 142;
    143; 144; 145; 146; 147; 148; 149; 153; 160; 161; 163; 164; 166; 168; 169; 171; 172; 173; 174; 176; 177; 178; 179; 180; 181; 187; 199; 200; 204; 213; 216; 224; 225; 240; 248; 255; 257; 272; 280; 290; 294; 299; 300; 309; 314; 316; 365; 408; 421; 435;
    444; 450; 451; 452; 453; 454; 455; 456; 480; 485; 486; 487. Block: 2763 Lots: 144; 149; 150; 155; 158; 160; 162; 166; 170; 171; 172; 173; 174; 175; 176; 177; 178; 179; 180; 185; 190; 195; 206; 212; 215; 220; 224; 226; 227; 233; 237; 238; 239; 240;
    245; 248; 252; 256; 275; 279; 329; 331; 335; 339; 343; 345; 352; 353; 357; 360; 371; 373; 379; 384. Block: 2764 Lots: 1; 9; 17; 21; 25; 37; 38; 39; 51; 53; 70; 86; 92; 95. Block: 2765 Lots: 1; 5; 11; 13; 15; 20; 22; 29; 31; 34; 42; 46; 56; 59; 63;
    67; 70; 74; 78; 79; 86; 95; 98; 99; 100; 101; 102; 103; 104; 105; 107; 109; 111; 113; 115; 118; 123; 127; 132; 133; 138; 140; 146; 150; 151; 152; 153; 154; 155; 156; 161; 162; 163; 164; 165; 166; 168; 177; 195; 197; 198; 201; 205; 206; 209; 210; 211;
    212; 213; 214; 215; 216; 217; 218; 219; 226; 227; 228; 232; 246; 247; 248; 249; 250; 255; 256; 257; 258; 259; 261; 263; 264; 266; 267; 268; 269; 273; 274; 276; 277; 281; 282; 283; 284; 289; 290; 293; 294; 295; 296; 297; 298; 299; 300; 301; 302; 303;
    304; 305; 307; 308; 309; 310; 311; 312; 313; 314; 316; 647. Block: 2766 Lots: 1; 12; 15; 16; 17; 18; 20; 21; 22; 24; 25; 26; 27; 28; 29; 31; 46; 47; 48; 49; 50; 51; 52; 53; 54; 55; 56; 57; 58; 59; 60; 61; 70; 71; 72; 73; 74; 77; 78; 79; 80; 81; 87;
    88; 90; 92; 98; 114; 117; 118; 132; 133; 134; 135; 136; 137; 138; 139; 140; 145; 165; 167; 168; 180; 184; 190; 196; 204; 206; 208; 212; 214; 217; 218; 226; 230; 232; 240; 245; 254; 265; 276; 283; 286; 289; 291; 294; 295; 300; 320; 450; 451; 459; 515;
    520; 522; 523; 533; 535; 537; 539; 835. Block: 2768 Lots: 1; 5; 9; 12; 15; 23; 33; 34; 41; 49; 53; 60; 65; 77; 81; 83; 87; 89; 91; 93; 97; 101; 105; 115; 117; 120; 137; 145; 149; 153; 159; 171; 179; 187; 188; 192; 193; 196; 198; 206; 207; 208; 210;
    212; 216; 218; 222; 226; 228; 230; 233; 237; 241; 246; 249; 251; 253; 258; 260; 265; 275; 279; 280; 281; 285; 289; 295; 297; 298; 299; 303; 305; 333; 337; 343; 346; 352; 353; 354; 356; 360; 368; 376; 377; 379; 382. Block: 2769 Lots: 1; 5; 10; 12;
    13; 17; 19; 21; 27; 32; 38; 44; 49; 52; 54; 57; 62; 64; 66; 67; 71; 72; 73; 80; 84; 88; 90; 93; 94; 96; 97; 102; 106; 108; 109; 112; 120; 134; 141; 145; 161; 167; 170; 172; 186; 193; 195; 200; 205; 219; 4593. Block: 2770 Lots: 1. Block: 2771 Lots:
    30; 45; 74; 75; 99; 100; 121; 130; 135; 138; 153; 161; 165; 170; 173; 174; 175; 177; 181; 185; 201; 203; 210; 211; 212; 215; 217; 219; 225; 233; 235; 237; 5279. Block: 2772 Lots: 1; 9; 13; 15; 17; 19; 20; 25; 31; 35; 41; 43; 49; 50; 54; 56; 57; 59;
    61; 62; 64; 67; 69; 72; 77; 79; 81; 84; 86; 87; 89; 91; 102; 114; 115; 121; 123; 125; 130; 131; 132; 134; 137; 150; 157; 163; 170; 213; 217; 219; 225; 230; 234; 236; 237; 241; 244; 245; 256; 261; 262; 266; 270; 450; 7973. Block: 2774 Lots: 125; 142;
    146; 152; 163; 165; 170; 172; 191; 196; 198; 200; 202; 205; 216; 220; 225; 227; 229; 230; 233; 239; 246; 251; 256; 258; 281; 284; 287; 288; 290; 294; 296; 298; 299; 301; 303; 304; 305; 306; 308; 316; 321; 322; 323; 328; 329; 331; 333; 334; 335; 337;
    340; 342; 344; 347; 349; 367; 369; 372; 375; 601; 631; 1289. Block: 2775 Lots: 1; 9; 16; 18; 20; 27; 29; 30; 34; 36; 38; 40; 44; 49; 53; 63; 71; 73; 77; 78; 80; 81; 83; 85; 93; 97; 145; 148; 155; 169; 173; 178; 182; 187; 193; 196; 198; 201; 203; 204;
    208; 210; 216; 230; 236; 238; 279. Block: 2777 Lots: 25; 100; 105; 150; 152; 162; 166; 172; 173; 177; 180; 183; 185; 186; 196; 200; 205; 230; 246; 250; 292; 353; 410; 417; 418; 420; 428; 433; 442; 446; 447; 449; 451; 453; 455; 457; 600; 901; 903.
    Block: 2778 Lots: 100. Block: 2779 Lots: 1. Block: 2780 Lots: 2; 72; 73; 74; 172; 500. Block: 2781 Lots: 160; 301; 306; 400; 500; 800. Area 2: Block: 3513 Lots: 44. Block: 3540 Lots: 29; 40; 101. Block: 3542 Lots: 1; 13; 20. Block: 3576 Lots: 1; 50.
    Block: 3579 Lots: 1. Block: 3616 Lots: 1; 12; 17; 30. Block: 3617 Lots: 1. Block: 3618 Lots: 1. Block: 3619 Lots: 1. Block: 3696 Lots: 32; 43; 44; 45; 50; 142. Block: 3697 Lots: 11; 16; 18. Block: 3698 Lots: 31; 34; 36; 47; 58. Block: 3699 Lots: 37.
    Block: 3700 Lots: 26; 31; 46; 57; 58; 59; 61; 62; 63. Block: 3702 Lots: 1; 49; 101. Block: 3706 Lots: 1; 20. Block: 3827 Lots: 1; 30; 44; 55; 86; 101; 126; 127; 130; 142; 158. Block: 3828 Lots: 37; 39; 41. Block: 3829 Lots: 34. Block: 3830 Lots: 44.
    Block: 3831 Lots: 35; 36; 40; 65. Block: 3832 Lots: 37. Block: 3835 Lots: 3; 100. Block: 3836 Lots: 1. Block: 3837 Lots: 1. Block: 3838 Lots: 1; 118; 139; 159; 175; 176; 187; 198; 225; 226; 227; 250; 260; 301; 311; 318. Block: 3840 Lots: 1; 23; 100;
    125. Block: 3841 Lots: 1. Block: 3842 Lots: 2; 55. Block: 3843 Lots: 1; 45. Block: 3844 Lots: 1; 16; 31; 124; 125; 128; 129; 225. Block: 3847 Lots: 1; 3; 5; 10; 14; 18; 21. Block: 3848 Lots: 30; 55; 57; 65; 81. Block: 3849 Lots: 1. Block: 3850 Lots:
    1; 11. Block: 3851 Lots: 1; 5; 20; 24; 35; 60. Block: 3852 Lots: 1; 164. Block: 3856 Lots: 1; 10; 13; 18. Block: 3857 Lots: 9; 15; 16; 21; 27; 33; 40. Block: 3858 Lots: 16; 21; 25; 27; 29; 31; 35. Block: 3859 Lots: 1; 40. Block: 5541 Lots: 7; 8; 14;
    200; 210; 215; 275. Block: 5559 Lots: 1; 40. Block: 5560 Lots: 1; 5; 60; 62; 68; 77. Block: 5610 Lots: 5; 6; 16; 87; 120. Block: 5611 Lots: 2; 27; 28; 46; 49; 50; 55; 56; 60; 63; 66; 68; 69; 72; 74; 77; 78; 80; 84; 154.</text>
</level>