<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-607</num>
  <heading>Inspections.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-607 Inspections. Inspection of concrete and concrete construction shall conform to the requirements of tables 10-1 and 10-2 and the provisions of this subchapter. (a) Controlled inspection. Controlled inspection of concrete construction shall include:
    (1) STRENGTH TESTS. Strength tests shall be performed on all structural concrete. The provisions of reference standard RS 10-3 shall apply. A licensed concrete testing laboratory shall, in compliance with reference standards RS 10-17, RS 10-51 and
    RS 10-52, sample the concrete, make and cure the test specimens at the job site, transport the specimens to the laboratory and test the specimens for compressive strength. Written reports of the results shall be furnished to the architect or engineer
    designated for controlled inspection and to the concrete producer immediately, but not more than five days following the conclusion of the compression strength tests. Test specimens shall be stored on the job site in an insulated curing box of sufficient
    size and strength to contain all the specimens made in any four consecutive working days and to protect the specimens from falling over, being jarred or otherwise disturbed during the period of initial curing. The box shall be erected, furnished and
    maintained by the concrete contractor. Such box shall be equipped to provide the moisture and to regulate the temperature necessary to maintain the proper curing conditions required by reference standard RS 10-52. Such box shall be located in an area
    free from vibration such as pile driving and traffic of all kinds. No concrete requiring inspection shall be delivered to the site until such storage curing box has been provided. Specimens shall remain undisturbed in the curing box until ready for
    delivery to the testing laboratory but not less than sixteen hours. Specimens delivered to the laboratory prior to an age of forty-eight hours shall not be demolded prior to delivery. All specimens shall be carefully removed from the box and transported
    to the laboratory by the licensed concrete testing laboratory in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 10-52. All specimens shall be delivered to the laboratory before the laboratory closes at the end of the second working day following
    the day the specimens were molded. The date of arrival at the laboratory shall be recorded on the specimen test reports. All concrete failing to meet the specified minimum strength requirements shall be rejected by the architect or engineer designated
    for controlled inspection pending verification of the adequacy of the construction as described in section 27-598 of article three of this subchapter. (2) ADDITIONAL TESTS. Each sample of fresh concrete made in accordance with reference standard RS
    10-51 for the purpose of molding strength test specimens shall be made under the supervision of the architect or engineer designated for controlled inspection. Each sample shall be tested by the licensed concrete testing laboratory to determine its
    slump in accordance with reference standard RS 10-49, its entrained air content in accordance with reference standards RS 10-61 and RS 10-62, its unit weight in accordance with reference standards RS 10-63 and RS 10-64 and its temperature. If any
    of the tests fail to meet the specified requirements, the concrete shall be sampled again and the particular test that failed shall be repeated. If the second test fails to meet the specified requirements, then, with the approval of the architect
    or engineer designated for controlled inspection, adjustments shall be made to the concrete in the mixer to correct the deficiency. Test specimens shall not be molded from any sample that did not meet the specified requirements nor shall the concrete
    from which the sample was taken be placed in the structure, provided, however, that such concrete may be used elsewhere in the work where it meets or exceeds the specified requirements, but only with the approval of the architect or engineer designated
    for controlled inspection. In such case, test specimens shall be molded by the licensed concrete testing laboratory which shall also record the precise location where the concrete was placed in the structure. (3) CONTROLLED INSPECTION LOG BOOK. A
    controlled inspection log book, limited solely to the concrete construction work, readily available to inspectors and representatives of the department, concrete suppliers and the architect and/or engineer of record, shall be maintained at the job
    site by the architect or engineer designated for controlled inspection, who shall make therein daily entries pertaining to the progress of the work. The entries shall describe, but not be limited to, the location, size and dimensions of the concrete
    members for which forms were constructed that day; the reinforcement installed in, and the specific locations and time spans of, every concrete placement; the air temperature, wind velocity and direction and other weather conditions during the twenty-four
    hours after concrete has been placed, speci- fically at eight a.m., noon and four p.m., the protections taken against excessive temperatures and adverse weather conditions at each placement made that day; the methods used, to cure the concrete and
    the period during which such methods were maintained; the actual hour when forms were stripped and shores were reinstalled and tensioning was applied to all prestressed members. The log shall become a part of the documentation to be filed with the
    commissioner as provided in section 27-606 and shall include the attestation of the architect or engineer designated for controlled inspection that the concrete construction work complies with the approved plans and the provisions of this code. (b)
    Other required inspection. Quality control or inspection shall be provided with respect to all operations of mixing and placing concrete and reinforcement that are not designated for controlled inspection. In the case of sidewalks, curbs, paving,
    slabs-on-grade and any work designated in table 10-1 under the caption "Elements That Are Not Subject to Controlled Inspection" or in table 10-2 under the caption "Operations on Structural Elements That Are Not Subject to Controlled Inspection," all
    inspections shall be subject to and in accordance with the requirements of subdivision (b) of section 27-132. If any test to determine the quality or compressive strength of the concrete is required, the fresh concrete shall be sampled and tested
    for slump, entrained air content, unit weight and temperature. Compression strength test specimens shall be molded only by a licensed concrete testing laboratory or by a person certified by the American Concrete Institute as qualified to perform such
    function. Attestation shall be executed by the person superintending the use of the material in accordance with the requirements of subdivision (b) of section 27-132 of article seven of subchapter one of this chapter.</text>
</level>