<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-117</num>
  <heading>Existing refuse burning equipment.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-117 Existing refuse burning equipment. (a) Every owner of refuse burning equipment that has been operated at any time subsequent to January first, nineteen hundred sixty-five, whether such operation was required by law or not, shall, except as
    otherwise provided by this code: (1) Resume or continue the operation of such refuse burning equipment; or (2) Construct, maintain and operate a refuse compacting system in conformity with all applicable laws and regulations; or (3) Install, maintain
    and operate a refuse containerization system in conformity with all applicable laws and regulations; or (4) In the case of non-residential buildings or occupancies from which the department of sanitation has not collected refuse at any time subsequent
    to January first, nineteen hundred sixty-five, arrange for the continued collection of all refuse from such premises by a person, other than the department of sanitation, who is authorized to collect and remove refuse pursuant to applicable provisions
    of the code. (b) No person subject to the provisions of subdivision (a) of this section shall construct a refuse compacting system except with the prior written permission of the department of buildings upon application filed at an office of the department
    of buildings. The department of buildings shall, in writing, promptly notify the commissioner of the receipt of any such application. (c) No person subject to the provisions of subdivision (a) of this section shall install a refuse containerization
    system to be serviced by the department of sanitation except with the prior written permission of the department of sanitation upon application filed with the commissioner of sanitation. In considering any such application the commissioner of sanitation
    may take into account: (1) The number, capacity and specifications of the containers to be used; (2) The dimensions and suitability of the areas or rooms in which the containers are to be stored; (3) The accessibility of the containers to vehicles
    operated by the department of sanitation for the collection of refuse; (4) The frequency of collection of refuse and the cost to the department of sanitation of such collection which would be necessitated by the installation of the proposed refuse
    containerization system, as compared with the frequency and cost of such collection which would ensue upon the installation of either a refuse compacting system or other alternate refuse containerization system; (5) The adverse public health and environmental
    effects which may arise from the installation and operation of the refuse containerization system, including, without limitation, provision of harborage for rodents, insects or other pests; and (6) Such other factors as the commissioner of sanitation
    may deem necessary and proper. (d) The department of sanitation shall collect, without charge, refuse resulting from the operation of a refuse compacting system constructed, maintained and operated in conformity with subdivision (a) of this section
    or of a refuse containerization system installed, maintained and operated in conformity with such subdivision, unless prior to May twentieth, nineteen hundred sixty-six, the department of sanitation of the city of New York was not obligated to collect
    without charge refuse from the structures in which such refuse compacting system or refuse containerization system is installed. (e) The obligation of the department of sanitation under subdivision (d) of this section shall terminate: (1) If the use
    of such structure is changed in such a manner that if such change had occurred prior to May twentieth, nineteen hundred sixty-six, the department of sanitation would not have been obligated to collect, without charge, refuse from such structure; or
    (2) If, where the collection of refuse from such structure involves entry by the department of sanitation upon premises which are not owned and occupied by the city of New York, such department is not furnished with such indemnities and insurance
    protection as it may reasonably require. (f) In the event of the sealing of refuse burning equipment by the board pursuant to section 24-178 of this code, any collection of refuse by the department of sanitation from the location of said refuse burning
    equipment shall be at the expense of the owner of said equipment. Said expenses shall be recoverd in a civil action brought in the name of the commissioner of sanitation. (g) Notwithstanding any provision of this section to the contrary, the commissioner
    may authorize the discontinuance of the operation of certain refuse burning equipment as provided herein: (1) Upon the application of any owner of refuse burning equipment in a multiple dwelling containing forty-two dwelling units or less per unit
    of refuse burning equipment, provided that the applicant shows to the satisfaction of the commissioner that it would not be reasonably practicable for the applicant to cause the equipment in such multiple dwelling to fully meet the standards and requirements
    of this code or to install a reasonably efficient refuse compacting system or refuse containerization system by reason of the physical characteristics of the multiple dwelling or otherwise. (2) Upon the application of any owner of refuse burning equipment
    in a public building, in a public housing project operated by the New York city housing authority containing forty-two or less dwelling units, or in a building operated by a charitable or non-profit institution. (3) Operation of such refuse burning
    equipment shall be discontinued within thirty days after notice to the applicant of the authorization permitting discontinuance. Notice shall be given by the mailing of a copy of the authorization to the applicant at the address designated in the
    application. (4) Upon the discontinuance of operations pursuant to such authorization, the department of sanitation shall collect the refuse from the location of the refuse burning equipment designated in such authorization. (h) Any person who does
    not resume or who discontinues the operation of refuse burning equipment pursuant to the provisions of this section shall immediately notify the commissioner to such effect in writing, and shall within thirty days after such notice seal such refuse
    burning equipment in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations. To insure such compliance, the department may from time to time inspect such refuse burning equipment in accordance with section 24-108 of this code, and the commissioner may
    issue such orders with regard to the sealing of such refuse burning equipment as he or she deems necessary and proper. (i) The provisions of this section shall not apply to refuse burning equipment which is in a building to be demolished to permit
    the erection of a new building if: (1) The new building application has been approved by the department of buildings; and (2) Certificates of eviction have been issued by the state division of housing and community renewal, which is the city rent
    agency pursuant to section 26-403, where required; and (3) Final order for eviction has been issued. (j) Notwithstanding any provision of this section to the contrary, every owner of refuse burning equipment shall cease the operation of and remove
    or seal such refuse burning equipment within four years of the effective date of this subdivision. Substitution, modification or reduction by an owner of essential or required services subject to the provisions of the city rent and rehabilitation
    law or the rent stabilization law of nineteen hundred sixty-nine shall be permitted if such substitution, modification or reduction is necessary to comply with this subdivision and subdivision (a) of this section and is the minimum substitution, modification
    or reduction of essential or required services that is required for such compliance. This subdivision shall not apply to refuse burning equipment described in subdivisions one, two and three of section 24-118 of this subchapter.</text>
</level>