<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-802</num>
  <heading>Notification of impending conversion.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-802 Notification of impending conversion. (a) Notice shall be provided by the owner to the tenant association, or if no tenant association exists, to each tenant, and to the department of the intention of the owner to take any action that will
    result in the conversion of the assisted rental housing. (b) Such notice shall be provided no less than twelve months prior to the taking of such action by the owner. Such notice shall include the following information: (1) The name and address of
    each owner of the assisted rental housing. For any owner that is a corporation, the notice shall contain the names and addresses of the officers and directors of the corporation and of any person directly or indirectly holding more than ten percent
    of any class of the outstanding stock of the corporation. For any owner that is a partnership or joint venture, the notice shall contain the name and address of each individual who is a principal or exercises control of such entities. (2) The address
    and/or addresses and the name and/or names of the assisted rental housing and the type of program or programs to which the assisted rental housing is subject; (3) The nature of the action that the owner intends to take that will result in a conversion;
    (4) The date on which such action resulting in the conversion is anticipated to take place; (5) The provision of law, rule or regulation pursuant to which such action is authorized; (6) The total number and type of dwelling units subject to a conversion;
    (7) The current rent schedule for the dwelling units along with an estimation of the rent increases anticipated upon conversion; (8) The income and expense report for the twelve-month period prior to the notice including capital improvements, real
    property taxes and other municipal charges; (9) The amount of the outstanding mortgage as of the date of the notice; (10) The two most recent inspection reports from the real estate assessment center of the United States department of housing and
    urban development, for the assisted rental housing or group of multiple dwelling units operated together under the same ownership for which such inspection reports are required, or, the reports of the two most recent comprehensive building-wide inspection
    reports that may have been conducted by the department or by the New York state division of housing and community renewal; (11) A statement of notice in a manner approved by the department which advises a tenant association, or if no tenant association
    exists, advises each tenant, of the first opportunity to purchase as required by section 26-806 of this chapter, or of the right of first refusal, as required by section 26-805 of this chapter; (12) Such other information the department may require.
    (c) During the twelve-month notification period provided for in subdivision b of this section the owner may not sell or contract to sell the assisted rental housing, but may engage in such discussions with other interested parties. (d) Notice shall
    not be required of an owner who intends to maintain the property as assisted rental housing or intends to transfer, lease or refinance a mortgage in order to maintain the property as assisted rental housing. (e) Where an owner decides not to convert
    the assisted rental housing program, such owner may withdraw the notice of intention to convert the assisted rental housing program, subject to the terms of any accepted offer to purchase or executed purchase and sale agreement, and to existing statutory
    and common law remedies. In such event, the owner shall give notice to the tenant association, or if no tenant association exists, to each tenant, or if applicable, to a qualified entity, and to the department. However, should the owner at any time
    decide to take an action that will result in conversion, the twelve-month notice period of this section as well as all other applicable requirements of this chapter shall be complied with. (f) Notwithstanding any of the above, if any applicable supervening
    statute or program has a notice requirement substantially similar to any notice requirement of this section, then the notice requirement under this section shall be that of the supervening statute or program. (g) Notwithstanding any of the above,
    if the notices required by this section requires more information than is required by any applicable supervening city, state or federal statute or program, then such additional information shall be provided within the time period established by the
    supervening statute or program.</text>
</level>