<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-188</num>
  <heading>Accessible pedestrian signals program.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-188 Accessible pedestrian signals program. a. The department shall establish an accessible pedestrian signals program. As part of this program, the department shall identify intersections where accessible pedestrian signals may be installed based
    on guidelines, including, but not limited to, those set forth in the most recent version of the manual on uniform traffic control devices. The department, after consultation with the mayor's office for people with disabilities and with advocates for
    and members of the visually impaired community, shall identify intersections which reflect the greatest crossing difficulty for persons with visual impairments. Commencing in 2012, the department shall annually install, based on such guidelines, an
    accessible pedestrian signal at each corner of twenty-five intersections identified by the department following such consultation. b. On or before November 30, 2012, and on or before every November 30 thereafter, the department shall post on its website
    a report analyzing the status of the accessible pedestrian signals program which shall include, but not be limited to, a detailed assessment of the program including cost, funding sources for such program including, but not limited to city, state
    and federal funding, recommendations for improvements to such program, availability of new technology that may be employed by the department for use in such program and any additional intersections in the city that may warrant inclusion in such program.
    In addition, such report shall list the fifty top ranked intersections for new accessible pedestrian signals, as evaluated by the department after consultation with the mayor's office for people with disabilities and with advocates for and members
    of the visually impaired community, based on the criteria set forth in subdivision a of this section. c. The department shall post on its website the locations of all such accessible pedestrian signals, disaggregated by community district and council
    district.</text>
</level>