<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-123</num>
  <heading>Temporary commission on childhood and child caring programs.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-123. Temporary commission on childhood and child caring programs. a. There is hereby established a temporary commission on childhood and child caring programs consisting of fifteen members. The mayor shall appoint nine members, one of whom shall
    serve as chairperson. The speaker of the council shall appoint six members. None of the fifteen members appointed by the mayor or the speaker shall be elected officials or employees of the city of New York. In addition, the president of the council,
    the comptroller, the human resources administrator, the chancellor of the board of education of the city, the chairperson of the general welfare committee of the council, the commissioner of the department of health and mental hygiene of the city,
    the commissioner of the department of mental health of the city, the speaker of the council or his or her representative, and a representative from the office of the mayor shall each serve as a non-voting, ex-officio member of the commission or shall
    designate a person to serve in his or her place. The commissioner of the department of social services of the state of New York may, at his or her discretion, serve as a non-voting, ex-officio member of the commission or designate a person to serve
    in his or her place. Such commission shall have a duration of nine months. The members of the commission shall be appointed within thirty days of the effective date of this section. Each member, including each ex-officio member, shall serve without
    compensation for the duration of the commission. b. The commission may appoint an executive director to serve at its pleasure and may employ or retain such other employees and consultants as are necessary to fulfill its functions, within appropriations
    for such purposes. c. On or before the thirtieth day of September nineteen hundred ninety-one, the commission shall issue a report to the mayor and the council. The report shall make specific recommendations with respect to the areas listed below
    and shall include an assessment of the fiscal implications of such recommendations: 1. The role of childhood and child caring programs in education; 2. The role of childhood and child caring programs in providing support to families; 3. The role of
    childhood and child caring programs in community development; 4. The role of childhood and child caring programs for children with special needs, including, but not limited to, children with mental and physical disabilities, homeless children and
    children in need of preventive services; 5. The role of childhood and child caring programs in welfare reform; 6. The role of employers in the public and private sectors in providing childhood and child caring programs; 7. Methods to increase the
    number of licensed day care facilities and family day care providers and to recruit and retain personnel for childhood and child caring programs, including, but not limited to, tax incentives; 8. Methods to obtain additional resources for childhood
    and child caring programs and to improve the allocation of existing resources; 9. Methods to make childhood and child caring programs affordable for more families; and 10. The need, if any, to change licensing standards to promote childhood and child
    caring programs. d. Notwithstanding subdivision a of this section, the mayor shall appoint four additional members to the commission, and the speaker of the council shall appoint two additional members. None of the members appointed pursuant to this
    subdivision shall be elected officials or employees of the city of New York. Each additional member shall serve without compensation for the duration of the commission.</text>
</level>