<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-771</num>
  <heading>Statement of employee rights and employer obligations under state and federal law.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 20-771 Statement of employee rights and employer obligations under state and federal law. a. Every licensed employment agency under the jurisdiction of the commissioner and engaged in the job placement of domestic or household employees shall provide
    to each applicant for employment as a domestic or household employee and his or her prospective employer, before job placement is arranged, a written statement indicating the rights of such employee and the obligations of his or her employer under
    state and federal law. Such statement of rights and obligations shall embody provisions of state and federal laws that pertain to domestic or household employees, both in their capacity as workers in New York state and the United States and in their
    capacity specifically as domestic or household employees in New York state and the United States. Such statement of rights and obligations shall include, but not be limited to, a general description of employee rights and employer obligations pursuant
    to laws regarding minimum wage, overtime and hours of work, record keeping, social security payments, unemployment insurance coverage, disability insurance coverage and workers' compensation. Such statement of rights and obligations shall be prepared
    and distributed by the commissioner to licensed employment agencies over which the commissioner has jurisdiction. b. Every employment agency engaged in the job placement of domestic or household employees shall keep on file in its principal place
    of business for a period of three (3) years a statement, signed by the employer of a domestic or household employee whom the employment agency has placed with such employer, indicating that the employer has read and understands the statement of rights
    and obligations he or she received pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section. * NB There are 2 ยง 20-771's</text>
</level>