<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-326</num>
  <heading>Regulation of use of lakes and reservoirs used for city water supply.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-326 Regulation of use of lakes and reservoirs used for city water supply. a. Any natural lake or any reservoir used or built by the city for water supply purposes may be used by the public for boating, cutting ice and fishing. The city and its
    representatives shall not prohibit such use, and they are required to afford access to such lakes or reservoirs, except that the city may prohibit such use in the event of a declaration of an emergency by the governor as hereinafter provided and except
    in the event of the declaration of war by or against the United States of America. The city may grant permits to boat owners for the use of boats on such lakes and reservoirs, and may prescribe rules and regulations for their proper use. b. If any
    emergency shall have been declared to exist by the governor in the manner hereinafter provided in subdivision c of this section or in the event of a declaration of war by or against the United States of America, the mayor, for the duration of such
    emergency or of such war, may revoke, in whole or in part, the privileges set forth in subdivision a hereof and prohibit the use by the public of the lakes and reservoirs of the city. The commissioner may make reasonable rules and regulations as to
    the use of such reservoirs during such emergency or war period. Any such order of revocation shall define the terms and extent of revocation, and shall state the date on which it shall become effective. Any rules and regulations promulgated by the
    commissioner of environmental protection during such emergency shall be published once in a newspaper circulating in each of the counties in which the water supply property to be affected thereby shall be located. c. The governor is hereby empowered
    to declare the existence of an emergency affecting the city's water supply sources upon application of the commissioner of environmental protection and subject to the following conditions: 1. Notice of the application by the commissioner to have such
    emergency declared and of the date and place of the public hearing to be had thereon shall be published at least twice in a newspaper published in each county in which are located the sources of water supply as to which it is claimed the emergency
    exists and in addition written notice of such application and of the date and place of the hearing thereon shall be served on the clerk of the board of supervisors of each such county at least eight days before such hearing. 2. After such public hearing,
    at which all persons interested shall have an opportunity to be heard, the governor, may, if he or she deems such emergency to exist, declare the existence of such emergency affecting the city's water supply sources and fix the period for which the
    emergency shall be deemed to exist. The duration of such period of emergency may be extended after the giving of similar notice and after holding of a similar public hearing. 3. Notwithstanding the requirements of paragraphs one and two of subdivision
    c of this section, the governor shall have the power to declare the existence of an emergency affecting the city's water supply sources or any part thereof upon application of the commissioner without notice, and without a public hearing for a period
    not exceeding thirty days. Where such emergency is so declared, however, it shall not be extended or renewed except after notice and public hearing as provided in such paragraphs one and two. d. In the event of the declaration of an emergency by the
    governor or of the declaration of war by or against the United States of America, duly designated employees of the department of environmental protection are empowered and authorized to act as peace officers in any county in which any water supply
    property of the city is located for the purpose of enforcing the rules and regulations promulgated by the commissioner for the period of the emergency. The department of environmental protection shall file in the office of the sheriff of each such
    county a certificate of appointment of each such designated employee, and shall attach to each such certificate a complete copy of the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to subdivisions a and b of this section. Copies of all amendments of
    such rules and regulations shall be filed by the commissioner with each such sheriff. The sheriff of any such county may cancel any such certificate for cause, and forthwith shall mail written notice of such cancellation to the department of environmental
    protection, specifying the cause of such revocation. Immediately upon any such cancellation, the employee whose certificate shall have been cancelled, shall have no further authority to act as a peace officer. Each employee so appointed at all times
    when on duty, shall have in his or her possession a shield or other suitable badge of authority which he or she shall exhibit at once to any person upon request. e. It shall be the special duty of the employees so appointed to prevent breaches of
    the peace and unlawful depredations and to arrest and bring before the proper judicial officer any person guilty of violating any of such rules and regulations. f. Any person convicted of violating any of the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant
    to subdivision a of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than ten dollars for the first offense, twenty dollars or ten days imprisonment, or both, for the second offense, or fifty dollars or fifty days imprisonment, or both, for the
    third or any subsequent offense.</text>
</level>