<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>17-706</num>
  <heading>Sale of tobacco products to minors prohibited.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 17-706 Sale of tobacco products to minors prohibited. Any person operating a place of business wherein tobacco products are sold or offered for sale must be licensed as required by section 17-703 of this code and is prohibited from selling such
    products to individuals under eighteen years of age, and shall post in a conspicuous place a sign upon which there shall be imprinted the following statement, "SALE OF CIGARETTES, CIGARS, CHEWING TOBACCO, POWDERED TOBACCO, OR OTHER TOBACCO PRODUCTS,
    ROLLING PAPER OR PIPES, TO PERSONS UNDER EIGHTEEN YEARS OF AGE IS PROHIBITED BY LAW." Such sign shall be printed on a white card in red letters at least one-half inch in height. Sale of tobacco products in such places, other than by a vending machine,
    shall be made only to an individual who demonstrates, through a driver's license or other photographic identification card issued by a government entity or educational institution, that the individual is at least eighteen years of age. Such identification
    need not be required of any individual who reasonably appears to be at least twenty-five years of age, provided, however, that such appearance shall not constitute a defense in any proceeding alleging the sale of a tobacco product to an individual
    under eighteen years of age. * NB Effective until May 18, 2014 * ยง 17-706 Sale of cigarettes, tobacco products, or electronic cigarettes to minors and young adults prohibited. a. Any person operating a place of business wherein cigarettes, tobacco
    products, or electronic cigarettes are sold or offered for sale is prohibited from selling such cigarettes, tobacco products, or electronic cigarettes to individuals under twenty-one years of age Sale of cigarettes, tobacco products, or electronic
    cigarettes in such places shall be made only to an individual who demonstrates, through a driver's license or other photographic identification card issued by a government entity or educational institution, that the individual is at least twenty-one
    years of age. Such identification need not be required of any individual who reasonably appears to be at least thirty years of age, provided, however, that such appearance shall not constitute a defense in any proceeding alleging the sale of cigarettes,
    tobacco products, or electronic cigarettes to an individual under twenty-one years of age. b. Any person operating a place of business wherein non-tobacco shisha, pipes, or rolling papers are sold or offered for sale is prohibited from selling such
    non-tobacco shisha, pipes, or rolling papers to individuals under eighteen years of age. Sale of non-tobacco shisha, pipes, or rolling papers in such places shall be made only to an individual who demonstrates, through a driver's license or other
    photographic identification card issued by a government entity or educational institution, that the individual is at least eighteen years of age. Such identification need not be required of any individual who reasonably appears to be at least twenty-five
    years of age, provided, however, that such appearance shall not constitute a defense in any proceeding alleging the sale of non-tobacco shisha, pipes, or rolling papers to an individual under eighteen years of age. c. Any person operating a place
    of business wherein cigarettes, tobacco products, electronic cigarettes, herbal cigarettes, non-tobacco shisha, pipes, or rolling papers are sold or offered for sale shall post in a conspicuous place a sign, in accordance with the rules of the department,
    advising persons about the minimum age requirements for the purchase of such items. * NB Effective May 18, 2014</text>
</level>