<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-264</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>* ยง 20-264 Definitions. a. Whenever used in this subchapter, the words "dealer in second-hand articles" shall mean any person who, in any way or as a principal broker or agent: 1. Deals in the purchase or sale of second-hand articles of whatever nature,
    or 2. Accepts or receives second-hand articles as returns of merchandise or in exchange for or for credits on any other articles or merchandise, or 3. Deals in the purchase or sale of any second-hand manufactured article composed wholly or in part
    of gold, silver, platinum or other metals, or 4. Deals in the purchase or sale of old gold, silver, platinum or other precious metals, or 5. Deals in the purchase of articles or things comprised of gold, silver, platinum or other precious metals for
    the purpose of melting or refining, or 6. Engages in melting previous metals for the purpose of selling, or 7. Deals in the purchase or sale of pawnbroker tickets or other evidence of pledged articles, or 8. Not being a pawnbroker deals in the redemption
    or sale of pledged articles, or 9. Deals in the purchase or sale of any used electrical appliance, electronic equipment or component parts. b. Nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed to apply to: 1. Pianos, books, magazines, rugs,
    tapestries, artists' burlaps, painting, sculpture, drawings, etchings and engravings; 2. The first purchase or sale in the city of any imported second-hand article; 3. The acceptance or receipt of merchandise which is not second-hand as a return,
    exchange, or for credit or refund if such merchandise was originally purchased as new merchandise from the person accepting or receiving the same, nor to the resale of such merchandise; 4. The acceptance or receipt of second-hand merchandise as a
    return, trade-in, exchange, or for credit or refund if such merchandise was originally purchased as new merchandise from the person accepting or receiving the same, nor to the first subsequent sale or exchange of such merchandise to any person other
    than an ultimate consumer; 5. The first sale, at retail of merchandise which has been rebuilt by the manufacturer or vendor originally manufacturing it, or the licensed agents thereof, and sold as factory rebuilt merchandise. c. The burden of proof
    that an article was originally purchased from the person accepting or receiving it, that it was the first subsequent sale or exchange thereof to a person other than an ultimate consumer or that it was a first sale at retail of such factory rebuilt
    merchandise shall be upon the person asserting the same. Evidence of an existing trade-practice in the city, if any, shall be admissible for the purpose of determining whether or not merchandise is second-hand. * NB There are 2 ยง 20-264's</text>
</level>