<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-880</num>
  <heading>Equipment not required to be vented.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-880 Equipment not required to be vented. (a) Ranges for which a vent is not required by reference standard RS 15-2. (b) Built-in domestic cooking units for which a vent is not required by reference standard RS 15-2. (c) Hot plates and laundry stoves.
    (d) Type 1 clothes dryers. (*e) Water heaters with inputs not over five thousand Btu/hr. (See note below.) (*f) Automatically controlled instantaneous water heaters that supply water to a single faucet which is attached to and made a part of the equipment.
    (*g) A single booster type (automatic instantaneous) water heater when designed and used solely for the sanitizing rinse requirements of a national sanitation foundation class one, two or three dishwashing machine, provided that the input is limited
    to fifty thousand Btu/hr. the storage capacity is limited to twelve and one-half gallons and the heater is installed in a commercial kitchen having a mechanical exhaust system. (*h) Refrigerators. (*i) Counter equipment. (*j) Room heaters for which
    a vent is not required by reference standard RS 15.0. (*k) Other equipment for which a vent is not required and which are not provided with flue collars. (*l) Specialized equipment of limited input such as laboratory burners or gas lights. Note: When
    any, or all, of the equipment marked with an asterisk (*) is installed so that the aggregate input rating exceeds thirty Btu/hr. per cubic foot of room or space in which it is installed, one or more pieces of the equipment shall be provided with a
    venting system or other equivalent means for removing the vent gases to the outdoor air so that the aggregate input rating of the remaining unvented equipment does not exceed the thirty Btu/hr. per cubic foot figure. When the room or space in which
    such equipment is installed is directly connected to another room or space by a doorway, archway, or other opening of comparable size, which cannot be closed, the volume of such adjacent room or space may be included in the calculations.</text>
</level>