<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-622</num>
  <heading>Empirical provisions in lieu of design.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-622 Empirical provisions in lieu of design. The provisions of this section may be used in lieu of structural analysis only for those buildings in occupancy group J-3 where the specific occupancies correspond to a live load requirement of forty
    psf, or less, and to constructions wherein the supporting framing consists of multiple, closely spaced members, such as joists, studs, platform or balloon frames. All wood structural members in other classes of construction shall be proportioned on
    the basis of the analysis of stresses. All requirements established in this section may be reduced when an analysis of stresses, executed in accordance with reference standard RS 10-8, indicates such reduction is feasible. Sizes of wood members stated
    in this section are nominal sizes. (a) Stud walls and partitions. (1) Studs shall be of equivalent or better grade than the minimum grades for the various species as established in reference standard RS 10-13. (2) Corner posts shall be 3-stud members
    or members of equivalent strength. (3) Load bearing studs shall be set with the larger cross section dimension perpendicular to the wall or partition. Studs in exterior walls of one story buildings of construction class II-D and II-E shall be at least
    two inches by three inches spaced not more than sixteen inches on center, or where studs are two inches by four inches, spaced not more than twenty-four inches on center. Studs for other classes of construction shall be at least two inches by four
    inches spaced not more than sixteen inches on center. (4) Stud walls resting on concrete or masonry shall have sills at least two inches in nominal thickness. Where such sills bear on concrete, they shall be fastened with minimum one-half inch bolts
    embedded at least six inches. Each sill piece shall have at least two anchor bolts, with one bolt located at least one inch from each end of the plate, and with intermediate spacing not more than eight feet. Where such sills bear on masonry, they
    shall be anchored in accordance with the applicable provisions of reference standard RS 10-1. (5) Stud partitions that rest directly over each other and are not parallel to floor joists or beams may extend down between the joists and rest on the top
    plate of the partition, partition girder, or foundation below, or may be constructed on sill plates running on top of the beams or joists. (6) All load bearing stud partitions shall be supported on walls, other partitions, double joists or beams,
    solid bridging, or on beams at least as wide as the studs. Joists supporting a partition parallel to the joists wherein the joists are spaced apart to permit the passage of piping or duct work shall be provided with solid blocking at intervals of
    not more than sixteen inches. (7) Load bearing partitions perpendicular to joists shall not be offset from supporting girders, walls or partitions by more than the depth of the joists unless the joists are proportioned on the basis of analysis of
    stress. (8) In interior walls and in bearing partitions, double studs shall be provided at the sides of openings that are greater than three feet six inches up to six feet in width, and triple-studs shall be provided at the sides of openings of greater
    width. (9) Headers shall be provided over each opening in exterior walls and bearing partitions. Where the opening does not exceed three feet, each end of the header shall be supported on a stud or framing anchor. Where the opening exceeds three feet
    in width each end of the header shall be supported on one stud and where the opening exceeds six feet each end shall be supported on two studs. (10) All studs in exterior walls and in bearing partitions shall be capped with double top plates installed
    to provide overlapping at corners and at intersections with other walls and bearing partitions. End joists in double top plates shall be offset at least twenty-four inches. In lieu of double top plates, a continuous header of similar dimensions may
    be used. For platform frame construction, studs shall rest on a single bottom plate. (b) Bracing of exterior walls. Exterior stud walls shall be braced by one inch by four inch continuous diagonal strips let into the face of the studs and into the
    top and bottom plates at each corner of the building. Bracing may also be provided by one of the following means: (1) Wood board sheathing of one inch nominal thickness, applied diagonally. (2) For one and two-story dwellings, plywood sheathing at
    least four feet by eight feet (except where cut to fit around openings and for similar purposes) and at least five-sixteenths of an inch thick on studs spaced sixteen inches or less on centers and at least three-eighths of an inch thick on studs spaced
    more than sixteen inches but not exceeding twenty-four inches on centers. (3) For one story dwellings and for the upper story of two story dwellings, fiberboard sheathing applied vertically in panels at least four feet by eight feet (except where
    cut to fit around openings and for similar purposes). Fiberboard sheathing shall be at least one-half inch thick and shall conform to the provisions of reference standard RS 10-27. (4) For one story dwellings and for the upper story of two story dwellings,
    gypsum board sheathing applied horizontally in panels at least two feet by eight feet (except where cut to fit around openings and for similar purposes). Gypsum boards shall be at least one-half inch thick and shall conform to the provisions of reference
    standard RS 10-19. (c) Floor and roof framing. (1) SPAN TABLES. Joists and rafters may be used in accordance with reference standard RS 10-13. (2) BRIDGING. In all floor and roof and roof framing, there shall be at least one line of bridging for each
    eight feet of span. The bridging shall consist of at least one inch by three inch lumber or equivalent metal bracing. A line of bridging or solid blocking shall also be required at supports unless lateral support is provided by nailing to a beam,
    header, or to the studs. Midspan bridging is not required for floor or roof framing in one- and two-family dwellings where joist depth does not exceed twelve inches. Bridging shall bear securely against and be anchored to the members to be braced.
    (3) NOTCHES. Notches in the ends of joists and rafters shall not exceed one-fourth the depth unless adequate reinforcement is provided or analysis of stresses indicates that larger openings are feasible without the necessity for reinforcement. Notches
    in joists or rafters, located in the span shall not exceed one-sixth the depth and shall not be located in the middle third of the span. Bored holes shall not be within two inches of the top or bottom of the joists or rafter and the diameter of any
    such hole shall not exceed one-third the depth. For stair stringers, the minimum effective depth of the wood at any notch shall be three and one-half inches unless the stringer is continuously supported on a wall or partition. (4) SUPPORT. a. Floor
    or roof framing may be supported on stud partitions. b. Tail beams over twelve feet long and all header and trimmer beams over six feet long shall be hung in metal stirrups having anchors, or by other methods providing adequate support. Trimmers and
    headers shall be doubled where the header is four feet or more in length. c. Except where supported on a one inch by four inch ribbon strip and nailed to the adjoining stud, the ends of floor joists shall have at least one and one-half inches of bearing
    on wood or metal, nor less than four inches on masonry. d. Joists framing from opposite sides of and supported on a beam, girder, or partition shall be lapped at least four inches and fastened, butted end-to-end and tied by metal straps or dogs, or
    otherwise tied together in a manner providing adequate support. e. Joists framing into the side of a wood girder shall be supported by framing anchors, on ledger strips at least two inches by two inches, or by equivalent methods. f. Wood joists and
    rafters bearing on masonry walls shall be anchored to such walls in accordance with the applicable provisions of reference standard RS 10-1. (5) RAFTERS AND CEILING JOISTS. a. Where rafters meet to form a ridge, they shall be placed directly opposite
    each other and nailed to a ridge board at least one inch thick, and not less than the cut end of the rafters in depth. b. Provisions shall be made to resist the thrust from inclined rafters by connection of collar beams at least one inch by six inches,
    by connection to joists, or by equivalent means. c. Where ceiling joists are not parallel to rafters, subflooring or metal straps attached to the ends of the rafters shall be installed in a manner to provide a continuous tie across the building. d.
    Ceiling joists shall be continuous, or where they meet over interior partitions, shall be securely joined to provide a continuous tie across the building. e. Valley rafters shall be double members. Hip rafters may be single members. Valley and hip
    rafters shall be two inches deeper than jack rafters. f. Trussed rafters shall be designed in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 10-8. (6) Built-up members shall be securely spiked or bolted together and provision shall be made
    to resist the horizontal shear between laminations. (d) Nailing schedule. The size and number of nails for connections shall be in accordance with table 10-4.</text>
</level>