<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>20-268</num>
  <heading>Restrictions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 20-268 Restrictions. a. It shall be unlawful for any dealer in second-hand articles to carry on his or her business at any place other than the one designated in such license. b. It shall be unlawful for any such dealer to purchase any second-hand
    goods, or things from any person whom he or she knows to be or has reason to believe is a minor. c. It shall be unlawful for any person whose principal business is dealing in second-hand articles to purchase any second-hand goods or articles from
    any person between the hours of 12:00 A.M. and 6:00 A.M. d. It shall be unlawful for any such dealer to sell or dispose of any articles or things except household furniture, curtains, carpets, stoves, kitchen utensils, office furniture, automobiles,
    motor and other vehicles, machinery, belting, building materials and barrels, or other articles or things received from a dealer or pawnbroker, or which have been received from persons known to be jewelers, dealers, banking institutions, executors
    or administrators, until the expiration of fifteen days after such purchase or redemption. e. All second-hand articles or things purchased for the purpose of melting or refining by persons principally engaged in such business, from persons who are
    not jewelers or dealers, shall not be sold, refined or melted or disposed of until the expiration of fifteen days after such purchase. Such items as described in the preceding paragraph shall be kept on the premises described in the license which
    is required by section 20-265 of this chapter. f. It shall be unlawful for any person licensed as a dealer in second-hand articles, to be licensed as a pawnbroker. It shall be unlawful for any such dealer to receive any article by way of pledge or
    pawn, or employ subterfuge for receiving goods as security for the advancement of money; nor shall any sign, device or subterfuge be displayed, used or employed by any such dealer in or about the premises where such business is conducted, which in
    any way resembles the emblem or sign commonly used by pawnbrokers, or which is intended to give the appearance that the business conducted on such premises is, or is connected with, the business of a pawnbroker; nor shall there be any sign displayed
    which is calculated to deceive. g. (1) All open lots used as places of storage by junk dealers and dealers in second-hand articles, except lots used as places of display by dealers engaged exclusively in the sale of used or second-hand automobiles,
    shall be enclosed on all sides adjoining any street by a sheet metal or wooden fence which shall be sufficient to obscure such premises from the public view, and at least six feet in height. It shall be unlawful for such dealer to display or exhibit
    such property or articles on or in front of any such fence. It shall be the duty of such dealer occupying such premises to keep such fence free and clear of all signs, posters, handbills or other forms of advertisement of any sort whatsoever, except
    that such dealer may display one sign not exceeding twenty-four feet in length by six feet in height on such fence on each street which such premises shall adjoin, such sign to be used for the purpose of advertising the business of such dealer. The
    same restrictions shall apply to the owner of such premises in the event that such premises are made available for lease by such owner. (2) It shall be unlawful to stack or to permit the stacking of any motor vehicles of any kind, or any parts thereof,
    upon any private property within the city unless such vehicles or parts thereof are completely enclosed within a building, or within an area surrounded by a six foot high fence constructed of sheet metal or wood. When stacked in an open lot such motor
    vehicles or parts thereof shall be on the interior portion of the lot and the base of such stack shall be a distance of not less than twenty feet from such fence, and the height of such stack shall not exceed twenty feet. There shall be no less than
    a five hundred foot distance between the area so used and any place of worship, school or other public building. (3) The commissioner shall cause periodic inspection to be made of the area and must be satisfied that such premises comply with all laws
    and rules and regulations of the department of buildings, the fire department, the department of transportation, the department of health and mental hygiene, and the department of environmental protection insofar as the same are applicable thereto.
    For purposes of facilitating the inspection prescribed by this section, the commissioner is authorized to call upon the heads of the above named departments and such departments and their employees shall make such inspections as may be required. (4)
    The provisions set forth in paragraph (2) hereof relating to the five hundred foot distance from any place of worship, school or public building, shall not apply to any existing licensed premises.</text>
</level>