<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-108</num>
  <heading>Inspection and samples.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-108 Inspection and samples. (a) The department may inspect at any reasonable time and in a reasonable manner any equipment, apparatus, fuel, matter or thing which affects or may affect the emission of air contaminant including but not limited to
    the premises where the equipment, apparatus, or fuel is used, or where the fuel is stored, purchased, sold, or offered for sale for use in New York city. (b) The department may inspect at any reasonable time and in a reasonable manner any record relating
    to a use of equipment or apparatus which affects or may affect the emission of air contaminant, or relating to the use of fuel, or the distribution, storage or transportation of fuel for use in New York city. (c) The department may, at any reasonable
    time and in a reasonable manner, obtain a sample of air contaminant, fuel, process material, or other material which affects or may affect the emission of air contaminant. (d) If an authorized employee of the department obtains a sample of air contaminant,
    fuel, process material or other material which affects or may affect the emission of air contaminant during the course of an inspection, he or she shall give to the owner of the equipment or fuel, prior to leaving the premises, a receipt for the sample
    obtained. (e) No person shall refuse entry or access into the public areas of a multiple dwelling or a place of business to an authorized employee of the department who presents appropriate credentials nor shall any person refuse entry or access into
    any other portion of a premises to an authorized employee of the department who presents appropriate credentials and a search warrant. (f) The owner of every building, other than a one- or two-family home, shall make the area where the heating system
    or refuse burning equipment, or both, is located readily accessible to members of the department pursuant to the requirements of section 27-2033.</text>
</level>