<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>19-147</num>
  <heading>Replacement of pavement and maintenance of street hardware.</heading>
  <text>ยง 19-147 Replacement of pavement and maintenance of street hardware. a. General provisions. Whenever any pavement, sidewalk, curb or gutter in any street shall be taken up, the person or persons by whom or for whose benefit the same is removed shall
    restore such pavement, sidewalk, curb or gutter to its proper condition to the satisfaction of the commissioner of transportation. b. Rock refills. Whenever rock is excavated, not more than one-third of the total excavation shall be refilled with
    the broken stone, which must be in pieces not exceeding six inches in their largest dimension, mingled with clean earth and sand, and restored in such manner as to insure the thorough and compact filling of all spaces. c. Restoration in certain cases.
    Whenever any pavement in any street shall be taken up, or any paving stones in a street shall have been removed in violation of this subchapter or of section 24-521 of the code, the person or persons by whom or for whose benefit the pavement was taken
    up or paving stones removed shall forthwith return such stones to their former places, and shall otherwise restore the pavement to its normal condition to the satisfaction of the commissioner. d. Maintenance of street hardware. All utility maintenance
    hole (manhole) covers, castings, and other street hardware shall be maintained flush with the existing surrounding grade. All loose, slippery or broken utility maintenance hole (manhole) covers, castings and other street hardware shall be replaced
    at the direction of and to the satisfaction of the commissioner. e. Payment of cost. If the pavement, sidewalk, curb, gutter or street hardware is not properly restored, replaced or maintained to the satisfaction of the commissioner pursuant to subdivisions
    a, b, c and d of this section, the commissioner may restore, replace or maintain the pavement, sidewalk, curb, gutter or street hardware to its proper condition and the person or persons by whom or for whose benefit the same was removed shall be liable
    for the cost and expense of the restoration. f. Rules. The commissioner is hereby authorized to establish such rules as, in his or her judgment, shall be deemed necessary for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section. g. Reasonable
    notice of improper or inadequate restoration of pavement or maintenance of street hardware. Except where the condition of the pavement or hardware is an imminent danger to life or safety, reasonable notice of improper or inadequate restoration of
    pavement or maintenance of street hardware shall be given to a person by ordinary mail. In the case of utilities such notice may be oral or written and shall be given to a person or at a place designated by the utility and the utility shall respond
    within twenty-four hours.</text>
</level>