<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-951</num>
  <heading>Inspections and tests.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-951 Inspections and tests. (a) Inspections. Every new system and every part of an existing system that is altered, extended, renovated, or repaired, except for ordinary repairs, shall comply with the applicable requirements of this subchapter.
    (b) Notification. Advance notification of tests and inspections required by this section shall be given to the commissioner. (c) Representation at test. Tests required by this section shall be conducted in the presence of the commissioner or his or
    her authorized representative, or in lieu thereof, the commissioner may accept a signed statement of an architect or engineer, whose name is submitted with the notification in subdivision (b) of this section, declaring that he or she has witnessed
    the tests and that the standpipe system meets the requirements of this code. If a representative of the commissioner does not appear within two days after receipt of such report by the commissioner, the report shall be deemed to be accepted by the
    commissioner. (d) Testing equipment required. All equipment, material, and labor required for testing a system or part thereof shall be furnished by, and at the expense of, the person responsible for installing the work. (e) Testing of system. Systems
    may be tested in sections, or parts, in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter. (f) Acceptance. Before the acceptance of such system, each system shall be subjected to the tests required by this section. (g) Standpipe system tests. (1)
    PRESSURE TESTS. a. The test shall demonstrate that the system will sustain a hydrostatic pressure of at least one hundred psig, and at least three hundred psig at the siamese connection, for a period of at least one hour at the topmost hose outlet
    and at the lowest fire pump supply connection to the system. In buildings not exceeding three stories or forty feet in height, the test pressures need not be more than fifty psig. in excess of the normal hydrostatic pressures at the topmost hose outlet,
    and this pressure must be maintained for a period of at least one hour. b. Pressure tanks shall be tested to demonstrate that they will sustain a hydrostatic pressure of at least one hundred fifty per cent of the normal maximum required operating
    pressure for a period of at least one hour. (2) FLOW TEST. The system shall be flow tested to determine that water is available at the top outlet of each riser, the lowest outlet in each riser, and through each siamese connection. The system shall
    be flushed to remove all foreign matter from the system. Flow shall be through at least a two and one-half inch hose without nozzle at each one of the above mentioned locations at separate times. (3) ALTERATION TESTS. When alterations, additions,
    or repairs are made to a standpipe system, the entire system shall be subjected to a hydrostatic test pressure of at least fifty psig at the highest hose outlet, and in addition, a flow test shall be made as stated in paragraph two of this subdivision
    through the new or altered portion of the system. (h) Pump tests. (1) Fire pumps shall be tested at the factory, and a certified test curve shall be furnished with each pump. (2) Pumps shall be tested after installation to ascertain that the pump
    is supplying its rated capacity at the highest required hose outlet or through the roof manifold. The test shall be performed as follows: a. At least fifty feet of approved two and one-half inch rubber lined hose equipped with a one and one-eighth
    inch nozzle shall be connected to the highest two and one-half inch hose outlet valve. One of these assemblies shall be connected in parallel for each two hundred fifty gpm of rated pump capacity. b. The nozzle or nozzles of the hose assembly shall
    discharge at, or above, the highest required hose outlet or through a manifold. c. Pitot tube gauge readings shall be taken at each nozzle to determine that the required pump capacity is being discharged. d. For manually operated fire pumps, the suction
    and discharge pressures shall be recorded for each step or pump speed. The pump rpm electrical current, and voltage readings shall be recorded with the specific discharge pressure for each supply condition. e. Automatic fire pumps shall be tested
    to ascertain that all of the automatic controls are in good working order. f. All of the above readings shall be noted on the required standpipe diagram or a framed chart, which shall be mounted in a visible location near the pump control panel. g.
    When pumps are supplied by two independent services, the test shall be conducted from each service independent of the other and, in addition, with both services supplying the pump. (i) Test equipment for fire pumps. (1) For every fire pump installation,
    there shall be provided for test purposes at least three fifty foot lengths of approved two and one-half inch rubber lined fire hose. Hose shall be hung in the pump room or other convenient location. (2) Three two and one-half inch by one and one-eighth
    inch nozzles, three spanner wrenches, and twelve washers shall be stored with the required hose.</text>
</level>