<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>21-312</num>
  <heading>Shelters for adults.</heading>
  <text>ยง 21-312 Shelters for adults. a. Definitions. 1. "Census" shall mean the actual number of persons receiving shelter at a shelter for adults. 2. "Certified capacity" shall mean the maximum number of persons who may receive shelter at a shelter for adults
    at any one time as authorized by the New York state office of temporary and disability assistance. b. No shelter for adults shall be operated with a census of more than two hundred persons. Notwithstanding such prohibition, any shelter with a census
    of greater than two hundred persons on June first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight may continue to shelter the number of persons specified on the shelter's operating certificate as of that date as long as such shelter is operating in compliance with
    applicable statutes, laws, rules and regulations. * b. No shelter for adults shall be operated with a census of more than two hundred persons. Notwithstanding such prohibition, any shelter with a census of greater than two hundred persons on June
    first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight may continue to operate in excess of the abovementioned two hundred person limitation, and such shelter may continue to shelter the highest number of persons permitted, authorized, approved or otherwise allowed
    between June first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight and December seventeenth, nineteen hundred ninety-eight, by the state of New York office of temporary and disability assistance. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any shelter with
    a census of greater than two hundred persons on the effective date of this local law to reduce its census below two hundred persons. * The validity of this local law is currently a subject of a disagreement between the Mayor and the City Council.
    c. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision b of this section, homeless single adult shelters may provide short-term emergency shelter to persons in excess of the certified capacity only when the conditions set forth in subdivision h of section
    491.4 of title 18 of the official compilation of the codes, rules and regulations of the state of New York are met, and in no event for more than thirty days in any calendar year. Whenever a shelter for adults operates above its certified capacity,
    the speaker of the council shall be notified in writing within three business days. d. A minimum of seven supervisory staff members shall be required to be present whenever a shelter for adults operates with a census of two hundred and one persons
    or more, and one additional supervisory staff member shall be required for every forty persons in excess of two hundred and one. e. The commissioner shall submit to the speaker of the council quarterly reports summarizing the health, sanitation, safety
    and fire protection-related deficiencies identified in any inspection of a shelter for adults conducted by any state agency, including but not limited to the office of temporary and disability assistance, the office of children and family services,
    and the New York state department of health; and any city agency including, but not limited to, the New York city fire department, the New York city department of health and mental hygiene, and the New York city department of buildings; any other
    government agency; and any organization appointed by any court. The first such report shall be due thirty business days following the calendar quarter ending September thirtieth, nineteen hundred and ninety-eight and all subsequent reports shall be
    due thirty business days following the last day of each succeeding calendar quarter. Such quarterly reports shall include, but not be limited to, the following: 1. a list of all deficiencies identified by any state, city or other inspecting government
    agencies or organizations appointed by any court during the quarter which have not yet been brought into compliance with applicable statutes, laws, rules and regulations and the date on which deficiencies previously reported to the speaker of the
    council were brought into compliance; 2. a list of all deficiencies identified by the fire department in three or more consecutive inspections which have not yet been brought into compliance with applicable statutes, laws, rules and regulations; 3.
    a copy of all court orders regarding health, sanitation, safety and fire protection-related deficiencies issued during the quarter; and 4. a copy of all corrective action plans, and amendments thereto, regarding health, sanitation, safety and fire
    protection-related deficiencies filed with any court during the quarter.</text>
</level>