<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-356</num>
  <heading>Construction and repair of highways and bridges; rules and regulations to prevent improper use.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-356 Construction and repair of highways and bridges; rules and regulations to prevent improper use. a. The city is hereby required to build and construct such highways and bridges as may be made necessary by the construction of any reservoir under
    this subchapter, and to repair and forever maintain such additional highways and bridges and to remove the snow and to sand the highway surfaces whenever necessary, except such as shall be part of any state route; and in case any bridge or highway
    thus constructed shall cross any railroad, it shall do so above or below such railroad and not upon the same level. The plans and specifications for any highways required to be constructed under the provisions of this section shall be approved by
    the state department of transportation. b. The commissioner of environmental protection shall make such reasonable rules and regulations, not in conflict with the highway law, as may be necessary to prevent improper and destructive use of highways
    and bridges constructed under the provisions of the water supply laws of the city of New York. Provided, however, that the commissioner of environmental protection shall have no greater authority in respect thereto than is now, or may hereafter be,
    vested by the highway law of the state of New York in the town, county or state authorities in relation to the construction and regulation of town, county and state highways. Any individual or corporation failing to observe such rules and regulations
    shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, in addition, shall be liable for actual damages to such highways and bridges, to be recovered by the city. c. The state commissioner of transportation, in his or her discretion, shall have the power to perform,
    at the request of the commissioner of environmental protection and at the expense of the city, any work of original construction of substituting routes required to be performed by the city pursuant to this section. Whenever the state commissioner
    of transportation shall grant such a request of the commissioner of environmental protection, he or she shall prepare and submit to such commissioner of environmental protection for his or her approval an estimate of the cost of performing such work.
    Such estimate of cost shall be an estimate of the cost of performing such work of construction pursuant to plans, designs and specifications prepared by the commissioner of environmental protection and approved by the state commissioner of transportation,
    and shall include all costs in connection with performing such work, including the costs of engineering, auditing and administration. Upon approval of such estimate by the commissioner of environmental protection, the city shall thereupon deposit
    with the state comptroller, who is authorized to receive and accept the same, for the purpose of this subdivision, a sum of money equal to such estimate, which shall be subject to the draft or requisition of the state commissioner of transportation
    and a copy of the resolution of such commissioner of environmental protection authorizing such deposit shall be filed with the state commissioner of transportation and with the state comptroller. If, at any time prior to the award of a contract for
    the performance of such work or prior to the state commissioner of transportation becoming obligated to award such a contract, it appears to such commissioner of environmental protection that the state commissioner of transportation, for any reason,
    will be unable to award a contract for the performance of such work or that it is undesirable that such a contract be awarded, any sum or sums so deposited by the city, less the amount of cost which the state commissioner of transportation has already
    incurred, if any, shall be refunded to the city by the state comptroller upon demand of such commissioner of environmental protection made to the state comptroller and to the state commissioner of transportation. The performance of any such work of
    construction shall be by contract, to be let, so far as practicable, in the manner provided by section thirty-eight of the highway law, which section shall, so far as practicable, apply to contracts hereunder and payments thereon. Such contract shall
    be subject to and in conformity with such plans, designs and specifications of the commissioner of environmental protection. No contract shall be executed for any such work until satisfactory proof has been furnished to the state commissioner of transportation
    that the city has made available any real property required and any easements deemed necessary. When work performed by the state commissioner of transportation hereunder has been completed and the cost thereof paid, the state commissioner of transportation
    shall render to the commissioner of environmental protection an itemized statement showing in full (a) the amount of money which has been deposited by the city with the state comptroller in connection with such work, and (b) all disbursements made
    by the state commissioner of transportation in connection with the performance of such work. Any surplus money shall be paid to the city upon the warrant of the state comptroller upon vouchers therefor approved by the state commissioner of transportation.</text>
</level>