<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-171</num>
  <heading>Sulfur exemption certificates.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-171 Sulfur exemption certificates. (a) Except for fuel burning equipment that must comply with the sulfur dioxide emission standards of section 24-144 of this code, the commissioner may grant a certificate of exemption from the sulfur content restrictions
    of section 24-169 of this code if the applicant establishes to the satisfaction of the commissioner that the fuel burning equipment is operated in such a manner, or is equipped with such control apparatus, as to continuously prevent the emission of
    any sulfur compound or compounds in an amount greater than that which would have been emitted from the same fuel burning equipment, if operated, in the absence of control apparatus, using fuel which complies with the sulfur content restrictions of
    section 24-169 of this code. (b) The commissioner may grant a temporary certificate of exemption from the sulfur content restrictions of section 24-169 of this code, if the applicant establishes to the satisfaction of the commissioner that the application
    is for the purpose of conducting an experimental operation prior to application for a sulfur exemption certificate. (c) A sulfur exemption certificate shall be valid for one year from the date granted or renewed, unless sooner suspended or revoked.
    Application for renewal shall be made by the holder of the certificate, and shall be postmarked, or where personally delivered, date stamped by the department no later than ninety days prior to the expiration of the certificate. The commissioner may
    renew a sulfur exemption certificate if he or she is satisfied that the provisions of this code and the conditions and terms contained in the certificate will be met. (d) Any sulfur exemption certificate or temporary sulfur exemption certificate issued
    by the commissioner shall be limited to the kind and amount of fuel specified, and to use in the equipment described, and may be further limited as determined by the commissioner. (e) A separate application for a sulfur exemption certificate or temporary
    sulfur exemption certificate shall be made for each unit of fuel burning equipment for which exemption is sought. (f) In addition to the conditions and limitations for the issuance of a sulfur exemption certificate or temporary sulfur exemption certificate
    specified in this section, the commissioner may provide such further conditions or limitations as he or she may deem appropriate. (g) A temporary sulfur exemption certificate shall be valid for three months from the date granted or renewed, unless
    sooner suspended or revoked. The commissioner may renew a temporary certificate no more than once upon application which is postmarked or dated by the department no later than fourteen days prior to the expiration of the certificate.</text>
</level>