<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>26-412</num>
  <heading>Prohibitions.</heading>
  <text>ยง 26-412 Prohibitions. a. It shall be unlawful, regardless of any contract, lease or other obligation heretofore or hereafter entered into, for any person to demand or receive any rent for any housing accommodations in excess of the applicable maximum
    rent established therefor by the city rent agency or otherwise to do or omit to do any act, in violation of any regulation, order or requirement of the city rent agency under the state enabling act or under this chapter, or to offer, solicit, attempt
    or agree to do any of the foregoing. b. It shall be unlawful for any person to remove or attempt to remove from any housing accommodations the tenant or occupant thereof or to refuse to renew the lease or agreement for the use of said accommodations,
    because such tenant or occupant has taken, or proposes to take, action authorized or required by the state rent act or by this chapter or any provision of this code, the multiple dwelling law, or the health code of the city of New York, or any regulation,
    order or requirement thereunder. c. It shall be unlawful for any officer or employee of the city rent agency or for any official adviser or consultant to the city rent agency to disclose, otherwise than in the course of official duty, any information
    obtained under this chapter, or to use any such information for personal benefit. d. It shall be unlawful for any person, with intent to cause any tenant to vacate housing accommodations or to surrender or waive any rights of such tenant under this
    chapter or the regulations promulgated thereunder, to engage in any course of conduct including, but not limited to, interruption or discontinuance of essential services which interferes with or disturbs or is intended to interfere with or disturb
    the comfort, repose, peace or quiet of such tenant in his or her use or occupancy of the housing accommodations. e. It shall be unlawful for any person to make any statement or entry false in any material respect in any document or report submitted
    in any proceeding before the city rent agency or required to be kept filed under this chapter or any regulation, order or requirement thereunder, or to wilfully omit or neglect to make any material statement or entry required to be made in any such
    document or report; f. It shall be unlawful for a landlord or a successor in interest to use housing accommodations or the site on which same were located for any purposes other than that specified in the certificate of eviction.</text>
</level>