<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-501</num>
  <heading>Sewage disposal to protect water supply.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-501 Sewage disposal to protect water supply. a. 1. The commissioner of environmental protection is authorized and empowered to enter into a contract or agreement, subject to the approval of the mayor, with the appropriate authorities of the following
    localities: (a) The town board of any town and the municipal authorities of any village within the Croton watershed in the county of Westchester, (b) The authorities of the town of Carmel, Putnam county, (c) The municipal authorities of the village
    of Brewster, Putnam county, to provide for the disposal of the sewage of any town or village within the Croton watershed, of one or more villages or sewer districts within the town of Carmel, and of the village of Brewster, in the manner provided
    for in such agreement. The town board of any such town or the municipal authorities of any such village are likewise authorized and empowered to enter into such agreement. They may provide in such contract or agreement that all persons within the
    area affected owning buildings on streets where sewers are, or may hereafter be constructed or located under such agreement, or any modification thereof, shall connect with the sewer systems as provided in such contract or agreement. 2. In the event
    of the failure of any such person or persons to connect with any sewer system and the failure of the town board of any such town or the municipal authorities of any such village to compel such person or persons to connect with such sewer system within
    sixty days after notice and demand, the city shall have the right to cause such connection to be made at the expense of the owner failing or neglecting to connect with such sewer system. The expense of making any such connection may be recovered by
    the city in a suit in any court having competent jurisdiction. 3. With respect to the town of Carmel, such contract or agreement may authorize or require the construction, operation and maintenance of a sewage disposal plant, equipment and facilities
    for the disposition of the sewage of one or more villages or sewer districts in the town of Carmel or the extension, improvement, operation and maintenance of existing plants, if any, for such purpose. The town board of the town of Carmel is hereby
    authorized to contract between one or more sewer districts or between one or more villages and one or more sewer districts for any trunk sewer lines or laterals thereof to convey the sewage of such village, villages, district, or districts to a disposal
    plant operated by any district, village or municipality. The cost and expense of such trunk sewer, pumping station or appurtenant works shall be apportioned by the town board of the town of Carmel pro rata to the volume of sewage or population, or
    both, of the area benefited. b. 1. The commissioner of environmental protection is authorized and empowered, subject to the approval of the mayor, to enter into contracts or agreements with the municipal authorities of any towns or incorporated villages
    within the Esopus and Schoharie watersheds, in the counties of Ulster, Delaware, Schoharie and Greene, to provide, maintain and operate systems and plants for the collection and disposal of sewage in any such town or village. The municipal authorities
    of any such village or the town board of any such town are likewise authorized and empowered to enter into such agreements with the city. 2. When a sewerage system shall have been constructed, the city shall lay and thereafter maintain such pipes
    as may be necessary from such sewerage system to the outside of the foundation walls of buildings containing water-using sanitary plumbing. The cost of such pipes shall be paid by the city and in all cases where such pipes are so laid the owner shall
    make no claim for damage for such entry on his or her property unless the city shall have failed to replace and leave the surface and all improvements in the same condition as they were before the laying of such pipes. 3. When the city shall have
    constructed a sewerage system and shall have laid the necessary pipes from such system to the outside of the foundation wall of any building containing water-using sanitary plumbing, the owner of such building shall cause the drainage and sewerage
    of such building to be connected with and discharged into such pipes. 4. Upon the approval of the state engineer of the plans for any system of sewerage and disposal works prepared pursuant to any agreement entered into under the provisions of paragraph
    one of this subdivision, and upon the filing of such plans in the office of the state commissioner of health and of the town clerks in the towns in which such sewers and disposal works are located, the city is granted the right to such reasonable
    use of the highways, roads, streets and other public property of any county, village or town through which such sewer may pass or in which any part thereof may be located as may be necessary to construct, maintain and operate such sewer and disposal
    works. Where the route of such sewer follows any state highway, county highway or town road, such highway or road shall be replaced and repaired by the city to the satisfaction of the department, body or official having jurisdiction thereover. c.
    Notwithstanding any provision of any general, special or local law or of any charter, the commissioner of environmental protection is hereby authorized and empowered to enter into a contract or agreement, subject to the approval of the mayor, with
    the governing body of the county of Westchester, to provide for the disposal of the sewage of any municipality located in the county of Westchester wherein such disposal is required to protect the water supply of the city of New York. The governing
    body of the county of Westchester is likewise authorized and empowered to enter into such contract or agreement.</text>
</level>