<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-770</num>
  <heading>Noise control of mechanical equipment.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-770 Noise control of mechanical equipment. (a) Minimum airborne noise insulation requirements. (1) BOILER ROOMS. Boiler rooms adjoining dwelling spaces, either vertically or horizontally, shall be separated therefrom by floor-ceiling or partition
    constructions having a minimum STC rating of fifty. (2) MECHANICAL EQUIPMENT SPACES. Spaces or shafts containing air conditioning, refrigeration, or ventilating equipment, elevator machinery, or other mechanical equipment shall be separated both vertically
    and horizontally from dwelling units by constructions that will provide a minimum STC rating of fifty. Spaces or shafts containing equipment totaling more than seventy-five rated h.p. shall not be located vertically or horizontally adjacent to dwelling
    units unless the total sound power level output of all the equipment in the space or shaft is certified not to exceed the maximum sound power levels of table 12-3 in any octave band. Such sound power level ratings shall be obtained by tests conducted
    in accordance with the procedures of reference standard RS 12-5. a. Ventilating openings into mechanical equipment spaces. Ventilating openings into boiler rooms and other mechanical equipment spaces shall not be located in yards or courts where there
    are windows opening from living quarters, unless such ventilating openings are provided with sound attenuating devices if needed to limit noise transmission to NC-40 (noise criterion) levels in the exposed dwelling units. For permits issued after
    January first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, the permissible noise levels shall not exceed NC-35. b. Noise criteria requirements. Noise criteria requirements prescribed in this subchapter shall be in accordance with reference standard RS 12-4. Table
    12-3 Maximum Sound Power Levels Permitted in Mechanical Spaces or Shafts Adjoining Dwelling Spaces ======================================================================== Max. Sound Power Level db(a) ------------------------------------- Octave Bands,
    c.p.s. db re db re Mid-Frequency 10(-13) Watts 10(-12) Watts ------------------------------------------------------------------------ 63 101 91 125 101 91 250 103 93 500 105 95 1000 102 92 2000 101 91 4000 98 88 8000 96 86 ========================================================================
    Notes: a. The maximum sound power levels shall be reduced five db in any octave band where the equipment data indicate pure tone generation. The presence of pure tones may be determined by means of one-third octave band analysis. The criterion for
    a significant pure-tone component shall be an audible pure-tone sound together with an increase of the sound pressure level in the corresponding one-third octave band above the mean of the two adjacent one-third of at least: Center frequency of one-third
    octave band.......... 40/125 160/250 215/500 630/1,000 1,000/10,000 Increase in sound pressure level (db)............ 6 4 3 2 1 1/2 ------------------------------------------------------------------------ b. For permits issued after January first,
    nineteen hundred seventy-two, the maximum sound power levels shall be changed as follows: ======================================================================== Octave Bands, c.p.s. db re db re Mid-Frequency 10(-13) Watts 10(-12) Watts ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    63 98 88 125 97 87 250 100 90 1000 97 87 2000 96 86 4000 93 83 8000 91 81 ======================================================================== (3) DUCTWORK. Ducts serving dwelling units shall be lined with duct lining for at least twenty feet
    from the fan discharge or intake; otherwise, an approved sound attenuating device shall be installed therein. All toilet exhaust ducts shall be lined with duct lining for at least twenty feet upstream of the exhaust fan intake, otherwise, an approved
    sound attenuating device shall be installed therein. Duct lining shall conform to the requirements of subchapter thirteen of this chapter. (4) EXTERIOR MECHANICAL EQUIPMENT. Mechanical equipment in a building in any occupancy group, when located outside
    of the building in a yard or court or on a roof, or where the equipment opens to the exterior of the building, shall be subject to the noise output limitations given in table 12-4 where one or more windows of a dwelling unit in any building in occupancy
    groups J-1, J-2, or J-3 is located within a sphere of one hundred foot radius whose center is any part of the equipment or its housing, unless it can be shown that the sound pressure levels, in octave bands, of the exterior mechanical equipment as
    measured within the dwelling unit do not exceed the levels given in table 12-5. (For Table 12-4 see chapter 839 of the laws of 1986) Notes: a. The minimum distance shall be measured in a straight line regardless of obstructions. Interpolated levels
    may be used for distances between those given in this table. See note a. at end of table 12-3. 1. In the event sound power level data for the exterior mechanical equipment is not available, the sound pressure levels in octave bands, of the exterior
    mechanical equipment shall be measured. 2. The measurements shall be obtained with the microphone of the measuring equipment located at the interior of the dwelling unit affected in a line with the window nearest the exterior mechanical equipment.
    The window shall be fully open and the microphone shall be located three ft. away from the open portion of the window. 3. Measurements shall be obtained during times when the ambient sound pressure levels, in octave bands, are at least six db lower
    at all octave bands than the sound pressure levels measured with the exterior equipment operating. By ambient sound pressure levels is meant the measured sound pressure levels, at the above described measuring location, with the exterior equipment
    not in operation. b. For permits issued after January first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, the permitted maximum sound power levels for exterior mechanical equipment adjoining buildings shall be changed as follows: (For Table 12-5 see chapter 839
    of the laws of 1986) Notes: a. Measurements shall be obtained with a sound level meter and octave band analyzer, calibrated both electronically and acoustically before and after the measurements are made. The equipment used shall meet the requirements
    of reference standards RS 12-6. b. For permits issued after January first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, the maximum sound pressure levels shall be changed as follows: ====================================================================== Octave Bands
    Decibels Center Frequencies (cps) re .0002 microbar ------------------------------------------------------------------------ 63 61 125 53 250 46 500 40 1000 36 2000 34 4000 33 8000 32 ========================================================================
    (b) Minimum structure-borne noise and vibration isolation requirements. All isolators used in accordance with the following requirements shall be approved. (1) BOILER ROOMS. a. Boilers. All boilers supported on floors above a story having dwelling
    units shall be supported on resilient isolators having a minimum static deflection of one inch. The isolators shall be installed directly under the structural frame of the boiler. b. Boiler breeching and piping. When boilers are equipped with mechanical
    draft fans, the boiler breeching and piping that is supported from or on slabs, floors, or walls that are contiguous to the dwelling unit shall be supported for a distance of fifty pipe diameters on or from resilient isolators. Each isolator shall
    have a minimum static deflection of one inch. (2) INCINERATOR CHARGING CHUTES. a. Metal chutes. Metal chutes, metal chute supports, and/or metal chute bracing, shall be free of direct contact with the shaft enclosure and the openings provided in the
    floor construction. Metal chutes shall be resiliently supported at each structural support location. Isolators shall provide a minimum static deflection of 0.30 in. All chutes shall be plumb. b. Masonry chutes. The interior chute wall shall be plumb
    and without obstructions for the full height of the shaft and shall have a smooth interior finish. (3) PIPING. a. Metal piping connected to power driven equipment shall be resiliently supported from or on the building structure for a distance of fifty
    pipe diameters from the power driven equipment. The resilient isolators shall have a minimum static deflection of one inch for all piping with a four inch or larger actual outside diameter and one-half inch for piping with less than four inches in
    actual outside diameter. Piping connected to fluid pressure-reducing valves, shall be resiliently isolated for a distance of fifty pipe diameters from pressure reducing valves and isolators shall provide a minimum static deflection of one-half inch.
    b. Equipment such as heat exchangers, absorption refrigeration machines, etc., that is located on any floor or roof other than a floor on grade, and that is not power driven but is connected by metal piping to power driven equipment, shall be resiliently
    supported from or on the building structure, for a distance of fifty pipe diameters from the power driven equipment. The resilient supports shall be vibration isolators having a minimum static deflection of one inch and shall incorporate approved
    resilient pads having a minimum thickness of one-quarter inch. (4) Fans. Except for fans installed in compliance with section 27-353 of article five of subchapter five of this chapter all fan equipment located on any roof or floor other than a floor
    on grade shall be mounted on or from vibration isolators. Fan equipment with motor drives separated from the fan equipment shall be supported on an isolated integral rigid structural base supporting both the fan and motor. Fan equipment with motor
    drives supported from the fan equipment shall be mounted directly on vibration isolators. Each isolator shall have provision for leveling. Isolators shall incorporate resilient pads having a minimum thickness of one-quarter inch. The vibration isolators
    shall provide a minimum isolator efficiency of ninety percent at fan rotor rpm with a maximum deflection of two inches. Fans and compressors of three h.p. or less assembled in unitary containers may meet this requirement with isolators internal to
    the container providing the isolators meet the above minimum isolator efficiencies. (5) PUMPS. All pumps of three h. p. or more located on any floor other than a floor on grade shall be supported on vibration isolators having a minimum isolation efficiency
    of eighty-five per cent at the lowest disturbing frequency. Each isolator shall incorporate a leveling device and a resilient pad having a minimum thickness of one-quarter inch. (6) COMPRESSORS. Compressors and drives located on a floor other than
    a floor on grade shall be mounted on vibration isolators having a minimum isolation efficiency of eighty-five per cent at the lowest disturbing frequency. Each isolator shall incorporate a leveling device and a resilient pad having a minimum thickness
    of one-quarter inch. (7) COOLING TOWERS. All moving parts of cooling towers located on a roof or floor other than a floor on grade shall be installed on vibration isolators providing a minimum isolation efficiency of eighty-five per cent at fan rotor
    rpm with a maximum static deflection of four inches. Each isolator shall incorporate a leveling device and a resilient pad having a minimum thickness of one-quarter inch. (8) EVAPORATIVE CONDENSERS. Evaporative and air cooled condensers located on
    a roof or floor other than a floor on grade shall be mounted on vibration isolators providing a minimum isolation efficiency of eighty-five per cent at fan rotor rpm with a maximum static deflection of four inches. Each isolator shall incorporate
    a leveling device and a resilient pad having a minimum thickness of one-quarter inch. (9) DUCT CONNECTIONS TO FAN EQUIPMENT. Flexible connections shall be installed between fan equipment and connecting ductwork. (10) ELEVATOR MACHINERY. Gear-driven
    machinery, gearless machinery, motor generators, and controllers located in an elevator machinery room or shaft on a roof, or on a floor other than a floor on grade, shall be supported on vibration isolator pads having a minimum thickness of one-half
    inch. (c) Maximum permissible air velocities in ducts. (1) DUCTS LOCATED OVER CEILINGS OF DWELLING SPACES. The maximum permissible air velocity in ductwork located over the ceilings of dwelling spaces or in masonry shafts adjoining dwelling spaces
    shall not exceed the velocities prescribed in table 12-6. Table 12-6 Maximum Permissible Air Velocities in Ducts ======================================================================== Type of System Branch Ducts Sub-Main Ducts Main Ducts ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Low Velocity 750 fpm 1000 fpm 1500 fpm High Velocity 1000 2000 3000 ======================================================================== In the application of table 12-6 the following shall apply: a. Any duct that connects directly to any terminal
    device (grille, diffuser, etc.) shall be classified as a branch duct for a distance of at least four feet from the terminal device. b. Any duct that connects a branch duct to a main duct or to the fan shall be classified as a sub-main duct. No duct
    may be classified as a sub-main duct if it connects to a terminal device by means of a connection less than four feet in length. c. When a duct is connected to the fan and to two or more sub-main ducts it shall be classified as a main duct. d. The
    maximum velocities shown in table 12-6 for low velocity ductwork shall apply in all cases except where a system of round ductwork is used and an acoustic air control device with self-contained attenuation components is located in the duct work prior
    to each air terminal device. Branch ducts, if any, connecting the acoustic air control devices to the terminals shall not have air velocities exceeding seven hundred fifty fpm. Maximum power level ratings for the acoustic air control devices shall
    be three db less than the values shown in table 12-7. (d) Maximum permissible sound power levels of fan coil units, grilles, registers, diffusers and induction units. Sound power level data, in octave bands, shall be certified in accordance with the
    provisions of section 27-131 of article seven of subchapter one of this chapter, for grilles, registers, diffusers and induction units at design operating conditions and for coil units when operating at specified cfm. The sound power levels shall
    not exceed the levels listed in table 12-7 when measured in accordance with the provisions of reference standard RS 12-5. Table 12-7 Maximum Permissible Sound Power Levels for Terminal Units(1) ========================================================================
    Sound Power Levels, db Octave Bands, c.p.s. ---------------------------------- Mid-Frequency db re 10(-13) db re 10(-12) Watts ________________________________________________________________________ 63 79 69 125 73 63 250 67 57 500 62 52 1000 59
    49 2000 57 47 4000 54 44 8000 53 43 ======================================================================== Note: (1) For permits issued after January first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, the Maximum Permissible Sound Power Level for terminal units
    shall be changed as follows: ======================================================================== Octave Bands c.p.s. Sound Power Levels Mid Frequencies dB re 10(-13) Watts db re 10(-12) Watts ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    63 76 66 125 69 59 250 62 52 500 57 47 1000 54 44 2000 52 42 4000 49 39 8000 48 38 ========================================================================
  </text>
</level>