<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>22-255</num>
  <heading>Visitor pass.</heading>
  <text>ยง 22-255 Visitor pass. The department or a designee of the department shall be authorized to issue a visitor pass as a requirement for any person to enter a public wholesale market including but not limited to: retailers who enter the market to purchase
    products and their employees and temporary employees; and, subject to the provisions of section 22-264 of this chapter, officers and business agents of labor unions or organizations covered by such section and officers and business agents of the affiliates
    thereof, including international unions, pension and welfare funds and others. Such pass shall be in a form prescribed by the commissioner, may contain a photograph of such person and shall indicate the reason the person is visiting the market, whether
    such person visits the market on a regular basis or, in the event that such person does not regularly visit the market, the date for which such pass shall be valid. The commissioner may provide for the issuance of permanent visitor passes to those
    persons who regularly visit a market, and shall provide for the expeditious issuance of passes at the market entrance to persons wishing to enter the market on a single or occasional basis. A pass shall be in possession of such person at all times
    when such person is in the market and shall be worn and visible in compliance with rules promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to section 22-266 of this chapter. The department or, at the direction of the department, a designee of the department,
    shall be authorized to deny a visitor pass and entry into a market to any person whose presence may constitute a threat to the orderly operation of a market or who has failed to provide the identifying information required by the commissioner or the
    designee of the commissioner. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any public wholesale market to which access by the public has routinely been permitted without control, restriction or other regulation for no less than a year directly
    preceding the effective date of this provision; provided, however, that the commissioner may apply such provisions upon a determination that an emergency exists that necessitates the temporary restriction of access to such a market. For the purposes
    of this section, a "designee of the department" shall mean an agency of the city or, in the discretion of the commissioner, a wholesaler cooperative or similar organization. Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the denial of a visitor
    pass to a representative of a labor union or labor organization solely because such person seeks to engage in the lawful exercise within a public wholesale market of an activity protected under the provisions of the National Labor Relations Act, 29
    U.S.C. ยง 141 et seq., including, but not limited to, the lawful picketing of a place of business of a wholesale business or market business in connection with a legitimate labor dispute, except as may otherwise be prohibited by law. However, such
    person shall not impede any reasonable measure undertaken by a police officer or authorized employee of the department intended to control vehicle and pedestrian traffic within such public wholesale market or upon any street, avenue, parkway, plaza,
    square or other public place designated as a public market. The commissioner shall consult with the commissioner of labor relations prior to reaching any determination that an activity be a representative of a labor union or organization is not lawful
    under the National Labor Relations Act.</text>
</level>