<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-163.4</num>
  <heading>Use of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel and best available retrofit technology by the city's diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-163.4 Use of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel and best available retrofit technology by the city's diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles. a. Definitions. When used in this section: (1) "Best available retrofit technology" means technology, verified by
    the United States environmental protection agency or the California air resources board, for reducing the emission of pollutants that achieves reductions in particulate matter emissions at the highest classification level for diesel emission control
    strategies, as set forth in subdivision d of this section, that is applicable to the particular engine and application. Such technology shall also, at a reasonable cost, achieve the greatest reduction in emissions of nitrogen oxides at such particulate
    matter reduction level and shall in no event result in a net increase in the emissions of either particulate matter or nitrogen oxides. (2) "City agency" means a city, county, borough, administration, department, division, bureau, board or commission,
    or a corporation, institution or agency of government, the expenses of which are paid in whole or in part from the city treasury. (3) "Gross vehicle weight rating" means the value specified by the manufacturer of a motor vehicle model as the maximum
    design loaded weight of a single vehicle of that model. (4) "Motor vehicle" means a vehicle operated or driven upon a public highway which is propelled by any power other than muscular power, except electrically-driven mobility assistance devices
    operated or driven by a person with a disability, provided, however, that this term shall not include vehicles that are specially equipped for emergency response by the department, office of emergency management, sheriff's office of the department
    of finance, police department or fire department or vehicles, other than buses, specially equipped for emergency response by the department of correction. (5) "Person" means any natural person, co-partnership, firm, company, association, joint stock
    association, corporation or other like organization. (6) "Reasonable cost" means that such technology does not cost greater than thirty percent more than other technology applicable to the particular engine and application that falls within the same
    classification level for diesel emission control strategies, as set forth in subdivision d of this section, when considering the cost of the strategies, themselves, and the cost of installation. (7) "Ultra low sulfur diesel fuel" means diesel fuel
    that has a sulfur content of no more than fifteen parts per million. (8) "Biodiesel" means a fuel, designated B100, that is composed exclusively of mono-alkyl esters of long chain fatty acids derived from feedstock and that meets the specifications
    of the American society of testing and materials designation D 6751-12. b. (1) Each diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle owned or operated by a city agency shall be powered by an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing biodiesel as follows: i.
    for the fiscal years beginning July 1, 2014, and July 1, 2015, an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing at least five percent biodiesel (B5) by volume; and ii. for the fiscal year beginning July 1, 2016, and thereafter, between the months
    of April to November, inclusive, an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing at least twenty percent biodiesel (B20) by volume, and between the months of December to March, inclusive, an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing at least
    five percent biodiesel (B5) by volume. (2) Diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles having a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 8,500 pounds that are owned or operated by city agencies shall utilize the best available retrofit technology or be equipped
    with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter as set forth in section 86.007-11 of title 40 of the code of federal regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental
    protection agency standard for such pollutant that is at least as stringent, pursuant to the following schedule: i. 7% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2007; ii. 14% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2008; iii. 30% of all such motor
    vehicles by January 1, 2009; iv. 50% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2010; v. 70% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2011; vi. 90% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2012; vii. 100% of all such motor vehicles by July 1, 2012.
    (3) Notwithstanding any provision of subdivision c of this section, diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles having a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 8,500 pounds that are owned or operated by city agencies shall utilize the best available retrofit
    technology that meets the level 4 emission control strategy as defined in subdivision d of this section, or be equipped with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter as
    set forth in section 86.007-11 of title 40 of the code of federal regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for such pollutant that is at least as stringent, pursuant to the following schedule: i. 50%
    of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2014; ii. 70% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2015; iii. 80% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2016; and iv. 90% of all such motor vehicles by January 1, 2017. c. (1) The commissioner shall
    make determinations, and shall publish a list containing such determinations, as to the best available retrofit technology to be used for each type of diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle to which this section applies. Each such determination shall be
    reviewed and revised, as needed, on a regular basis, but in no event less often than once every six months. (2) The commissioner may determine that a technology, whether or not it has been verified by the United States environmental protection agency
    or the California air resources board, may be appropriate to test, on an experimental basis, on a particular type of diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle owned or operated by a city agency. The commissioner may authorize such technology to be installed
    on up to five percent or twenty-five of such type of motor vehicle, whichever is less. Any motor vehicle on which such technology is installed may be counted for the purpose of meeting the requirements of paragraph two of subdivision b of this section.
    Such technology shall not be required to be installed on other motor vehicles of the same type and shall be subject to the provisions of paragraph three of this subdivision. (3) No city agency shall be required to replace best available retrofit technology
    or experimental technology utilized for a diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle in accordance with the provisions of this section within three years of having first utilized such technology for such vehicle, except that technology that falls within Level
    4, as set forth in subdivision d of this section, shall not be required to be replaced until it has reached the end of its useful life. d. The classification levels for diesel emission control strategies are as follows, with Level 4 being the highest
    classification level: i. Level 4 - strategy reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by 85 percent or greater or reduces engine emissions to less than or equal to 0.01 grams diesel particulate matter per brake horsepower-hour; ii. Level 3 - strategy
    reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 50 and 84 percent; iii. Level 2 - strategy reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between 25 and 49 percent; iv. Level 1 - strategy reduces diesel particulate matter emissions by between
    20 and 24 percent. e. The commissioner shall issue a written determination that permits the use of diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million to fulfill the requirements of this section if ultra low sulfur diesel
    fuel is not available to meet the needs of city agencies to fulfill the requirements of this section. Such determination shall expire after six months and shall be renewed in writing every six months if such lack of availability persists, but in no
    event shall be in effect after September 1, 2006. f. (1) The commissioner may issue a waiver for the use of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel where a city agency makes a written finding, which is approved, in writing, by the commissioner, that a sufficient
    quantity of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel, or diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million where a determination is in effect pursuant to subdivision e of this section, is not available to meet the requirements of
    this section, provided that such agency, to the extent practicable, shall use whatever quantity of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel or diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million is available for its diesel fuel-powered
    motor vehicles. Any waiver issued pursuant to this paragraph shall expire after two months, unless the city agency renews the finding, in writing, and the commissioner approves such renewal, in writing. (2) The commissioner may issue a waiver for
    the use of an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend that contains the amount of biodiesel required pursuant to subdivision b of this section where a city agency makes a written finding, which is approved, in writing, by the commissioner, that a sufficient
    quantity of such ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing biodiesel is not available to meet the requirements of this section. Any waiver issued pursuant to this paragraph shall expire after two months, unless the city agency renews the finding,
    in writing, and the commissioner approves such renewal, in writing. (3) The commissioner may issue a waiver for the use of an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend that contains the amount of biodiesel required pursuant to subdivision b of this section
    where a city agency makes a written finding, which is approved, in writing, by the commissioner, that the use of biodiesel in a particular type of motor vehicle would void the manufacturer's warranty for such vehicle. g. (1) Not later than January
    1, 2007, and not later than January 1 of each year thereafter, the commissioner shall submit a report to the comptroller and the speaker of the council regarding, among other things, the use of ultra low sulfur diesel fuel and the use of the best
    available retrofit technology by diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles owned or operated by city agencies during the immediately preceding calendar year. The information contained in this report shall include, but not be limited to, for each city agency:
    (i) the total number of diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles owned or operated by such agency; (ii) the number of such motor vehicles that were powered by ultra low sulfur diesel fuel; (iii) the total number of diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles owned
    or operated by such agency having a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 8,500 pounds; (iv) the number of such motor vehicles that utilized the best available retrofit technology, including a breakdown by motor vehicle model, engine year and the
    type of technology used for each vehicle; (v) the number of such motor vehicles that are equipped with an engine certified to the applicable 2007 United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter as set forth in section
    86.007-11 of title 40 of the code of federal regulations or to any subsequent United States environmental protection agency standard for particulate matter that is at least as stringent; (vi) the number of such motor vehicles that utilized technology
    in accordance with paragraph two of subdivision c of this section and the results and analyses regarding the testing of such technology; and (vii) all waivers, findings, and renewals of such findings, issued pursuant to subdivision f of this section,
    which, for each waiver, shall include, but not be limited to, the quantity of diesel fuel needed to power diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles owned or operated by such agency; specific information concerning the availability of ultra low sulfur diesel
    fuel or diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million where a determination is in effect pursuant to subdivision e of this section; and detailed information concerning the agency's efforts to obtain ultra low sulfur
    diesel fuel or diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million where a determination is in effect pursuant to subdivision e of this section. (2) Where a determination is in effect pursuant to subdivision e of this section,
    information regarding diesel fuel that has a sulfur content of no more than thirty parts per million shall be reported wherever information is requested for ultra low sulfur diesel fuel pursuant to paragraph one of this subdivision. (3) The report
    due January 1, 2007 in accordance with paragraph one of this subdivision shall only include the information required pursuant to subparagraphs (i), (ii) and (vii) of such paragraph. h. This section shall not apply: (1) where federal or state funding
    precludes the city from imposing the requirements of this section; or (2) to purchases that are emergency procurements pursuant to section three hundred fifteen of the charter. i. B20 winter pilot program. Not later than December 1, 2016, the commissioner
    of citywide administrative services shall establish a pilot program to determine the feasibility of utilizing an ultra low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing at least twenty percent biodiesel (B20) by volume in city-owned diesel fuel-powered motor
    vehicles during the months of December to March, inclusive. The pilot program shall include not less than five percent of the city's total diesel fuel-powered motor vehicle fleet, which shall be representative of the vehicle types and operating conditions
    of the fleet as a whole, and shall include vehicles from the department of citywide administrative services, department of environmental protection, department of parks and recreation, department of sanitation, and department of transportation and
    vehicles from other city agencies at the discretion of the commissioner of citywide administrative services. Such pilot program shall continue until March 31 of the second calendar year after such pilot program was initiated, and within four months
    of the conclusion of such pilot program, the commissioner of citywide administrative services shall issue a report to the mayor and the speaker of the council detailing the findings of such pilot program with recommendations for the use of an ultra
    low sulfur diesel fuel blend containing at least twenty percent biodiesel (B20) by volume in city-owned diesel fuel-powered motor vehicles during the months of December to March, inclusive.</text>
</level>