<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>27-534</num>
  <heading>Exit openings.</heading>
  <text>ยง 27-534 Exit openings. Exit openings from assembly spaces shall comply with the following: (a) Capacity. The capacity of exit openings shall be listed as in table 8-1, based on the number of occupants for whom the opening satisfies the primary travel
    distance requirement. (b) Width. Exit openings shall be at least thirty-six inches wide for single doors and at least sixty-six inches but not more than eighty-eight inches wide for doors swinging in pairs, except that in assembly spaces having an
    occupant load of over three hundred persons, single door openings shall be at least forty-four inches wide. (c) Classification. Exit openings from assembly spaces shall be classified as follows: Class 1. Exit openings that are used for normal entry
    to the assembly space, and that open directly to a safe area or to an open exterior space. Class 2. Exit openings that are not used for normal entry to the assembly space, and that open directly to a safe area or to an open exterior space. Class 3.
    Exit openings that open from the assembly space into corridors, exit passageways, or vertical exits. (d) Distribution of classes. The required exit capacity from F-2 places of assembly, and from all other assembly spaces in which the net floor area,
    exclusive of stage area, is twelve square feet or more per person may be provided by exit openings of any class. The required exit capacity from assembly spaces in which the net floor area, exclusive of stage area, is less than twelve square feet
    per person shall be distributed so that exit openings of each class are provided to comply with the following requirements: 1. For assembly spaces in which the mean floor level is not more than fifteen feet above or below the adjoining grade elevation,
    the exit capacity shall be distributed as follows: Class 1--not less than forty per cent Class 2--not more than sixty per cent Class 3--not more than forty per cent 2. For assembly spaces in which the mean floor level is more than fifteen feet, but
    not more than thirty feet, above or below the adjoining grade elevation, the exit capacity shall be distributed as follows: Class 1--not less than sixty per cent Class 3--not more than forty per cent 3. For assembly spaces in which the mean floor
    level is more than thirty feet above or below the adjoining grade elevation, the exit capacity shall be distributed as follows: Class 1--not less than one hundred per cent (e) Location. No exit opening shall be closer than twelve feet to any part
    of a stage using scenery or scenic elements. All exit openings shall be clearly identifiable and shall not be disguised as part of a wall or covered in any way to obscure them from view. Where, because of the configuration of the assembly space enclosure
    an exit opening is not visible from all seats using it as a means of egress, directional exit signs shall be placed on the enclosure alongside the exit opening to indicate its location. These signs shall be in addition to those required over the exit
    opening. (f) Locking. No exit door shall be locked so as to prevent egress from an assembly space while it is occupied.</text>
</level>