<level>
  <type>section</type>
  <num>24-261</num>
  <heading>Citizen's complaint.</heading>
  <text>ยง 24-261 Citizen's complaint. (a) Any person other than personnel of the department and employees of the city of New York authorized by law to serve summonses for violation of the code may serve upon the department a complaint in a form prescribed by
    the commissioner alleging that a person has violated a provision of this code set forth in table VI, below, or an order or regulation promulgated under such provision together with evidence of such violation. Table VI Violation related to section
    or subdivision and order or regulation thereunder 24-208 24-216 24-220 (b) 24-224 24-232, except that the provisions of this section 24-261 shall apply only to violations by persons operating motor vehicles listed in sub- divisions one and two of
    column I, and subdivisions one and two of column II of Table 1. 24-234 24-236 24-237, except that the provisions of this section 24-261 shall apply only to a violation by a person operating a circulation device with a rated capacity in excess of fifty
    thousand British thermal units per hour or its equivalent. 24-238 24-240 24-241 24-244 24-245 (b) A person who has served a complaint pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section may serve upon the person allegedly in violation and upon the board a
    notice of violation in a form prescribed by the board, if within thirty days from service of such complaint: (1) The department has failed to serve a notice of violation, pursuant to section 24-259 of this code, for the violation alleged in a complaint
    pursuant to subdivision (a) of this section; or (2) The department fails to serve a written notice upon the complainant of its determination that his or her complaint is frivolous or duplicitous. (c) A person commencing a proceeding before the board
    pursuant to this section, shall prosecute such proceeding at his or her own expense. The department may intervene in such a proceeding at any time. (d) In any proceeding brought by the department after receiving a complaint pursuant to subdivision
    (a) of this section, the board shall award the complainant, out of the proceeds collected, fair and reasonable compensation, which shall not exceed twenty-five percent of the proceeds collected, for disclosure of information or evidence not in the
    possession of the department, which leads to the imposition of the civil penalty. (e) In any proceeding brought by a complainant, the board shall award, out of the proceeds collected, fifty percent of any civil penalty as fair and reasonable compensation
    to such person.</text>
</level>